hey everyone my name is Josh Gordon and
I'm here today with jayjay Oler and JJ
is the founder of art studio and he
recently added support for tensorflow
and care us to our so JJ thank you very
much for coming on the show thank you
and could you tell me a little bit about
the work you've done absolutely
tensorflow
came out I think about two and a half
years ago and from the day that it came
out I've been excited about what we
could do with tensorflow from our our
the art community is filled of people
who are not they don't self-identify as
software developers they identify as
statisticians or economists or
biologists and the interfaces we build
to modeling and statistics from are tend
to be really fluent high-level
interfaces that kind of are really well
married to the vocabulary of the domain
that people are doing work in and so
tensorflow brings this awesome
capability for neural networks and even
just as a general-purpose numerical
computing framework and I thought wow we
can do incredible things from our to
make all this power available to all
these people solving solving heart
problems then particularly the the
Charis interface which I hope we get to
talk about a little bit more is a really
nice high-level vocabulary for doing
deep learning that fits really well with
the way our users work and think and so
I was excited to both can make the core
capabilities of tensorflow available but
then also to make the Charis API
available that's one thing you did too
is you contributed some really great
educational resources especially yes so
we probably spent as much or more time
on educational resources as we did on
the actual interfaces so I worked on a
book along with Francois shalay about
deep learning with art adapted his deep
learning with Python book Francois is
actually the creator of Karass so worked
on that book we created a whole bunch of
examples probably 25 or so examples of
using Kerris and many many other
examples we created a gallery of kind of
longer form blog posts that describe
like really in-depth worked examples in
different domains so we have invested a
huge amount in educational resources and
are going to continue to do that and
this book is excellent the book is
awesome yes I've read the Python version
cover-to-cover
yep
I taught a class with it students loved
it I strongly recommend it to all the
developers I meet what's remarkable
about it is that it covers the concepts
the conceptual terrain of deep learning
in a way that's I think it's really
intuitive for people to understand was
not not a huge number of prerequisites
but it also has a wealth of practical
information about how to actually do
deep learning what are the small
problems you come up with what are the
failure modes and how to overcome them
so it's just it's a rare book that
combines kind of conceptual material and
practical material and so I I recommend
that as the first thing that people who
are in the art community and they say I
want to learn more about this I
recommend that they get that book and
read it first it's probably a lot of
work porting that over to our yeah it
was but most of the book is
predominantly conceptual and then there
are these examples and so I really just
changed the examples but really most of
the book is ends up being conceptual it
kind of at a higher level of the
specific languages so it wasn't too bad
and then another thing you have on the
our website the our city website which
is really cool is worked and end
examples that's right we have a gallery
where we don't just show you here's the
mechanics of solving a certain type of
problem but we go kind of from the
beginning here's the motivation here's
the data set maybe let's visualize the
data set a little bit
let's try different approaches to the
problem and see what works and doesn't
work so we we kind of cover and and like
what a what the workflow of a data
scientists would go through to solve
these problems so and well again we're
gonna be investing in more of those
because I think that's the way that
people can really get engaged with this
is not just learning the basic mechanics
and concepts but seeing how it actually
applies to their field
I like this combination a lot yes to
really solid set of learning resources
good so in addition to supporting care
us you also have support for tensorflow
estimators yes we have another our
package there's actually a suite of
7-hour packages that we have for
tensorflow there's our package called
tensorflow which is a low-level
interface to the full tensor flow graph
and the full potential api there's the
Charis a path which we've been talking
about and then we have tensorflow
estimators which is another high level
framework that Google has for doing
models like classification and
regression models classification and
regression using DNS and so there's a
really really high level functions that
come with a nice framework for
for data pre-processing and things and a
nice framework for deploying the models
so we have another package called TF
estimators that covers that covers the
estimators API deployment is it's really
important to have as well it is and
that's one of the things that I'm most
excited about because traditionally with
our when you do modeling and then you
want to deploy the model in some fashion
you have to bring the our runtime along
with you and that can be a challenge so
what the the design of tensorflow is
that you're writing a program but that
program is creating a graph and that
graph is executed by a runtime a C++
runtime so deploying models doesn't
require that you bring R or Python or
any these sorts of language that you
languages that you used to model in to
deployment and so we have another
package called TF deploy that helps
people with sort of serializing they're
saved models putting rest interfaces on
top of their saved models getting models
actually brought into JavaScript there's
the library called Kara CAS that let you
take a Karass model and run it in a
browser so we've got lots of tools for
that and that's actually one of the most
exciting things about tensorflow is that
is this deployment model so tensorflow
j/s ok supports a chaos' compatible api
ok and i believe what this means is that
people will be able to author models in
our that's right using the chaos
interface that's right and then deploy
them and deploy them right into a
browser yeah that's gonna be huge it's
phenomenal yeah so I think a lot of
people in the our community that I've
taught I mean all communities I think
this is such a fundamentally good idea
to take models and serialize them into
this runtime format that doesn't because
the the languages and tools that are
good for training you know for
exploratory data analysis training
models authoring models which are
different than languages that are good
for deployment it's a really good
division of responsibilities that
tensorflow kind of enforces and so I'm
hopeful that our users who want to put
their models in production now will have
a really straightforward way to do that
I think so too and it's a really good
opportunity for data scientists to
visualize the results of their
experiments I actually deploy the
toggles yeah yeah so say I'm an our
developer new to deep learning about how
much code is it going to take for me to
write my first neural network well
interestingly if you look at our
examples that the hard part about deep
learn
is not generally writing the code and
you know many of our examples are on the
order of a hundred lines of code or even
even less than that sometimes the hard
part is actually figuring out what sort
of model to build and how it should what
the architecture of the model should be
and what the hyper parameters of the
mouth should be that's where all the
time is the actual expression of the
model and code is actually quite trivial
but model and model building really ends
up being not about the code but about
about mapping your problem and the data
and the tools you have together to get a
good solution I completely agree it's
well put and I think a lot of people
from the art community especially from a
stats and data science background will
be natural the background and training
of people in the art community the the
the understanding how to do modeling
statistics probability is perfect for
for deep learning and I'm really excited
once more people in the art community
get get their hands on these tools of
the kind of work that we're gonna see me
too
so JJ thanks again for coming on the
show really appreciate it then just to
close things out where's the best place
for developers to go to learn more about
deep learning in our the best place we
have a website called tensorflow
that our studio com it has documentation
for all the packages as I talked about
Kerris and estimators and and the core
tensorflow api as information about
deployment it has a gallery of in-depth
examples kind of blog posts it has a
whole bunch of additional learning
resources so tensorflow down our studio
comm is definitely the place to go to to
get started ok thanks again really
appreciate it thanks
you