[Music]
welcome everyone I am Jeremiah and this
is tensorflow in production I'm excited
that you're all here because that means
you're excited about production and that
means you're building things that people
actually use so our talk today has three
parts I want to start by quickly drawing
a thread that kind of connects all of
them and the first thread is the origin
of these projects these projects really
come from our teams that are on the
front line of machine learning so these
are real problems that we've come across
doing machine learning at Google's scale
and these are the real solutions that
let us do machine learning at Google the
second thing I want to talk about is
this observation if we look at software
engineering over the years we see this
growth as we discover new tools as we
discover best practices we're really
getting more effective at doing machine
or doing software engineering and we're
getting more efficient we're seeing the
same kind of growth on the machine
learning side right we're discovering
new best practices and new tools the
catch is that this growth is maybe 10 or
15 years behind software engineering and
we're also rediscovering a lot of the
same things that exist in software
engineering but in a machine learning
context so we're doing things like
discovering version control for machine
learning or continuous integration for
machine learning so I think it's worth
keeping that in mind as we move through
the talks the first one up is going to
be tensorflow hub and this is something
that lets you share reusable pieces of
machine learning much the same way we
share code then we'll talk a little bit
about deploying machine learning models
with tensorflow serving and we'll finish
up with tensorflow extended which wraps
a lot of these things together in a
platform to increase your velocity
as a machine-learning practitioner so
with that I'd like to hand it over to
Andrew to talk about tensorflow hub
thanks Jeremiah hi everybody I'm Andrew
Gasper ovitch and I'd like to talk to
you a little bit about tensorflow hub
which is a new library that's designed
to bring reusability to machine learning
so software repositories have been a
real benefit to developer productivity
over the past 10 or 15 years and are
great
first of all because when you're writing
something new if you have a repository
you think oh maybe I'll check whether
there's something that already exists
and reuse that rather than starting from
scratch but a second thing that happens
is you start thinking maybe I'll write
my code in a way that's specifically
designed for reuse which is great
because it makes your code more modular
but it also has a potential to benefit a
whole community if you share that code
what we are doing with tensorflow hub is
bringing that idea of a repository to
machine learning in this case tensorflow
hub is designed so that you can create
share and reuse components of ml models
and if you think about it it's even more
important to have a repository for
machine learning even more so than
software development because in the case
of machine learning not only are you
reusing the algorithm and the expertise
but you're also reusing potentially
enormous amount of compute power that
went into training the model and all of
the training data as well so all four of
those the algorithm the training data
the compute and the expertise all go
into a module which is shareable
tensorflow hub and then you can import
those into your model
and those models those modules are
pre-trained so they have the weights and
the tensor flow graph inside and unlike
a model they're designed to be
composable which means that you can put
them together like building blocks and
add to your own stuff on top they're
reusable which means that they have
common signatures so that you can swap
one for another and they're retraining
Bowl which means that you can actually
back propagate through a module that
you've inserted into your graph so let's
take a quick look at an example in this
case we'll do a little bit of image
classification and say that we want to
make an app to classify rabbit breeds
from photos but we only have a few
hundred example photos probably not
enough to build a whole image classifier
from scratch but what we could do is
start from a general-purpose model and
we could take the reusable part of it
the architecture and the weights their
takeoff the classification and then we
could add our own classifier on top and
train it with our own examples we'll
keep that reusable part fixed and we'll
train our own classifier on top so if
you're using tensorflow hub you start at
tensorflow org / hub where you can find
a whole bunch of newly released
state-of-the-art research-oriented and
the well-known image modules some of
them are include classification and some
of them chop off the class
classification layers and just output
feature vectors so that's what we want
in our own case in this case because
we're going to add classification on top
so maybe we'll choose NASA net which is
a an image module that was created by a
neural architecture search so we'll
choose NASA net a the large version
with the feature vectors so we just
paste the URL for the module into our TF
hub code and then we're ready to use
that module just like a function in
between the module gets downloaded and
instantiate it into your graph so all
you have to do is get those feature
vectors add your own classification on
top and output the the new categories so
specifically what we're doing is
training just the classification part
while keeping all of the modules way
it's fixed but the great thing about
reusing a module is that you get all of
the training and compute that's gone
into that reusable portion so in the
case of nazma it was over 62,000 GPU
hours that went into finding the
architecture and training the model plus
all of the expertise the testing and the
research that went into nazma you're
reusing all of that in that one line of
code and as I mentioned before those
modules are trainable so if you have
enough data you can do fine tuning with
the module if you set that trainable
parameter to true and you select that
you want to use the training graph what
you'll end up doing is training the
entire thing along with your
classification the caveat being that of
course you have to lower the learning
rate so that you don't ruin the weights
inside the module but if you have enough
training data it's something that you
can do to get even better accuracy and
in general we have lots of image modules
on TF hub we have ones that are straight
out of research papers like NASA net we
have ones that are great for production
even once made for on device usage like
mobile net plus all of the industry
standard ones that people are familiar
with like inception and ResNet so let's
look at one more example in this case
doing a little bit of text
classification
we'll do look at some restaurant reviews
and decide whether they're positive or
negative sentiment and one of the great
things about TF hub is that all of those
modules because they're tensor flow
graphs you can include things like
pre-processing so the text modules that
are available on TF hub take whole
sentences and phrases not just
individual words because they have all
of the tokenization and pre-processing
stored in the graph itself so we'll use
one of those and basically the same idea
we're going to select a sentence
embedding module we'll add our own
classification on top and we'll train it
with our own data but we'll keep the
module itself fixed and just like before
we'll start by going to tensorflow org
slash hub and take a look at the text
modules that are available in this case
maybe we'll choose the universal
sentence encoder which is just recently
released based on a research paper from
last month the idea is that it was
trained on a variety of tasks and is
specifically meant to support using it
with a variety of tasks and it also
takes just a very small amount of
training data to use it in your model
which is perfect for our example case so
we'll use that universal sentence
encoder and just like before we'll paste
the URL into our code the difference
here is we're using it with a text
embedding column that way we can feed it
into one of the high-level tensorflow
estimators in this case the DNN
classifier but you could also use that
module it like I showed in the earlier
example calling it just as a function if
you are using the text and embedding
column that also just like any other
example can be trained as well and just
like any other example it's something
that you can do with a lower learning
rate if you have a lot of training data
and it may give you better accuracy
and so we have a lot of text modules
available on TF we actually just added
three new languages to the nn/lm modules
Chinese Korean and Indonesian those are
all trained on G news training data and
we also have a really great module
called Elmo from some recent research
which understands words in context and
of course the universal a sentence
encoder as I talked about so just to
show you for a minute some of those URLs
that we've been looking at maybe we'll
take apart the pieces here
TF hub dev is our new source for Google
and selected partner published modules
in this case this is Google that's the
publisher and new universal sentence
encoder is the name of the module the
one at the end is a version number so
tensorflow hub considers modules to be
immutable and so the version number is
there so that if you're you know doing
one training run and then another you
don't have a situation where the the
module change changes unexpectedly so
all modules on TF abductive are version
that way and one of the nice things
about those URLs if you paste them into
a browser you get the module
documentation the idea being that maybe
you read a new paper you see oh there's
a URL for TF hub module and it you paste
it into your browser you see the
documentation you paste it into some
code and in one line you're able to use
that module and try out the new research
and speaking of the universal encoder
the team just released a new light
version which is a much smaller size
it's about 25 megabytes and it's
specifically designed for cases where
the full text module wouldn't
for doing things like on device
classification also today we released a
new module from deep mind this one you
can feed in video and it will classify
and detect the actions in that video so
in this case it correctly guesses the
video is of people playing cricket and
of course we also have a number of other
interesting modules there's a generative
image module which is trained on Salemme
it has a progressive
gann inside and also the deep local
features module which can identify the
key points of landmark images those are
all available now on TFM and last but
not least I wanted to mention that we
just announced our support for
tensorflow j/s so using the tensorflow
j/s converter you can directly convert a
TF hub module into a format that can be
used on the web it's a really simple
integration to be able to take a module
and use it in the web browser with
sensor flow jas and we're really excited
to see what you build with it so just to
summarize tensorflow
hub is designed to be a starting point
for reusable machine learning and the
idea is just like with a software
repository before you start from scratch
check out what's available on tensorflow
hub and you may find that it's better to
start with a module and import that into
your model rather than starting the task
completely from scratch we have a lot of
modules available and we're adding more
all the time
and we're really excited to see what you
built so thanks next up is jeremiah to
talk about TF serving
all right thank you Andrew so next
tensorflow serving this is going to be
how we deploy modules our deploy models
just to get a sense for where this falls
in the machine learning process right we
start with our data we use tensorflow to
train a model in the output our artifact
there are these models right these are
saved models it's a graphical
representation of the data flow and once
we have those we want to share them with
the world
that's where tensorflow serving comes in
it's this big orange box so this is
something that takes our models and
exposes them to the world through a
service so clients can make requests
tensorflow serving will take them run
the inference run the model come up with
an answer and return that in a response
so tensorflow serving is actually the
libraries and binary is you need to do
this to do this production-grade
inference overtrained tensorflow models
it's written in c++ and supports things
like G RPC and plays nicely with
kubernetes so to do this well it has a
couple of features the first and most
important is it supports multiple models
so on one tensor flow model server you
can load multiple models right and just
like most folks probably wouldn't push a
new binary right to production you don't
want to push a new model right to
production either so having these
multiple models in memory lets you be
serving one model on production traffic
and load a new one and maybe send it
some canary request send it some QA
requests make sure everything's all
right
and then move the traffic over to that
new model and this supports doing things
like reloading if you have a stream of
models you're producing pensive low
serving will transparently load the new
ones and unload the old ones we've built
in a lot of isolation if you have a
model that's serving a lot of traffic in
one thread and it's time to load a new
model you make sure
do that in a separate thread that way we
don't cause any hiccups in the thread
that's serving production traffic and
again this entire system has been built
from the ground up to be very high
throughput things like selecting those
different models based on the name or
selecting different versions that's very
very efficient similarly it has some
advanced batching right this way we can
make use of accelerators we also see
improvements on standard CPUs with this
batching and then lots of other
enhancements everything from protocol
buffer magic to lots more and this is
really what we use inside Google to
serve tensorflow I think there's over
1,500 projects that use it it serves
somewhere in the neighborhood of 10
million QPS which ends up being about a
hundred million items predicted per
second and we're also seeing some
adoption outside of Google one of the
new things I'd like to share today is
distributed serving so looking inside
Google we've seen a couple of trends one
is that models are getting bigger and
bigger some of the ones inside Google
are over a terabyte in size the other
thing we're seeing is this sharing of
sub-graphs right TF hub is producing
these common pieces of models and we're
also seeing more and more specialization
in these models as they get bigger and
bigger right if you look at some of
these model structures they look less
like a model that would belong on one
machine and more like an entire system
so that's this is exactly what
distributed serving is meant for kinda
lets us take the single model and
basically break it up into micro
services so to get a better feel for
that will say that andrew has taken his
rabbit classifier and is serving it on a
model server and we'll say that I want
to create a similar system to classify
cat breeds and so I've done the same
thing I've started from tensorflow hub
so you can see I've got the tensorflow
hub module in the center there and
you'll notice that since we both started
from the same module we
the same bits of code we have the same
core to our mission their model so what
we can do is we can start a third server
and we can put the tensorflow hub module
on that server and we can remove it from
the servers on the outside and leave in
its place this placeholder we call a
remote op you can think of this as a
portal it's kind of a forwarding op that
when we run the inference it forwards at
the appropriate point in the in the
processing to the model server there the
computation is done and the result gets
sent back and the computation continues
on our classifiers on the outside so
there's a few reasons we might want to
do this right we can get rid of some
duplication now we only have one model
server loading all these weights we also
get the benefit that that can batch
requests that are coming from both sides
and also we can set up different
configurations you can imagine we might
have this model server just loaded with
TP use our tensor processing units so
that it can do what are most likely
convolutional operations and things like
that very efficiently so another place
where we use this is with large sharded
models so if you're familiar with deep
learning there's this technique of
embedding things like words or YouTube
video IDs as a string of numbers right
we represent them as this vector of
numbers and if you have a lot of words
or you have a lot of YouTube videos
you're gonna have a lot of data so much
that it won't fit on one machine so we
use a system like this to split up those
embeddings for the words into these
shards and we can distribute there and
of course the main model when it needs
something can reach out get it and then
do the computation another example is
what we call triggering models so we'll
say we're building a spam detector and
we have a full model which is a very
very powerful spam detector you know
maybe it looks at the words understands
the context it's very powerful but it's
very expensive and we can't afford to
run it on every single email message we
get
so what we do instead is we put this
triggering model in front of it as you
can imagine there's a lot of cases where
we're in a position to very quickly say
yes this is spam or no it's not so for
instance if we get an email that's from
within our own domain maybe we can just
say that's not spam and the triggering
model can quickly return that if it's
something that's difficult it can go
ahead and forward that on to the full
model where it will process it so a
similar concept is this mixture of
experts so in this case let's say we
want to build a system where we're going
to classify the breed of either a rabbit
or a cat so what we're gonna do is we're
gonna have two models we're gonna call
expert models right so we have one
that's an expert at rabbits and another
that's an expert at cats and so here
we're gonna use a gating model to get a
picture of either a rabbit or cat and
the only thing that's gonna do is decide
if it's a rabbit or a cat and forward it
on to the appropriate expert who will
process it and we'll send that that
result back all right there's lots of
use cases we're excited to see what
people start to build with these remote
ops the next thing I'll quickly mention
is a REST API this was one of the top
requests on github so we're happy to be
releasing this soon this will make it
much easier to integrate things with
existing existing services and it's nice
because you don't actually have to
choose on one model server with one
tensorflow model you can serve either
the restful endpoint or the GRP see
there's three api's there's some
higher-level ones like for
classification and regression there's
also a lower-level
predict and this is more of a tensor in
tensor out for the things that don't fit
into classify and regress so looking at
this quickly you can see the URI here we
can specify the model right this may be
like rabbit or cat
we can optionally specify a version and
our verbs are the classify regress and
predict we have two examples the first
one you can see we're asking the iris
model to classify something in here we
aren't giving it a version a model
version so it'll just use the most
recent or the highest version
automatically and the bottom example is
one where we're using the M NIST model
and we're specifying the version to be 3
1 4 and asking it to do a prediction so
this lets you this lets you easily
integrate things and easily version
models and switch between them I'll
quickly mention the API if you're
familiar with tensorflow example you
know that representing it in JSON is a
little bit cumbersome so you can see
it's pretty verbose here there's some
other warts like needing to encode
things base64 instead with tensorflow
serving the RESTful API uses a more
idiomatic JSON which is much more
pleasant much more succinct and here
this last example just kind of pulls it
all together where you can use curl to
actually make predictions from the
command-line so I encourage you to check
out the project that tensorflow serving
there's lots of great documentation and
things like that and we also welcome
contributions and code discussion ideas
on our github project page so I'd like
to finish with James to talk about
tensorflow extended
like all right so I'm gonna start with a
single non-controversial statement this
has been shown true made many times by
many people in short tf-x
is our answer to that statement I'll
start with a simple diagram this core
box represents your machine learning
code
this is the magic bits of algorithms
that actually take the data in and
produce reasonable results the blue
boxes represent everything else you need
to actually use machine learning
reliably and scalably in an actual real
production setting the blue boxes are
going to be where you're spending most
of your time it comprises most of the
lines of code it's also going to be the
source of most of the things that are
selling off your pagers in the middle of
the night in our case if we squint at
this just about correctly the core ml
box looks like tensorflow and all of the
blue boxes together comprise tf-x
so we're gonna quickly run through four
of the key principles that tf-x was
built on first Express ability and tf-x
is gonna be flexible in three ways first
of all we're gonna take advantage of the
flexibility built into tensorflow using
it as our trainer means that we can do
anything tensor for look into at the
model level which means you can have
wide models
deep models supervised models
unsupervised tree models anything that
we can whip up together second were
flexible with regards to input data we
could handle images texts sparse data
multimodal models where you might want
to Train images and surrounding text or
something like videos plus captions
third there are multiple ways you might
go about actually training a model if
your goal is to build a kitten detector
you may have all of your data up front
and your goal may be to build one model
of sufficient high quality and then
you're done
in contrast to that if your goal is to
build a viral kitten video detector or a
personalized kitten recommender then
you're not going to have all of your
data up front so typically your trade a
model get it into production and then as
data comes in
you'll throw away that model and train a
new model and then throw away that model
and train a new model we're actually
throwing out some good data along with
these models though so we can try a worm
starting strategy instead where we'll
continuously train the same model but as
data comes in we'll warm start based on
the previous state of the model and just
add the additional new data this will
let us result in higher quality models
with faster convergence next let's talk
about portability so each of the tf-x
modules represented by the blue boxes
don't need to do all of the heavy
lifting themselves they're part of an
open source ecosystem which means we can
lean on things like tensorflow and take
advantage of its native portability this
means we can run locally we can scale up
and run in a cloud environment we can
scale to devices that you're thinking
about today and to devices that you
might be thinking about tomorrow a large
portion of machine learning is data
processing so we rely on Apache beam
which is built for this task and again
we can take advantage of beams
portability as our own which means we
can use the direct runner locally where
you might be starting out with a small
piece of data building small models to
affirm that your approaches are actually
correct and then scale up into the cloud
with a data flow rudder also utilize
something like the flink runner or
things that are in progress right now
like a spark Runner will see the same
story again with kubernetes where we can
start with mini cube running locally
scale up into the cloud or two clusters
that we have for other purposes and
eventually scale to things that don't
yet exist but they're still in progress
so portability is only part of the
scalability story traditionally we've
seen two very different roles involved
in machine learnings you'll have the
data scientists on one side and be
production infrastructure engineers on
the other side the differences between
these are not just amounts of data but
there are key concerns that each has
about as they go about their daily busy
this with tf-x we can specifically
target use cases that are in common
between the two as well as things that
are specific to the two so this will
allow us to have one unified system that
can scale up to the cloud and down to
smaller environments and actually unlock
collaboration between these two roles
finally we believe heavily in
interactivity we were able to get quick
iterative results with responsive
tooling and fast debugging and there's
interactivity should remain such even at
scale with large sets of data or large
models this is a fairly ambitious goal
so where are we now so today we've
open-sourced a few key areas of
responsibility so we have transform
model analysis serving and facets each
one of these is useful on its own but is
much more so when used in concert with
the others so let's walk through what
this might look like in practice so our
goal here is to take a bunch of data
we've accumulated and do something
useful for our users of our product
these are the steps we want to take
along the way so let's start with step
one with the data we're going to pull
this up in facets and use it to actually
analyze what features might be useful
predictors look for any anomalies so
outliers in our data or missing features
to try to avoid the classic garbage in
garbage out problem and to try to inform
what data we're going to need to further
pre-process before it's useful for our
ml training which leads into our next
step which is to actually use transform
to transform our features so TF
transform will let you do full pass
analysis and transforms of your base
data and it's also very firmly attached
to the TF graph itself which will ensure
that you're applying the same transforms
in training as in serving from the code
you can see that we're taking advantage
of a few ops built into transform and we
could do things like scale generate
vocabularies or bucket eyes our base
data
and this code will look the same
regardless of our execution environment
and of course if you needed to find your
own operations you can do so so this
puts us at the point where we're
strongly suspicious that we have data we
can actually use to generate a model so
let's look at doing that we're going to
use a ten circle estimator which is a
high level API that will let us quickly
define train and export our model this
is a small set of estimators that are
present in court tensorflow there are a
lot more available and you can also
create your own we're going to look
ahead to some future steps and we're
gonna purposefully export two graphs
into our saved model one specific
disserving
and one specific to model evaluation and
again from the code you can see that
we're good in this case we're going to
use a white and deep model we're gonna
define it we're gonna train it we're
gonna do our exports so now we have a
model we could just push this directly
to production but that would probably be
a very bad idea so let's try to gain a
little more confidence and what would
happen if we actually did so for our
end-users so we're gonna step into TF
model analysis we're gonna utilize this
to evaluate our model over a large data
set and then we're going to define in
this case one but you could possibly use
many slices of this data that we want to
analyze independently from others this
will allow us to actually look at
subsets of our data that may be
representative of subsets of our users
and how our metrics actually track
between these groups for example you may
have sets of users in different
languages maybe access different devices
or maybe you have a very small but
passionate community of rabbit
aficionados mixed in with your larger
community of kitten fanatics and you
want to make sure that your model will
actually give a positive experiences to
both groups equally
so now we have a model that we're
confident in and we want to push it to
serving so let's get this up and for
some queries at it so this is quick now
we have a model up we have a server
listening on port 9000 for G RPC
requests so now we're going to back out
into our actual products code we can
assemble individual prediction requests
and then we can send them out to our
server
and if this slide doesn't look like your
actual code and this one looks more
similar than you'll be happy to see that
this is coming soon I'm treating a
little by showing you this now as
current state but we're super excited
about this and this is one of those real
soon now scenarios so that's today
what's coming next so first please
contribute and join the tensor flood org
community we don't want the only time
that we're talking back and forth here
to be at summits and conferences
secondly some of you may have seen the
tf-x paper at kdd last year this
specifies what we believe an end-to-end
platform actually looks like here it is
and by we believing that this is what it
looks like this is what it looks like
this is actually what's powering some of
the pretty awesome AI first products
that you've been seeing at i/o and that
you've probably been using yourselves
but again this is where we are now ss
right now this is not the full platform
but you can see what we're aiming for
and we'll get there eventually so again
please download this software use it to
make good things and send us feedback
and thank you from all of us for being
current and future users and for
choosing to spend your time with us
today
[Applause]
[Music]