[Music]
hi and welcome to ask tensorflow the
show where you get to ask questions
about tensorflow and we will try to
answer them my name is Magnus it's 10
I work as a developer advocate on the
tensorflow team and I'm Laurence Moroney
also a developer advocate on the team so
let's get started the first question is
from Bern burst on Twitter and the
question is how about advice on the
suitable data set for a learning
experience on tensorflow
that's a great question yes it is
there's a few that are great for
starting there's always kaggle who has
lots of open data sets that you can use
so if you don't have a user account on
Carole you should definitely check it
out
also models that are bundled will
tensorflow
you can find these in the tensorflow
slash models github directory and many
of them are from well-known AI /ml
problems including things like the
m-miss data set which is really the
hello world or machine learning to that
allows you to help classify handwritten
digits they can even detect my
handwriting it's doing something there's
also a tutorial called wide and deep
that uses census data from the UC irvine
machine learning repository indeed you
can find lots of data sets in that
repository to play with I actually found
one for a tutorial that I was writing
and it was from the West
Wisconsin breast cancer research data
and that was in the UC Irvine machine
learning repository so I wrote a
tutorial around that and you can see it
in the links underneath so the next
question comes from NAT Carly on Twitter
and not asks can I retrain a model to
recognize an object is something else
for example if it sees a sunflower and I
want to classify that as a weed instead
so this all falls into something that we
call retraining and the concept of
retraining removes the last layer which
contains the class labels and allows you
to relearn it with your own labels now
it's too long for me to explain it here
but fortunately we have something called
a tensor flow for poets code lab I've
put a link in the description below in
that code lab you'll take a look at the
standard mobile net code lab and retrain
it specifically for flowers I'd strongly
recommend looking into that and having a
play with it yeah it's a very common
technique in fact you can train a model
quite easy
silly with not so many example using
this kind of methodology which speeds
things up to right now yeah and the next
question is from Karim on Twitter and
the question is what's your best advice
for a computer science student to begin
in AI /ml the top three things to do top
three it's hard to think of just three
right yeah well I think a clear number
one is to learn Python not just for ml
but also because it's a staggeringly
cool and useful language I can't believe
the things I've been able to achieve as
since I learned and it's used everywhere
in machine learning and data science so
my number two after I've learned Python
would be to study some of the math
that's used in ml and it might be the
girl who don't want to learn math but
it's really not that bad and the two
parts of math that I really look into
number one would be regression so
regression is all around fitting align
two points in two dimension or a plane
two points in three dimensions as well
as getting into higher-order dimensions
and then the other one is matrices and
understanding how matrices fit the
picture for handling this higher-order
dimensional math so how to multiply and
transpose matrices and all that kind of
thing mm-hmm
how about number three number three my
number three would then be to practice
on simple examples then there are do
some great data sets out there as we
mentioned at the top of the show you
should download them play with them in a
spreadsheet and do correlations and
stuff and then you should load them into
a machine learning model to see if you
can do some classification and above all
have fun with it
yeah and there's so many amazing things
you can do with even quite simple models
so you should really go out there and
just try things out and if you love what
you do you'll do what you love yeah
right so next question this one comes
from Mitsuki in Tokyo and MIT's kiosks
at i/o last year we heard about TP use
when and how will they be available well
arigato meet Sachi that's a fabulous
question and fortunately it's really
easy to answer because they're now
available for you to play with in beta
there are details of the URL at the blog
post that I've linked underneath now
with some of the things we've have
there's some really really impressive
power available so the TP user that are
available on the cloud platform
pack up to a hundred and eighty
teraflops of floating-point performance
and about 64 gigabytes of high bandwidth
memory on a single board 180 teraflops
tariff teraflops that's a that's a Giga
gigaflop arraign that's a lot of flops
so we actually did a test on one of
these and a trained resonate 50 in less
than a day and when we actually posted
the first blog post about this we said
it cost less than two hundred dollars in
total we've actually been doing
retraining since then and it's come
closer to 100 dollars in total to train
a complete resonate 50 so how does this
work well TPU usage is paid for by the
second so the faster you go effectively
the cheaper it is and we have a tutorial
about using TP use to Train ResNet let's
add a little underneath I'd love to hear
what you're planning to do and the type
of machine learning you're going to be
doing so thanks everybody
again a lot of really really fun
questions some great stuff that we've
been able to look into we hope we've
been able to help you with answers to
these questions
I'm Lawrence and this is Magnus and
remember if you've got any more
questions for us please leave them in
the comments below or better still post
them on social media with the hashtag
ask tensorflow and we'll be here to
answer them for you
thank you so much
[Music]