welcome everybody to tensorflow meets
and this is our very first episode of
this show tensorflow meets is a show
where we meet with people in the
community who are working with
tensorflow
today it's my honor to meet finally with
chip she's teaching the famous cs20
course at Stanford I have to tell a
story before we begin about how I met
chip so I was studying and studying some
AI in Stanford and there was a robotics
course what was the instructor great
instruction he's amazing super cool guy
and the first homework assignment came
in and I did not have a clue years ago
was it that long okay and I just
remember and it was like you had offered
fit to help and like I was totally stuck
with this thing I chipped kind of
scribbled this thing on a napkin and
scanned it and emailed it to me and I
was like then suddenly I knew what was
going on and a second I knew this girl
was going to go places after that and
now look at you you're teaching you just
say that so as a tower
actually still considering doing an
English major because I came to Stanford
as a as a writer before Stanford I was
like trembling a little bit and then
wrote a couple of books and I really
liked writing but then I took this one
CS course I see us on 6 a.m. I everyone
s neighbor takes this 106a everybody yes
right yes and he said like okay like you
work here then you sort of like had to
take this course and take you to the
stand robotics right of the course
doctors I did like see us more and more
and yeah ya know you had written like
travel books in Vietnam right I'd like
to call them stories it was traveling
for almost three years like in Asia
Africa and South America
and it'll books about people I met and
what I saw and what I thought of their
life it was a whole new world to me like
that in so it's a journey from like
travel and meeting people about life and
then coming to study like an English
major and then in CS and now teaching AI
so tell us about the course I has an
idea when I was a sophomore and it was
doing one class natural language
processing and the course used
tensorflow I started digging into the
library and they did it all during the
summer I use it for my job at a startup
it was pretty early
of the tensile flow progress so there
was not a lot of documentation okay I
had a lot of trouble trying to figure
out what you do and and then I look into
the source code and get up and I said
wow this is like such a huge library
with so many amazing talks and why does
like what did they know by it before
maybe there should be a group we were
can just meet and learn from each other
and so I told you some of my professors
Stanford and we have a course on this of
flow and they were like we are too busy
to teach it so you know this is your
secondary of teaching it right now yeah
how's it been like picked up by students
do they like it um for me as a student
I'm not I for me two pictures of course
I need a faculty sponsorship and Chris
Manning was a person who did it and he
advertised a course on a very popular
course that he was teaching so the first
year was pretty overwhelming we got like
350 applications Wow I was only allowed
to take 20 because I'm not allowed to
like take more students than that nicely
yeah things the feedback was a pretty
positive and then Stanford
let me do it again look at more students
but I because I'm still carrying of food
work roles as a student stand for so I
don't think I'm I'm ready for like a lot
of students so this year we have about a
40 okay yeah it takes me on average 20
hours a week one lecture there to
lecture so doesn't mean 40 hours it's a
full-time job that's just a lot of time
a lot of the information that you've put
together for the course is available to
the public right your code is on github
and stuff like that
have you seen like any uptake from
students or from people outside using
your code or learning from your code I
think it was surprised at how many uses
so I guess use a github repo just shake
it on and I was like wow do you know
that's like they're like an average like
2,000 visitors I've only recently joined
the tensorflow team and just in the last
couple of months so I've been scouring
the web for things to learn how am I
gonna learn this how am I gonna learn
that and almost every like site that I
fall on well people always end up
pointing back to your github repo so
it's okay if you want to learn how to do
like a linear regression look at chips
codon if you want to learn how to do
this look at chips code so it's just
saying some of it is a bit embarrassing
because now because this year when I'm
preparing
again I redirect them notes from last
night oh my god is this you know like
when it when you try to make a joke but
it wasn't funny it just showed on the
paper it was like oh my God why did I
even do that
it's it's a constant process of
improving it's the same when you're
doing developer advocacy work it's like
sometimes like I look back on talks that
I've done it like no those jokes didn't
work I'm glad I get a chance to do it
again so I can have a slightly more
polished so say I'm a developer and like
I'm a typical software developer right
now and I really want to get into the AI
machine learning and there's a there's a
whole universe of technologies out there
AI nml what advice would you give me I
think it's a bit hard way to get advice
okay I think of myself as somebody who's
a starting I have been doing it for like
a little bit two years now it's because
it's such a nascent technology two years
is a long time so your experience is
very valuable so I think is it really
depends on on what exactly you want to
get into because yeah like MLA is very
broad so you can either become a
software developer so you can develop
tools like as a flow or pie chart you
can also be like apply research finishes
when you apply this a new research into
into production or I can just become a
very pure researcher so I come up with
new algorithms you know your new
architectures so for me um are they make
as for me I have always wanted to become
a researcher so in fact that for that
massive math is very important to me and
Jay brow need to know a matrix-matrix
multiplication yeah yeah so I think it
would recommend that you nature gets up
leadership brought back growl like shut
up and dinner so me some probability
okay background because everything is
indeed you Bhushan in this and anything
read a lot of papers so some advice that
have got from people who are in the fail
for a long time this is tell me to read
a lot of papers like this tell me like
in every morning check okay like
whatever photo like most popular papers
oh wow and yes dedication yeah just like
review them I like scheme does the
abstract she doesn't so know that they
what I go up to in the field right and
then take a lot of online courses
there's so many online courses available
for free and I yeah and after needs a
paper you can add implement it yourself
like yes you try because you cannot
render standard paper until you actually
like a man was a paper something about
and also can look at how other people
implement that um online just to compare
like the way you approach a problem
that's the magic of open source yeah and
like as we're talking about early run
like the open source that you've written
for your course that's on github has
been very valuable for me learning it as
well as for lots of other people you
just say thank ya you're welcome you're
welcome so thank you so much for being
on the show chip thank you so much for
having me oh you're very welcome and
we've learned so much and thanks
everybody for watching this episode of
tensorflow meets remember this show is
about you it's a show for the community
where we would love to have you on the
show where tensorflow meets you and
talks with you about what you do if
you've got any questions for me if
you've got any questions for chip please
leave them in the comments below and if
you want to be on the show if you're
doing something interesting please get
in touch with us and remember don't
forget to hit that subscribe button for
more great tensorflow content
bye
[Music]