hi everybody and welcome to this session
where we're going to talk about
breakthroughs and machine learning I'm
Laurence Moroney I'm a developer
advocate at Google are working on
tensorflow with the Google brain team
we're here today to talk about the
revolution that's going on in machine
learning and how that revolution is
transformative now
I come from a software development
background any software developers here
given that at i/o sure and this is this
transformation this revolution is
particularly from a developer's
perspective is really really cool
because it's giving us a whole new set
of tools that we can use to build
scenarios and to build solutions for
problems that may have been too complex
to even consider prior to this it's also
leading to massive advances in our
understanding of things like the
universe around us it's opening up new
fields in arts and it's impacting and
revolutionising things such as
healthcare and so many more things so
should we take a look at some of these
so first of all astronomy at school I
studied physics I wasn't the comm site
person so I'm a physics and astronomy
geek and it wasn't that long ago when we
learned how to discover what new how new
planets around other stars in our galaxy
and what the way that we discovered it
was that sometimes would observe like a
little wobble in the star and that meant
that there was a very large planet like
Jupiter size or even bigger
orbiting that star very closely and
causing a wobble because of the
gravitational attraction but of course
the kind of planets we want to find out
the small rocky ones like our earth on
Mars where you know there's a chance of
finding life on these planets and
finding those and discovering those was
very very difficult to do because small
ones close to the star you just wouldn't
see but there's with research that's
been going on in the Kepler mission
they've actually recently discovered
this planet called Kepler 90i
by sifting through data and building
models for using machine learning and
using tensorflow and Kepler 90i is
actually much closer to its host star
than Earth is so that its orbit is only
14 days instead of our 365 and a quarter
in a bitch and not only that which I
find really cool but they didn't just
find this as a single planet around that
star they've actually mapped and
the entire solar system of eight planets
that are there so these are some of the
advances it's it to me I find it's just
a wonderful time to be alive because
technology is enabling us to discover
these great new things and even closer
to home we've also discovered that
looking at scans of the human eye as you
would have seen in the keynotes you know
with machine learning trained models on
this we've been able to discover things
such as blood pressure predictions or
being able to assess a person's risk of
a heart attack or a stroke now just
imagine if this screening can be done on
a small mobile phone now how profound is
the effect going to be suddenly the
whole world is going to be able to
access easy rapid affordable and
non-invasive screening for things such
as heart diseases
it'll be saving many lives but it will
also be improving the quality of many
many more lives now these are just a few
of the breakthroughs and advances that
have been made because of tensorflow
intensive flow we've been working hard
with the community with all of you to
make this a machine learning platform
for everybody so today I want we want to
share a few of the new advances that
have been working on this so including
we'll be looking at robots and Vincents
going to come out in a few moments to
show us robots that learn and some of
the work that they've been doing to
improve how robots learn and then Debbie
is going to be from Newark she's going
to be showing us cosmology advancements
and including showing how building a
simulation of the entire universe will
help us understand the nature of the
unknowns in our universe like dark
matter and dark energy but first of all
I would love to welcome from the magenta
team we have Doug who's a principal
scientist Doug thanks Lawrence hey
thanks Doug thank you very much
all right day three we're getting there
hi everybody I'm Doug I am a research
scientist at Google working on a project
called magenta and so before we talk
about modeling the entire known universe
so we talked about robots I want to talk
to you a little bit about music and art
and how to use machine learning
potentially for expressive purposes so I
want to talk first about a drawing
project called sketch RNN where we
trained a neural network to do something
as important as draw the pig that you
see on the right there and I want to use
this as an example to actually highlight
a few I think important machine learning
concepts that were finding to be crucial
for using machine learning in the
context of art and music so let's dive
in there's gonna be able to get a little
technical but hopefully it'll be fun for
you all what we're gonna do is try to
learn to draw not by generating pixels
but actually by generating pen strokes
and I think this is a very interesting
representation to use because it's very
close to what we do when we draw so
specifically we're going to take the
data from the very popular quick-draw
game playing pictionary against machine
learning algorithm and that was captured
as Delta X Delta Y movements of the pen
we also know when the pen is put down on
the page and when the pen is lifted up
okay and we're gonna treat that as our
training domain one thing what I would
notice is that our observe is that we
didn't necessarily need a lot of this
data what's nice about the data is that
it fits the creative process it's closer
to drawing I argue than pixels are to
drawing it's actually modeling the
movement of the pen now what we're going
to do with these drawings is we're going
to push them through something called an
auto encoder what you're seeing on the
left the encoder networks job is to take
those strokes of that cat and encode
them in some way so that they can be
stored as a latent vector the yellow box
in the middle the job of the decoder is
to decode that latent vector back into a
generated sketch and the very important
point in fact the only point that you
really need to take away from this talk
is that that latent vector is worth
everything to us
first it's smaller in size than the
encoded or decoded drawing so it can't
memorize everything and because it can't
memorize we actually get some nice
effects for example you might notice if
you look carefully that
cat on the left which is actual data and
it's been pushed through the trained
model and decoded is not the same as the
cat on the right right the cat on the
left has five whiskers but the model
regenerated the sketch with six whiskers
why because that's what it usually sees
six whiskers is general its normal to
the model whereas five whiskers is hard
for the model to make sense of so this
idea of having a tight low dimensional
representation this latent vector that's
been trained on lots of data the goal is
that this model might learn to find some
of the generalities in a drawing learn
general strategies for creating
something so here's an example of
starting each of the four corners with a
drawing done by a human David the first
author and those are encoded in the
corners and now we just move linearly
around the space not the space of the
strokes but the space of the latent
vector and if you look closely what I
think you'll see is that the movements
and the changes from these faces say
from left to right are actually quite
smooth the model has dreamt up all of
those faces in the middle yet to my eye
they really do kind of fill the space of
possible drawings finally as I pointed
out with the cat whiskers these models
generalize not memorize it's not that
interesting to memorize a drawing it's
much more interesting to learn general
strategies for drawing and so we see
that with the five to six wizard cat I
think more interestingly and I think
it's also suggestive we also see this
with doing something like taking a model
that's only seen pigs and giving it a
picture of a truck and what's that model
going to do it's going to find a pig
truck because that's all it knows about
right and if that seems silly which I
grant it is in your own mind think about
how how hard it would be at least for me
if someone says draw a truck that looks
like a pig it's actually kind of hard to
make that transformation and these
models do it finally by the way they
they I get paid to do this I just want
to point that out as an aside so it's
kind of nice I said that last year it's
still true okay so these late and spaced
analogies another example of what's
happening in these Leighton spaces
obviously if you add and subtract pen
strokes you're not going to get far with
making something that's that's
recognizable but if you have a look at
the
these latent spaced analogies we take
the latent vector for a cat head and we
add a pig body and we subtract the pig
head and of course it stands to reason
that you should get a cat body and we
can do the same thing in Reverse and
this is real data this actually works
and the reason I mentioned it is it
shows that these latent space models are
learning some of the geometric relations
between the forms that people draw I'm
gonna switch gears now and move from
drawing to music and talk a little bit
about a model called n sense which is a
neural network synthesizer that takes
audio and learns to generalize in the
space of music you may have seen from
the beginning of I Oh with bathing that
this has been put into a hardware unit
called instant super how many people
have heard of Henson super how many
people want an instant super good ok
well that's possible as you know ok so I
want to for those of you that didn't see
the opening I have a short version of
the making of the instant super I like
to roll that now to give you guys a
better idea of what this model is up to
let's let's roll it now I just feel like
we're turning a corner and what could be
new possibilities
it could generate a sound that might
inspire resume the fun part is like even
though you think you know what you're
doing there's some weird interaction
happening that can give you something
totally unexpected why wait why did that
happen that way okay so what you see
here by the way the last person with the
long hair was Jesse Engel who was the
the main scientist on the instance
project this grid that you're seeing
this square where you can move around
the space is exactly the same idea as we
saw with those faces so the idea is that
you're moving around the Layton space
and you're able to discover sounds that
hopefully have some similarity and
because they're made up of learning what
makes humans you know how sound works
for us and the same way as a pig truck
gives us maybe some new ideas about how
sound works and as you probably know you
can make these yourself which i think is
my mind my favorite part about the
instant super project is that this is an
open-source github for those of you who
are makers and like to tinker please
give it a shot if not we'll see some
coming available from tons of people who
are building them on their own so I want
to keep going with music but I want to
move away from audio and I want to move
now to musical scores you know musical
notes something that you know think of
last night with with justice driving a
sequencer and talk about basically the
same idea which is can we learn a late
in space where we can move around what's
possible in in in a musical note or a
musical score rather so what you see
here is some three-part musical thing on
the top and some one part musical thing
on the bottom and then finding in a
latent space something that's in between
okay
and now I put the faces underneath this
what you're looking at now is a
representation of a musical drum score
where time is passing left to right and
what we're going to see is we're going
to start I'm going to play this for you
it's a little bit long so I want to set
this up we're gonna start with a drum
beat one measure of drums and we're
going to end with one measure of drums
and you're going to hear
those first you're gonna hear a and B
and then you're gonna hear this latent
space model try to figure out how to get
from A to B and everything in between is
made up by the model in exactly the same
way that the faces in the middle are
made up by the model so as you're
listening basically listen for whether
it makes musical sense or not that the
intermediate drums
let's give it a roll
[Music]
so you have it moving right along
it turns out take a look at this command
this make sense to some of you maybe we
were surprised to learn after a year of
doing magenta that this is not the right
way to work with musicians and artists I
know I laugh too but we really thought
hey it's a great idea guys
it's like paste this into terminal and
they're like what's terminal and then
you know you're in trouble right okay so
we've we've moved quite a bit towards
trying to build tools that musicians can
use this is a drum machine actually that
you can play with online built around
tensorflow Jas and I have a short clip
of this being used what you're going to
see is all the red is from you as a
musician you can play around with it and
then the blue is generated by the model
so let's give this a roll this one's
quite a bit shorter
[Music]
so this is available for you as a code
pen which allows you to play around at
the HTML and the CSS and the JavaScript
and really amazing a huge shout out to
taro par vienen who who did this he
grabbed one of our trained magenta
models and he used tensorflow Jas and he
hacked a bunch of code to make it work
and he put it out on Twitter and we had
no idea this was happening and then we
reached out to him I reached out to my
Twitter I said taro you're my hero this
is awesome and he's like oh you guys
care about this my King of course we
care about this this is our dream to
have people not just us playing with
this technology so I love it that we've
gotten there so part of what I want to
talk about today actually close with
we've cleaned up a lot of the code in
fact taro helped and we've now were able
to introduce magenta that Jas which is
very tightly integrated with tensorflow
Jas and it allows you for example to
grab a check pointed model and set up a
player and start sampling from it so in
three lines of code you can set up a
little drum machine or music sequencer
and we're also doing the same thing with
sketch RNN so we have the art side as
well and we've seen a lot of demos
driven by this a lot of really
interesting work both by Googlers and by
people from the outside and I think it
highly aligns well with what we're doing
in magenta so to close we're doing
research and generative models we're
working to engage with musicians and
artists very happy to see that
JavaScript stuff come along which is
really seems to be the language for that
hoping to see better tools come and
heavy engagement with the open-source
community if you want to learn more
please visit GG echo slash magenta also
you can follow my Twitter account I post
regular updates and try to be a
connector for that so that's what I have
for you and now I'd like to switch gears
and go to robots very exciting with my
colleague from Google brain vincent van
nuke thank you very much
[Applause]
thanks Doug
so my name is Benson and I lead the
brain robotics research team the
robotics research team at Google we when
you think about robots you may think
about precision and control you may
think about robots you know live in
factories they've got one very specific
job to do and they gotta do it over and
over again but as you saw in the keynote
earlier more and more robots are about
people right they're self-driving cars
that are driving in our streets
interacting with people they essentially
now live in our world not their world
and so they they really have to adapt
and perceive the world around them and
learn how to operate in this human
centric environment right so how do we
get robots to learn instead of having to
program them this is what we've been
embarking on and it turns out we can get
robots to learn it takes a lot of robots
it takes a lot of time and but we can
actually improve on this if we teach
robots how to behave collaboratively so
this is an example of a team of robots
that are learning together how to do a
very simple task like grasping objects
right at the FIR at the beginning they
have no idea what they're doing they try
and try and try and sometimes they will
grasp something every time they grasp
something we give them a reward and over
time they get better and better at it of
course we use deep learning for this we
basically have a convolutional network
that maps those images that the robots
see of the workspace in front of them to
actions and possible actions and this
collective learning of robots enables us
to get to levels of performance that we
haven't seen before but it takes a lot
of robots
in fact you know this is Google we would
much rather use lots of computers if we
could instead of lots of robots and so
the question becomes could we actually
use a lot of simulated robots virtual
robots to do this kind of tasks and
teach those robots to perform tasks and
would it actually matter in the real
world would they what they learn in
simulation actually apply to real tasks
and and it turns out the key to making
this work is to learn simulations that
are more and more faithful to reality so
on the right here you see what a typical
simulation of a robot would look like
this is a virtual robot trying to grasp
objects and simulation what you see on
the other side here may look like a real
robots doing the same task but in fact
it is completely simulated as well we've
learned a machine learning model that
map's
those simulated images to real images to
real looking images there are
essentially indistinguishable from what
a real robot would see in the real world
and by using this kind of data in a
simulated environment and training a
simulated model to accomplish tasks
using those images we can actually
transfer that information and make it
work in the real world as well so
there's lots of things we can do with
these kinds of simulated robots this is
Rainbow Dash our favorite little pony
and what you see here here is him taking
his very first steps and our very first
hops I should say he's really good for
somebody who's just starting to learn
how to walk and the way we accomplish
this is by having a virtual Rainbow Dash
running in simulation we train it using
deep reinforcement learning to run
around in the simulator and then we can
only basically download the model that
we've learned the simulation on to the
real robots and actually make it work in
the real world as well
there are many ways we can scale up
robotics and robotic learning in this
way one of the key ingredients turns out
to be learning by itself self
supervision self learning this is an
example of for example what you see at
the top here is somebody driving a car
and what we're trying to learn in this
instance is the 3d structure of the
world the geometry of everything what
you see at the bottom here is a
representation of how far things are
from the car right you probably are
looking at avoiding obstacles and
looking at other cars to not collide
with them and so you want to learn about
the 3d geometry based on those videos
the traditional way that you would do
this is by involving for example a 3d
camera or a lighter or something that
gives you a sense of depth here we're
going to do none of that we're going to
simply look at the video and learn
directly from the video the 3d structure
of the world and the way to do this is
to look at the video and try to predict
the future of this video you can imagine
that if you actually understand the 3d
geometry of the world you can do a
pretty good job at predicting what's
going to happen next in a video so we're
going to use that signal that tells us
how well we're doing at predicting the
future to learn what the 3d geometry of
the world looks like so at the end of
the day what we end up with is yet
another big convolutional network that
map's what you see at the top to what
you see at the bottom without involving
any 3d camera or anything like that this
idea of self learning or just learning
without any supervision directly from
the data is really really powerful
another problem that we have when we're
trying to teach robots how to do things
is that we have to communicate to them
what we want what we care about right
and the best way you can do that is by
simply showing them what you want them
to perform so here is an example
one of my colleagues basically doing the
robot dance and robots that is just
looking at him performing those tasks
and trying to imitate visually what he
is doing and what's remarkable here is
that you know even though the robot for
example doesn't have legs it tries to do
this crouching motion as best it can
given the agrees of freedom that it has
available and all of this is learn
entirely self supervise the way we go
about this is that if you think about
imitating somebody else for example
somebody pouring a glass of water or
kind of coke and it all relies on you
being able to look at them from a third
party view and picturing yourself doing
the same thing from your point of view
what it would look like if you did the
same thing yourself right so we
collected some of this data that looks
like that where you have somebody
looking at somebody else to do a task
and you end up with those two videos of
one taken by the person doing the task
and I know the one taken by another
person and what we want to teach the
robots is that those two things are
actually the same thing so we're going
to use again machine learning to perform
this match up we're gonna have a machine
learning model that is going to tell us
okay this image on the left is actually
of the same task as this image on the
right and once we've learned that
correspondence with lots of things we
can do with this one of them is just
imitation like this imagine you have
somebody pouring a glass of water the
robot sees them they try to picture
themselves doing the same task and try
best they can to imitate what they're
doing and so using again deep
reinforcement learning we can train
robots to learn those kinds of
activities completely based on visual
observation without any programming of
any kind so I won't let that robot for
me appear quite yet but it's very
encouraging that we can just look have
robots that understand essentially what
the name
sure what the fundamentals of the task
is regardless of whether they're pouring
a liquid or they're pouring beads or
whatever the glasses look like or the
containers all of that is abstracted and
the robot actually really understand
deeply what the task is about so I'm
very excited about this whole
perspective on teaching robots how to
learn instead of having to program them
right at some point I would want to be
able to tell my google assistant hey ok
Google
please go for my laundry right and for
that to happen we're gonna have to
rebuild the science of Robotics from the
ground up you're going to have to base
it on understanding and machine learning
and perception and of course we're going
to have to do that at Google scale with
that I'm going to give the stage to
Debbie who's going to talk to us about
cosmology thank you
[Applause]
thank you good afternoon everyone my
name is Debbie Bart I'm we're talking
about something a little bit different
from what you've heard so far so I lead
the data science engagement group at
nurse a nurse is the national energy
research scientific computing Center
we're a supercomputing Center at
Lawrence Berkeley National Lab just over
the bay from here we are the mission
computing Center for the Department of
Energy Office of Science and what this
means is that we have something like
7,000 scientists are using our
supercomputers to work on some of the
biggest questions in science today and
what I think is really cool as well is
that I get to work with some of the most
powerful computers on the planet one of
the things that we're noticing
especially in the last couple of years
is we've seen that scientists are
increasingly turning to deep learning
and machine learning methods to solve
some of these big questions that they're
working on I was seeing these questions
showing up in our workload on our
supercomputers so I want to focus on one
particular topic area it's very close to
my heart which is cosmology because I'm
a cosmologists are aiming my background
is in cosmology research because I've
always been interested in the really the
most fundamental questions that we have
in science about the nature of the
universe and perhaps one of the most
basic questions you can ask about the
universe is what is it made of and these
days we have a fairly good feel for how
much dark energy there is in the
universe how much dark matter how much
regular matter there is in the universe
and there's only about 5% of regular
matter which is everything that you and
I and all the stars and all the dust and
all the gas and all the galaxies out
there they're made of regular matter and
that makes up a pretty tiny proportion
of the contents of the universe the
thing that I find really interesting is
we don't just don't know what the rest
of it is dark matter we don't know what
that's made of but we see indirectly the
gravitational effect it has dark energy
we don't know what that is at all that
was only recently discovered about 15
years ago and dark energy just the name
that we give to an observation
which is the accelerated expansion of
the universe and this is I think really
exciting the fact that there is so much
that we have yet to discover means that
there are tremendous possibilities for
new ways for us to understand our
universe and we are building a bigger
and better telescopes we're collecting
data all the time and taking images and
observations of the sky to get more data
to help us understand this because we
only have one universe to observe so we
need to be able to collect as much data
as we can on that universe and we need
to be able to extract all the
information we can from our data from
our observations and cosmologists are
increasingly turning to deep learning to
extract meaning from our data and I'm
going to talk about a couple of
different ways that we're doing that but
first of all I want to kind of ground
this in the background of how we
actually do experiments in cosmology
because it's cosmology is not an
experimental science in the way that
many other physical sciences are so it's
not a lot we can do to experiment with
the universe we can't really do much to
change the nature of space-time although
it would be fun if we could but instead
we have to run simulations so we run
simulations in supercomputers of
theoretical universes and the different
physical models and the different
parameters that control those physical
models and that's how we experiment we
run these simulated universes and then
we compare the outputs of these
simulations to our observations of the
real universe around us so when we make
this comparison we're typically using
some statistical measure some kind of
reduced statistic like the power
spectrum which is illustrating this
animation here the power spectrum is a
measure of how matter is distributed
throughout the universe whether it's
kind of distributed fairly evenly
throughout space or whether it's
clustered on small scales and this is
illustrated in this the images on the
top of the slide here which is snapshots
of a simulated universe run in a
supercomputer and you can see that over
time gravity is pulling matter together
and so thats dark matter and regular
matter
he's acting upon that collapsing the
matter into these very typical cluster
and filamentary type structures whereas
dark energy is expanding space itself
expanding the volume of the this a
miniature universe and so by looking at
the distribution of matter and we can
start to learn something about the
nature of the matter itself how gravity
is acting on that and what dark energy
is doing but as you can imagine running
these kinds of simulations is very
computationally expensive even if you're
only simulating a tiny universe it still
requires a tremendous amount of compute
power and we spend billions of computer
hours on supercomputers around the world
on these kinds of simulations including
the supercomputers that I work with and
one of the ways that we're using deep
learning is to reduce the need for such
expensive simulations similar to the
previous speaker was talking about
Vincent's walking bout with robotics
we're exploring using generative
networks to produce in this case this
example two dimensional maps of the
universe so these are two dimensional
maps of the mass concentration of the
universe so you can imagine the
three-dimensional volume collapsed into
a two dimensional projection of the mass
density in the universe as you're
looking out at the sky and we use again
which is based on a fairly standard DC
gaen topology to produce new maps of
these new mass maps based on simulations
so this is an augmentation we're using
this network to augment an existing
simulation to produce new maps and we
see that it's doing a pretty good job so
just by looking by eye at the generated
images they look pretty similar to the
real input images the real simulated
images but as a scientist kind of
squinting at something and saying oh
yeah that looks about right is not good
enough and what I want is to be able to
quantify this to be able to quantify how
our network is working and quantify how
like the real images our generated
images are and this is I think where
scientific data has a real advantage
compared to natural image data because
scientific data usually are very often
has associated statistics with it so
statistics that you can use to evaluate
the success of your model so in this
case we were looking at reduced
statistics that describe the patterns in
the the maps like the power spectra and
other measures of the topology of the
maps and we see that not only do the
maps and look about right but the the
statistics that are contained in those
maps match those from the real
simulations so we can quantify the
accuracy of our network and this is
something that potentially could be
useful for the wider deep learning
community I'm using scientific data that
has these associated statistics could be
of real interest I think to deep
learning practitioners in trying to
quantify how well your networks are
working so I mentioned before that this
is an augmentation again that we've been
working on so far it can produce new
maps based on a physics model that it's
already seen and we're working at
scaling this up and producing physics
models that the network has never seen
before so making this into a true
emulator and this will help reduce the
need for these very computationally
expensive simulations and allow
cosmologists to explore parameter space
a bit more freely and I'd like to
explore a little bit further what this
network is actually learning I saw a
really interesting talk this morning
here and that was touching on this kind
of thing how we can use machine learning
to gain insight into the nature of the
data that we're working with so in their
work that I'm showing here we were
looking at which structures in our mass
maps are contributing to the model and
most strongly contributing to the model
by looking at a quantity called salience
II and so by if you look at the map of
saying it C which is the black and white
image here you can see that the peaks in
the salient C map corresponds to peaks
in the mass map and so these peaks and
amass mady's are concentrations of
matter and these corresponds to galaxy
clusters typically in the real universe
and this isn't news to cosmologists and
we've known for decades that galaxy
clusters are a really good way of
exploring cosmology
but the shapes of the features that this
network have learns are not you know
nice round Gaussian balls they are
irregular and they're showing some
structure and this is something that's
really interesting to me and there's
also indications that some of the
smaller mass concentrations are showing
off as important features in this
network and that's perhaps a little bit
unexpected so by taking this kind of
introspection into the features that our
network is learning we can start to
learn something about the data and get
insight into some of the physical
processes that are going on in our data
and learn what kind of structures
perhaps are most sensitive to the
interplay of gravity and dark energy I
think this is something that's a real a
real strong point of deep learning when
you are allowing the network to learn
features for itself rather than imposing
features doing feature engineering or
telling at any particular statistics you
can allow the the network to tell you
something about your data that might
surprise you so far that was looking at
two dimensional maps but of course the
universe is not a two dimensional space
it's at least four dimensions perhaps
many more dimensions depending on your
favorite model of string theory and what
we've been looking at three dimensions
is scaling this up another another level
and what the reason why three dimensions
are interesting from us from a
computational point of view because in a
three dimensional data volume you're
looking at three dimensional matrices
three dimensional convolutions this is
something that's computationally
expensive and it's something that can
run really well on a supercomputing
architecture so a team at CMU recently
demonstrated for the first time that
deep learning can be used to determine
the physical model of the universe from
three-dimensional simulations or the
full matter distribution so this is the
full three dimensional matter rather
than a two dimensional projection of the
matter density and this work showed that
the network was able to make
significantly better estimates of the
parameters that describe the physics of
the simulated universe compared to
traditional methods and where you might
be looking at one of these statistics
like the power spectrum and so this is a
really nice example of how the network
was able to learn and what structures in
this three-dimensional
massive volume were important rather
than just looking at statistics that we
in advance thought was going to be
useful so we're working on scaling this
up at the moment in collaboration with
nurse UC Berkeley Intel in Cray who are
industry partners at nurse we're using
larger simulation volumes even more data
and we're using tensor flow running on
thousands of CPU notes achieving with
several petabytes petaflop
of performance on Cori which is our
flagship supercomputer but perhaps the
most important part of this is that
we're able to predict more physical
parameters with even greater accuracy by
scaling up the training of this and this
is something that we're really excited
about and I think it's worth talking a
little bit more in technical daeso about
how we achieve this performance how we
are using tensor flow on our
supercomputers to get this kind of
performance and get this kind of insight
into our data and into our science now
supercomputers are fairly specialized we
have specialized hardware to allow the
tens of thousands of compute nodes we
have on these supercomputers to act
together as one compute machine you want
to use this machine as efficiently as
possible to train our network we have a
lot of performance available to us we
want to be able to take advantage of
that when we're running tensorflow so
the approach we take is using a fully
synchronous data parallel approach where
each node is training on a subset of the
data and we started off as many people
do using a G RPC for this where each
compute node is communicating with a
parameter server to send their parameter
updates and have that sent back and
forward but like many other people have
noted this is not a very efficient way
to run at scale we found that if we are
running beyond 100 nodes or so then we
had a real communication bottleneck
between the compute nodes and the
parameter servers so instead we use MPI
which is a message passing interface to
allow our compute nodes to communicate
with each other directly so removing the
need for parameter servers and this is
also has the advantage that can really
take advantage of our high speed
interconnects
the specialized hardware that connects
our compute nodes so we use a for
gradient aggregation for this we use
specialized MPI collective all reduce
which is designed by Cray who are our
partners with our supercomputers and
this MPI all reduce is is is pretty neat
it's able to avoid imbalances in a node
performance the straggler effect that
some of you might run into it's
overlapping communication and compute in
a way that allows very effective scaling
and we've seen that we were able to run
tensor flow on thousands of compute
nodes with very little drop in
efficiency and something that I've been
really excited to see here is a MPI or
reduce is coming soon in tensor flow and
we're excited to see how this is going
to work in the larger community so the
three things I'd like you to take away
from this talk the first is that
cosmology has some really cool science
problems and some really cool deep
learning problems the second is that
scientific data is different from
natural image data and so these one
understood statistics that we often have
associated the scientific data could be
a real use I think in the deep learning
community and the third thing is that
MPI or reduce in our experience is the
optimal strategy for scaling tensor flow
up to multiple nodes and we're looking
forward to seeing how the rest of the
community is gonna work with this so now
in turn things back to Lawrence thank
you
Thank You Debbie
great stuff actually simulating
universes so we're running very short on
time so I just want to share these are
like just three great stories but there
are countless more stories out there
this is a map that I created of people
who starred tensorflow and github and
who shared their location and we have
people from the outback of Australia to
the green fields of Ireland from the
North Arctic Circle in Norway all the
way down to deception island in
Antarctica there are countless stories
being created countless great new things
being done with tensorflow and with
machine learning we think some of those
stories are yours and if they are please
get in touch with us we'd love to hear
them and would love to share them so
with that I just want to say thank you
very much for attending today enjoy
what's left of i/o and have a safe
journey home thank you
[Music]