this week's question is one that I get
asked a lot how do I use tensorflow in
an IDE like pycharm and even if I have
it already installed it just doesn't
seem to get recognized and that's a
great question so let's take a look
here's the IDE PyCharm and it's a
personal favorite of mine if you've used
Android studio it'll look very familiar
here you can see I have a very simple
script written in Python but it's saying
that I don't have a module named
tensorflow
or even a module named numpy but if I go
to a terminal and I type Python and then
import tensorflow as TF and I'll print
the version of tensorflow you'll see
that I have tensorflow 1.6 installed so
what gives pycharm uses a virtual
environment to run tensorflow in and in
this case tensorflow and numpy haven't
been installed to this specific virtual
environment so let's take a look at
installing them now what's nice about
this is that I can try different
versions of the library on different
virtual machines so in this virtual
environment I'll install a later version
of tensorflow
so in my project settings if I go to the
project interpreter take a look at a
list of packages and then click the plus
I'll get a list of packages that I can
install and tensorflow is one of these
what's really neat about this is that I
can then specify the version I want to
install so I can pick for example 1.8
which was the most up-to-date version at
the time of recording this you can see
now that it's installing version 1.8 now
you can see it has successfully
installed and I have 1.8 so I can escape
out of there and go back to the editor
sometimes it takes the editor a few
moments to catch up so the red
underlines are still there but now I can
run my app without an error and in my
console you can see that it's training
and the values are coming out so that's
all it took to get tensorflow working in
pycharm and this leads nicely to the
next video where you can learn all about
using an IDE for step-by-step debugging
so don't forget to hit that subscribe
button
thank you
[Music]