[Music]
[Applause]
hi and welcome to coding tensorflow
a show where we focus on coding machine
learning and AI I'm Laurence Moroney a
developer advocate for tensorflow
and in this episode we're going to look
at using JavaScript for machine learning
in the browser this is achieved using
tensorflow j/s a javascript library for
training and deploying machine learn
models in the browser and on no js'
there's lots of great information about
it on the jsr tensorflow dot org site
including samples API Docs and
frequently asked questions in this first
episode I'll show you how easy it is to
build and train a very simple model that
executes entirely in the browser and in
the next episodes we'll look at setting
up a node environment and running more
complex examples are you ready to go ok
let's do this let's first create the
simplest web page imaginable it's empty
but for 1 div and we'll even leave that
empty too the next thing of course is to
add the tensorflow j/s libraries and
these can be inserted using a script tag
and I do that here always be sure to use
the latest version which you can find at
this URL be sure to put the script
loader in your head tag as shown here
great you now have your page set up for
tensorflow so let's now show a simple
but powerful example of how it can work
the goal of machine learning is to train
a model from input data this model can
be then used to in fare or predict
output data for future input values so
for example take a look at this data now
it's pretty obvious to the human eye
that there's a linear relationship in
this data
these dots can be joined by a straight
line thus even though I don't know what
the Y value is when X is 5 I can infer
that by looking at the line in machine
learning we do this by training a model
on the input data so let's take a look
at the code for this first of all I'm
going to create a new script block and
within that I'll create an asynchronous
function called learn
linear it's asynchronous because the
learning will take some time so it's
good to get into the habit of waiting
for the learning to finished now I'm
going to add a model I'm using a TF dot
sequential where the outputs of one
layer are the inputs to the next it's a
simple stack of layers with no branching
or any kind of skipping I will then add
a dense layer to this and dense means
all of the nodes in each of the layers
are connected to each other in this case
it's a little redundant as I only have
one layer and one node but it's the
easiest way to define a simple neural
network like this now that my model is
defined it's time to compile it to do
this I have to specify some parameters
including the loss function and the
optimizer I'm setting the loss function
to be a mean squared error it's a pretty
standard one particularly for linear
equations and the optimizer is going to
be said to SGD which stands for a
stochastic gradient descent this simply
defines a methodology for the learning
there are a bunch of them supported
including SGD and the popular atom you
can learn more about these in the
training optimizer section of the API
and we'll put a link below for the next
step I'll define my x and y values for
the line remember that graph we showed
earlier let's take a look at the points
on that you can see that I've labeled
them here with their x and y coordinates
from a machine learning perspective we
can consider the X values to be our
inputs and our Y values to be our
desired outputs thus in the future if we
feed in a new x value would get a Y
value back so to train a model to do
this we can create two tensors for the
training values one for the X's and one
for the Y's let's take a look at this in
code I'll create a tensor for the X's by
using TF tensor 2d you'll see that the
first element in this is my array of X
values minus 1 0 1 etc the second
parameter is the shape of this array 6
rows and 1 column I'll then do the same
for my y's giving my Y values and the
same shape six rows on one column
now all I have to do is
Rane my model now this can take some
time for complex models but because this
is really simple it's going to be really
quick either way because it takes an
indeterminate time you will await its
execution which is why you made this
function and a synchronous one to begin
with so let's take a look at the code to
train a model for a fixed number of
iterations known as epochs you call the
fit method here you can see I'm telling
it my input values the X's my output
values the Y's and then asking it to
train for 250 iterations once the model
is trained I can try to do a prediction
from it so if you're good at math you'll
see that the relationship here between x
and y is y equals 2x minus 1 thus the
value for X is 5
well then Y should be 9 you use the
model to predict method to get a
prediction so let's see that in action
I'll refer to the div called output
field that I created earlier and I'll
load the results of the prediction into
its inner text to do this I call model
duck predict and I pass my input tensor
which is a single value in a one by one
array tensorflow will then give me back
the value and you'll see that it
predicted 38.5 which is pretty close to
the correct value of 39 if i refresh the
value changes to 38.3 because I've
retrained the neural network I can
impact the accuracy by training for more
epochs giving the network more time to
error correct so let's make it say 500
epochs and now when i refresh we'll see
my value is 38.9 and another refresh
keeps it there so let's see what it
would predict for x equals 10 it gives
us 18 point 9 7 where of course the
correct value is 19 a refresh and
retrain the network and now I get 18
point 9 8 we're pretty close and that's
it you've just created a neural network
using javascript in the browser and
trained it to predict a linear
relationship this was made possible by
tensorflow Jas in the next episode of
this series you'll learn a little
about data science and this is the
process of preparing data for machine
learning and you'll do it by building a
simple classifier for tensorflow
which runs completely in the browser you
can learn more about tensorflow das on
tensorflow org and don't forget to hit
that subscribe button for more great
videos on this channel thank you
[Music]
[Applause]