hello welcome to this tensorflow session
about rain enforcement learning so this
is you Han I'm Martin and today we would
like to build a neural network with you
do you know about neural networks if I
say a serious question if I say softmax
or cross-entropy raise your hand if you
know what that is
like half the audience okay very quick
primer this is a neural network ok
layers of neurons those neurons they
always do the same thing they do a
weighted sum of all of their inputs and
then you can layer them in layers the
neurons in the first layer they do a
weighted sum of let's say pixels if we
are analyzing images the neurons in the
second layer will be doing weighted sum
sums of outputs from the first layer and
if you are building a classifier let's
say here probably you want to classify
those little square images into
airplanes and known airplanes you will
end up on a last layer which has as many
neurons as you have classes and if those
weights are configured correctly we'll
get to that then one of those neurons
will have a strong output on certain
images and tell you this is an airplane
or the other one we have us will have a
stronger output it will tell you no this
is not an airplane ok there is one more
thing in this there are activation
functions so a little bit more details
about what a neuron does for those who
like it you have the full oops right
here you have the the full transfer
function here so you see it's a weighted
sum plus something called the bias
that's just an additional degree of
freedom and then you feed this through
an activation function and in neural
networks that is always a non-linear
function and to simplify for us here
only to activation for
that counts so for all the intermediate
layers the white layers really that's
the simplest function you can imagine
you have it on the graphic okay
just this it's nonlinear we love it
everyone uses that let's not go any
further on the last layer though if
you're building a classifier typically
what you use is the soft max activation
function and that is an exponential
followed by a normalization so here I
have different classifier that
classifies in ten classes and you'll
have your weighted sums coming out of
your ten final neurons and what you do
in soft max is that you elevate all of
them to the exponential and then you
compute the norm of that vector of ten
elements and you divide everything by
ignore the effect of that since
exponential is it's a very steeply
increasing function is that it will pull
the winner apart I made a little
animation to show you like this this is
after soft max this is before soft max
so yours you see much clearer which of
those neurons is indicating the winning
class okay that's why it's called soft
max it pulls the winner at parts like a
max but it doesn't completely destroy
the rest of the information that's why
it's a soft version of Max okay so just
those two activation functions with that
we can build the stuff we want to build
so now coming out of our neural network
we have our let's say here ten final
neurons producing values which have been
normalized between zero and one we can
say those values or probabilities okay
the probability of this image being in
this class how are we going to determine
the the weights in those weighted sums
initially it's all just you know random
so initially our network doesn't do
anything actually so useful
we do this through supervised learning
so you provided images which you have
labeled beforehand you know what they
are and all those images your network is
going to output this set of
probabilities but you know what the
correct answer is because you are doing
supervised learning so you will include
your correct answer in a format that
looks like what the network is producing
it's the simplest encoding you can think
of it's called one hot encoding and
basically it's a bunch of zeros with
just one one in the middle that's the
index of the class you want so here to
represent 2/6 I have a vector of zeros
with a 1 in the sixth position and now
those vectors look very similar I can
compute the distance between them and
the good of the people who studied this
in a classifier
they tell us don't use any distance use
the cross-entropy distance why I don't
know they are smarter than me I just
follow in the entropy the cross-entropy
distance is computed like this so you
multiply element by element the elements
of the vector the known answer from the
top by the logarithm of the
probabilities you got from your neural
network and you then sum that up across
the vector this is the distance between
what the network has predicted and the
correct answer that's what you want if
you want to train a neural network you
get this it's called an error function
or a loss function from there on tensor
flow can take over and do the training
for you you just need an error function
so in a nutshell those are the
ingredients in our part that I want you
to be aware of
you have neurons you know the way it
sounds you have only two activation
functions that you can use either the
rayleigh activation function on
intermediate layers or if you build a
classifier on the last layer softmax and
the error function that we are going to
use is the cross entropy error function
that I had on the previous slide okay
all good on this bit of code this is how
you would write it in tensor flow so
there is a high level API in tensor flow
layers where you can instantiate an
entire layer at once you see I
instantiate the first layer here has 200
neurons and is activated by the Rayleigh
activation function it's this layer here
and this also instantiates the weights
and biases for this layer in the
background you don't see that it's in
the background I have a second layer
here which is this one is just 20
neurons again radio activation function
and this I need to do do this little
final layer so it's a dense layer again
with two neurons and even if you do
don't see it on the screen it is
activated by softmax but you don't see
it because I use its output in the cross
entropy function which has softmax built
in so it is a soft max layer it's just
that you don't see region soft packs in
the code
finally this here is my error function
which is the distance between the
correct answer here
one hot encoded and the output from my
neural network once I have that I can
give it to tensorflow take an optimizer
ask it to optimize this loss and the
magic will happen so what is this magic
tensorflow will take this error function
differentiate it relatively to all the
weights and all the biases all the
trainable variables in the system and
that gives it something that is
mathematically called a gradient and by
following this gradient it can figure
out how to adjust the weights and biases
in the neural network in a way that
makes this error smaller that makes the
difference between what the network
products and what we know to be true
smaller that's supervised learning so
that was the primary now why what do we
want to build today we would like with
you to build a neural network that plays
the
of pong but just from the pixels of the
game it's notoriously difficult to
explain to a computer and the rules of
the game and the strategies and all that
so you want to do way of all that and
just give it the pixels and find some
learning algorithm that will where it
will learn to play this game and of
course that is not the goal in itself
because figuring out how to program a
paddle to win Punk is it's super easy
you just always stay in front of the
ball you know and and you win all the
time
and actually we will train again such a
computer-controlled agent the goal here
is to explore learning algorithms
because this has applications hopefully
way beyond Punk so this looks like a
classifier we just learned how to build
a classifier you know we have the pixels
we will build on your own network and it
has three possible outcomes this is a
position in which you want to go up stay
still or you want to go down okay let's
try to do this by the book in a
classifier so we have a single
intermediate layer of neurons activated
with already of course and then a last
layer where there's three neurons
activated by softmax
we use the cross entropy loss so you
have the function here it's the distance
between the probabilities that this
policy network it's called the policy
Network predicts probability of going up
still or going down in the correct move
but what is the correct move I don't
know do you know you have no Martin
you're exactly right here unlike in the
supervised learning problem we actually
don't know what's correct move to play
here
however the environment requires that we
keep making moves of going up or staying
still or moving down to the progress
together so what we're gonna do is we're
gonna same for the move
which means picking one of the three
possible moves of moving the pedal up
Staines - you're going down randomly but
not completely randomly though we're
going to pick the move based on the
output of the network so for example if
the network stays the output probability
of going up is 0.8 then we should make
it so that there's 80% of chance which
choose to move up as our next vote
all right so now we know how to play the
game the policy network gives us
probabilities we are all alone a loaded
dice and pick from that and we know what
next moves to play but initially this
network is initialized with a random
weights so it will be playing random
moves how is that how does that inform
us about the correct move to play I need
to put the correct move in my formula
that's right so in this case we really
want the correct both to mean moves that
will lead to winning yeah we don't know
that until someone has score a point and
so that's what we're gonna do
only when someone either our pet or the
opponent hello has scored the point do
we know we have played well or not so
whenever somebody stores who are gonna
give ourself a reward if our pedo scores
the point
we'll give ourselves the positive one
reward point and if the opponent cattle
scores don't give ourself a negative one
reward point and then we're going to
structure our loss function slightly
differently than before over here once
again over here you see some a loss
function very much like the process
should be function we saw before now in
the middle here is the main difference
where instead of the correct label in
supervised learning problem we're just
going to put the same whole move in
there the move we played the move that
we happen to play and well some of the
moves may not be really moves our
helpers and so that's why every loss
function lost value is multiplied by the
reward out front this way boosts that
eventually lead to a winning point will
get encouraged and moves that lead to a
losing point will be discouraged over
time okay so you do this for every move
I can see how with this little
modification it could
to some learning but putting back my
mathematicians hat on I see a big
problem here you have this sample move
that is a picking operation a sampling
operation you pick one out of three that
is not differentiable and to apply you
know the minimization and a gradient
descent and all that the last function
must be differentiable you're right
Marty I see the hard question here the
simple move here it actually does depend
down the modest ways and biases but the
sampling operation is not differentiable
and so we're not going to differentiate
that instead we're going to look at the
sample moves as if they're constants and
then we play many games across many many
moves to get a lot of data treating all
of these sample moves as if they're
constant cancer labels and only
differentiating the probabilities that
our output by the model in blue here on
the screen and those probabilities
directly depend on the models ways and
biases and we can differentiate those
with respect with the ways and biases
this way we still get a valid gradient
and we can apply gradient descent
techniques oh okay so you kind of
cheated the part that is problematic
just regarded as constant you're going
to play many games with the same neural
network accumulate those plate moves
accumulate those rewards whenever you
know that you scored a point you
accumulate those rewards and and then
you plug that in and you only
differentiate relatively to the
predicted probabilities and yes you're
right that still gives you a gradient
that depends on weights and biases so we
should be able to do that ok I get it
this is clever so this will actually
strain probably very slowly here we want
to show you the minimum amount of stuff
you need to do to get it to Train but in
the minimal amount there are still two
little improvements that you always want
to do the first one is to discount the
rewards so probably if you lost the
point you did something wrong in the
three five seven
moves right before you lost that point
and probably before that you bounced the
ball correctly a couple of times and
that is that was correct you don't want
to discourage that
so it's customary to discount the
rewards through time backwards through
time with some exponential discount
factor so that the moves you played
closest the scoring point are the ones
that count the most so you see the here
we discounted them with a factor of 1/2
for instance and and then there is this
normalization step so what is that yeah
that's very interesting
so in experiments that we notice putting
in the normalizations that really help
training to make learning faster
therefore multiple ways to think about
this the way I like to think about this
is in the context of playing again you
see at the beginning of the time the
model only has randomized weights and
biases so it's gonna make a random moves
so most of time is not going to make the
right boat only once and wire is gonna
score a point but that's really by
chance by accident and most of time is
gonna lose points and we didn't want to
find a way to necessarily put more ways
to the very rare winning moves there so
they can learn what are the corrective
moves and performing is normalizing and
we were stabbed here naturally gives a
very nice boost to the rare when they
move so it does not get lost in you know
a ton of losing moves okay so let's go
let's train this but we need to play the
game and accumulate enough data to
compute this everything that we need for
this function here okay so those are the
sample moves we need the rewards and we
also need those probabilities which the
network can compute from us from the
pixels so we are going to collect the
pixels during gameplay that's how our
data set collected data set looks like
okay you have one column with the move
you actually played one column where you
would like to see the probabilities
predicted at that point but you were
actually going to store just the game
board and run the network to get the
probabilities in the last column with
the rewards you see there is a plus one
or minus one reward on
removed and scored a point and on all
the other moves you discount that reward
backwards in time with some exponential
discount so that's what we want to chew
and once you have this maybe you notice
in the formula you just multiply those
three columns together and sum all of
that that's power loss that's how the
loss is computed let's build it you
implemented this this this this demo so
can you walk us through the code let's
do that so up here you see a few
tensorflow
placeholders you should really think of
them as function arguments that are
required to compute alpha values for
models and so with three placeholders
for the input one for the observation
remember this really means the
difference between two consecutive
frames unit game play actually yes
because we didn't say that actually just
in the game of pong you don't really
train from the pixels because you don't
see the direction of the ball with from
just the picture but you train from the
Delta between two frames because there
you see the direction of the ball that's
the only wrinkle we are doing here which
is specific to pong all the rest is
reinforcement learning vanilla
reinforcement learning that applies to
many other problems that's right yeah
and for the actions placeholder is just
going to hold all the simple to move the
moves that the model happen to decide to
play and the rewards placeholder work
collect all the discounted rewards now
with those as impose we're ready to
build a model the networks really simple
is like the one marketing show before it
has a single dense layer a single ten
hidden layer with activation of the
riilu function 200 neurons
followed by a soft max layer you don't
receive calling us off the max function
here and that's really because the next
step the sampling operation already
takes in Logies which is the lab values
you get before you cross off max
function and it came to perform
multinomial sampling which just means
you output a random number of zero one
or two for the three classes that we
need output based on the probability you
specify the lot by the long
and this one has the softbox built-in so
already building this is a soft wax
layer okay we don't see it on the cover
but it is okay and just the parentheses
for those not familiar with a tensor
flow tensor flow builds and note a graph
of operations in memory so that's why
out of multi monomial we get an
operation and then we will have an
additional step to run it and actually
get those predictions out and
placeholders or the data you need to put
in when you actually run a node to be
able to get a numerical result out okay
so we have everything we need to play
the game still nothing to Train so let's
do the training part for training we
need a loss function so our beloved
cross my cross entropy loss function
computing the distance between our
actions so the moves we actually played
and logits which are from the previous
screen that's what the network predicts
from the pixels and then we modify it to
you to use using the reinforcement
learning paradigm we modified by
multiplying this per move loss by the
rewards by the per move rewards and now
with the with those rewards moves
leading to a scoring point will be
encouraged moves leading to a losing
point will be discouraged so now we have
our error function tensorflow can take
over we pick one of the optimizers in
the library and simply ask this
optimizer to minimize our loss function
which gives us a training operation and
we will when we will on the next slide
run this training operation feeding in
all the data we collected during
gameplay that is where the the gradient
will be computed and that's the
operation when run that will modify the
weights and biases in our policy network
so let's play this game this is what you
need to do to play one game in 21 points
so the technical wrinkle is that
intensive
if you want to actually execute one of
those operations you need a session so
we define a session and then in a loop
we play a game so first we get the
pixels from the game stage compute the
Delta between two frames
okay that's technical and then we run
session not run this sample operation
remember sample operation is what we got
from our picking multinomial function so
that's what decides the next move to
play then we use a punk simulator here
from open AI gem we can give it this
move to play and it will play the move
and give us a new game state give us a
reward if we score the point and give us
information on whether this game in 21
points is finished ok that's what we
need now we simply log all that stuff we
log the pixels we log the move we played
we lock the reward if we got one so we
know how to play one game and we will
come and play many of those games to
collect a large backlog of moves right
that's right playing games in
reinforcement learning or in our
experiment really is a way of collecting
data now that we have collected love
data playing one game only ten games why
not we can start processing rewards as
we plan to will discount the rewards so
that the moves that did not get any
reward during gameplay now case a
discounted reward based on whether or
not they eventually led to winning or
losing points and how far they are from
the moves that actually won or lost a
point and then we normalize those
rewards as we explained before now
already we have all the data in place we
have observations
that's the differences between game
frames the action stuff happens to plate
and the rewards so that we know if those
actions were good or bad and then we're
ready to call the training up and
training out is what we saw a couple
slides before where we had optimized
already initialized and this is going to
do the heavy lifting and compute the
gradients for us and modify the weights
just slightly suppose we played 10 games
we modify the way slightly and then
we'll go back and play more games to get
even more data and repeat the process
and expectation or the hope is that
the model will let you play a little
better every time I'm a bit skeptical do
you really think this is going to work
well sometimes we see the model I should
forget to play a little bit worse
so we'll see okay live demo like that
all let's go let's run this game so this
is a live demo I'm not completely sure
that we are going to win but we shall
see so Brown on this side is the
computer-controlled paddle very simple
algorithm is just stays in front of the
ball at all times so there is only one
way to win to win it's vertical velocity
is limited so you have to hit the ball
on the very side of the paddle to say is
to send to send it at a very steep angle
and then you can overcome the vertical
velocity of the opponent that's the only
way to score on the right in green we
have our neural network controlled agent
in its slightly behind them so we'll see
if it wins and if you want I want this
side of the room to cheer for ground and
this side of the room to cheer for AI
okay it's very even right now one thing
yeah go go go
ai is willing hey I is winning I'm happy
because this is a live demo there is no
guarantee that a I will win actually win
one thing that is interesting here
actually is that this is learning from
just the pixels so initially the AI had
no idea of even which what game it was
playing what the rules were
it had even no idea which paddle it was
playing okay and we didn't have to
explain that we just give the pixels and
on scoring points we get a public if we
give a positive or a negative reward and
that's it from that it learns and you
see you see those emerging strategies
like what I said hitting the ball on the
side and sending again at a very steep
angle is the only way of winning and it
picked that up
we never explain it it's just an
emerging strategy this is looking good
pretty close yeah it's looking good it's
it's a bit close but it's looking good
you think well when okay next point I
want a loud cheer what AI wins because I
hope this is going to work
hey 20 okay one more one more
yeah good job your hand this is
fantastic
all right so what was going on during
gameplay actually remember how this
network was built right here so neurons
in this very first layer they have a
connection to every pixel of the board
did you weighted sum of all the pixels
in the board alright so they have a
weight for every pixel and it's fairly
easy to represent those weights on the
board and see what those neurons are
seeing on the board so let's try to do
that right here oops we pick H of those
200 neurons and here we visualize
superimposed on the board the weights
that have been trained and to the
untrained eye doesn't see much
here's maybe you can enlighten us a
marketing we're looking at what the
model sees so rather what the model
cares about when you sees the game
pixels that we gave it you see that one
of neurons apparently Hedren pretty much
nothing it's still looking like the
white noise at the beginning of
initialization that contribute much to
the gameplay but for the only other
neurons you see some interesting
patterns there we see a few things that
the model seems to put a lot of weights
on it cares a lot about where the
opponent paddle is and where is the
moving it not cares about the balls
trajectory across the game board and
quaint Rossini also cares a whole lot
about where its own paddle is on the
right because like Martin pointed out
before
at the beginning of learning the model
could even know which pedo is playing
and so he has to learn to remember
that's important piece of information to
be able to play game well and when you
think about this this is really
consistent with how we human beings will
believe consists of importing
informations to be able to play the game
well so we wanted to show this to you
not to show our prowess at pong
although it worked but mostly to explore
training algorithms and you see mostly
in your networks you do supervised
training and in nature well sometimes
when we teach people it looks like
supervised training probably in class
the teacher says this is you know the
Eiffel Tower and the people say ok
that's the Eiffel Tower and so on but if
you think about a kitten jumping on a
furball and missing it and jumping again
until it catches it and there is no
teacher there it has to figure out a
sequence of moves and it gets a reward
from catching the ball or not catching
it so it looks like in nature there are
multiple ways of training our own neural
networks and one of them is probably
quite close to this reinforcement
learning way of kitchen you have you you
build this model is there some other
thoughts it inspired you yeah
I have a technical insights maybe for
you as a takeaway message in run
experiments we see that there are some
steps which are not differentiable
particularly in this case sampling a
move are the probability output from a
network and playing a game I get a
reward back yes those factors really do
depend on the model itself but in a now
differentiable way
and so even with the powerful tools like
tensor flow you wouldn't be able to very
naively view the lost function and run
gradient descent training but there are
ways to get around it and that's exactly
the techniques were showing today so
what you're saying is that the
reinforcement learning can solve many
more problems that just Punk and it's a
way of getting around some non
differential step that you find in your
problem great that's great so what is
this going we want to show you a couple
of things from the lab because this has
had mostly lab applications and then one
last thing what is this this is very
interesting everyone what we're
witnessing here is a human expert of
pancake flipping trying to teach a
robotic arm doing the same thing and
there's a model in the back supporting
the robotic arm whose output controls
the joints movement or the motors in it
what angle was speed to move toward and
the goal of this is to flip the pancake
in the pink it's not just any regular
pin cable rather is instrumented with
sensors so that it knows even be flipped
if you land it on the floor or on the
table or Bank in the frame head doesn't
seem to be working is trying is trying
in another experiment and so what is the
reward here the reward probably is that
if you flip the pancake correctly then
you get the positive reward and
otherwise negative reward
okay and speaking of reward function in
another experiment I was gonna say the
experimenters say the reward to be a
small amount of positive rewards for any
moments the pancakes on the floor and
that machine learned but why learned was
to free the pancake as high as possible
to maximize pancake airborne high
never thought I would say something like
that that way you can maximize the
reward just because you take a long time
for YouTube laying on the floor that's
kind of funny but actually it's it's
it's it's a nice illustration of the
fact that you can change the learn
behavior by changing your lost function
exactly you have learned oh thanks yeah
cool we know how to play pong and flip
pancakes
that's significant progress deepmind
also published this video so they use
reinforcement learning and they built
those skeletal models here the neural
network is predicting the power to send
to the simulated muscles and joints of
these models and the reward is basically
a positive reward whenever you manage to
move forward in a negative reward when
you either move backward or when you
fall through a hole or when you just
crumpled to the ground the rest is just
reinforcement learning as we have shown
you today so all of these behaviors are
emerging behaviors nobody taught those
models and look you have some wonderful
emerging behaviors it's coming in a
couple of seconds look at this jump
after this those are nice jumps but
there is a much nicer one in a second
you will see a jump or the athletic jump
with the model swinging arms to get
momentum then lifting one leg cushioning
right here look at this this is a
fantastic athletic jump it looks like
from the from the Olympics and it's a
completely emerging behavior optimized
way of walking around in why do I not
see people doing this I mean I could but
well you know there are multiple ways of
running probably the the last function
didn't have any factor discouraging you
know useless movements so again by
modifying the last function you get
different behaviors and actually one
last one not this one this one is kind
of funny yes still playing around but I
la I like the look here it figured out
how to run sideways this
fantastic yes there are two ways of
running and it did figure out how to
move sideways this one you probably seen
this is move 74 in Game four of alphago
versus Lise at all and that's the one
move that Lisa told late
that was called the God move and he's a
world famous for just that he played one
correct move and managed to gain to win
one game against alphago he lost four to
one which is fantastic and alphago also
uses reinforcement learning not exactly
the same way here it was an entirely
built out of reinforcement learning okay
because for turn-based games the
algorithm for winning is actually quite
easy you just play all the moves to the
end and then pick the ones that leads to
positive outcomes the only problem is
that you can't compute that there are
too many of them so you use what is
called a value function you unroll on
your couple of moves and then you use
something that looks at the board and
tells you this is good for white and
good for black or good for black and
that's what they built using
reinforcement learning and I find it
interesting because it kind of emulates
the way we humans solve this problem
this is a very visual game we have a
very powerful visual cortex when we look
at the board
go is a game of influence and we see
that in this region black has a strong
influence in this region wide has a
strong presence so we can kind of
process that and what they built is a
value function that does kind of the
same thing and allows them to unroll the
move to a much shallower depth because
after just a couple of moves their value
function built using a reinforcement
learning tells them this is great for
white or good for black so these are
results from the lab
let's try to do something reals so some
application what if we build a neural
network it's a recurrent neural network
okay that's a different architecture of
neural network but for what you have to
know it still has weights and biases in
the middle okay and this neural network
of recurrent neural networks are good
for producing sequences so let's say we
build one that produces sequences of
characters int we structure it so that
those characters actually represent a
neural network yeah when you don't let
work is a sequence of layers so you can
figure out a syntax for saying this is
my first layer this is how big it is and
blah blah blah so why not produce a
sequence of characters that represents a
neural network what if then we train
this neural network on some problem we
care about let's say scoring airplanes
in pictures so this will train to a
given accuracy what if now we take this
accuracy and make it a reward in a
reinforcement learning algorithm so this
accuracy becomes the reward and we apply
reinforcement learning which allows us
to modify the weights and biases in our
original neural network to produce a
better neural network architecture it's
not just tuning the parameters we are
changing the shape of the network that
works better for our problem the problem
we hear about we get a neural network
that is generating a neural network for
our specific problem it's called new
neural architecture search and we
actually published the paper on this and
I find this a very nice application of a
technology designed initially to beat
Punk so Martin you're saying we have
neural networks now learn to build other
neural networks yes Steve man yep so you
you had to finish you build this demo so
can you tell us a word about the tools
that you used yeah definitely so we used
on tensorflow
for for the model itself and his support
for
tracking the metrics of during the
process training I really don't want to
run the training on my laptop but I
probably could so I used a cloud which
is running energy for the training the
model that was playing the game that we
saw before I like them all took maybe
about one day of training to accomplish
that and so with ml engine you have this
job based view and you can launch 20
jobs with different parameters like this
and just let them run and it's just
practicality right it will tear down the
whole cluster when there when when every
job is done and so on that's right
yeah I used a managing a lot of as well
for that there are many other tools in
cloud for doing machine learning but one
we just launched is Auto ml vision
that's one when you do not program
you're just put in your labeled data and
it figures out the model for you and now
you know how it works and also this uses
lots of CPU GPU cycles so cloud GPUs are
useful when you're doing neural
architecture search and they are
available to you as well them so thank
you that's all we wanted to show you
today please give us feedback we just
released this code to github so you have
the github URL if you want to train a
punk agent yourself go into it you can
take a picture there and if you want you
the URL is still on the screen if you
want to learn machine learning I'm not
going to say it's easy but I'm not going
to say it's impossible either we have
this series a relatively short series of
videos and code samples and code labs
called tensorflow without a PhD that is
designed to give you the keys to the
machine learning kingdom so you go
through those videos this talk is one of
them
and it gives you all the vocabulary and
all the concepts and we are trying to
explain the concepts in a language that
developers understand because we are
developers thank you very much
[Music]