[Applause]
hi and welcome to coding tensorflow
where you will learn all about coding
machine learning and AI with tensorflow
I'm Laurence Moroney a developer
advocate for tensorflow and I'll be your
guide to tensorflow light today
tensorflow light is tensor flows
lightweight solution for mobile and
embedded devices it lets you run machine
learn models on mobile devices with low
latency quickly so you can take
advantage of them to do classification
regression or anything else that you
might want without necessarily incurring
a round trip to the server it's
presently supported on Android and iOS
via a C++ API as well as a Java wrapper
for Android developers on Android
devices that support it the interpreter
will also use Android neural networks
API for hardware acceleration otherwise
it can just default to the CPU for
execution before you start with
tensorflow light you will need a trained
model you'll train it from a set of data
using a high powered machine and when
you're done you'll have a model file and
a set of associated check points this
model can then be exported to be used on
a mobile device but before we do that
let's take a look at the model itself
there are a number of formats that it
could be in all of these formats are
based on the concept of protocol buffers
and they define data structures with a
protocol buffer or protobuf for short
you can use tools to generate code in C
Python and other languages that can then
be used to load save and access the data
in a simple way you can learn more about
protocol buffers at this link the first
of these is a graph def file which will
have the dot PB extension if it's binary
or dot PB txt if it's in text format
while the text former as you can see on
this slide is designed to be human
readable it's also very verbose and it's
not a size or memory efficient as its
binary counterpart either way it's the
heart of your model data it contains a
description of your graph in a way that
can be read by another process for
example this model defines the
operations of multiplying matrices a and
B together to get see you
may also encounter a checkpoint file and
this contains serialized variables from
a tensor flow graph it doesn't contain
the graph structure just the state of
the variables at a particular iteration
of the learning it's useful to tell you
variable values at different points in
the learning process there's also a
frozen graphed F where the variables
from the latest checkpoint file are
combined with the graphed and turned
into constants this is important in the
process of using tensor flow light
you'll see in a moment how you can
combine a graph def in a checkpoint to
make one of these the process is called
freezing because every variable is
converted into a constant with a value
from the constant read from a particular
checkpoint finally there's the tensor
flow light model Li te which is built
from the frozen graph using the tensor
flow optimising converter tool or toko
for short the previous section is great
if you've done a lot of work to train
models and you either don't want to
rerun the code and retrain them or maybe
you don't have access to the original
code and data but if you do have access
to the code you can also go straight to
the tensor flow light creation process
in your code as part of the training
let's have a look what that looks like
here's a sample piece of code that
converts to tensor containing an image
from the sessions graph death into a TF
light object as you can see it's pretty
straightforward it's a single line
though I'll give one small word of
warning because tensorflow light is
presently in Developer Preview there are
quite a few operations intensive flow
that are not yet handled by tensor flow
light so it may not be quite ready for
your custom models but we're working on
it all the time so for the rest of this
video I'm going to talk about some of
the more popular public models for
common scenarios that are fully
compatible with tensor flow light to get
a compatibility guide check out this
link two of the more popular models that
we've tested with tensor flow light and
you can use with the preview are the
first is Inception v3 this was built to
validate the popular image net dataset
and this is used in universities as a
benchmark for image for
datian so for example using inception
this image receive these classifications
showing an 88% chance that this image is
a panda bear
interestingly enough the number two
results is for something called an in
dress which looks like this
and you can see the confusion because
it's also a cute black-and-white little
critter in addition to Inception
tensorflow lights also supports the
mobile nets set of models these have
been designed to be mobile first so they
have lower power requirements but
they're not quite as accurate as
something like Inception let's take a
look at an example of a mobile net
module running on Android this app takes
a look at the camera feed and uses a
trained mobile net to classify the
dominant images in the picture here for
example you can see I was holding up a
water bottle to the camera and it got it
right you can download the code and the
mobile net models for this as part of
the tensor flow for poets code labs at
these links in part 1 you'll learn all
about mobile net image classification
and in part 2 you'll see how to deploy
that to a mobile device using tensor
flow lights I'll also be making some
more videos going into the details of
how you can build an app just like this
one providing image classification on
both Android and iOS so make sure you
subscribe to this channel right now and
if you have any questions please leave
them in the comments below thank you
very much and it's time to start coding
tensorflow don't forget to click the
subscribe button for more great videos
like these ones