[Music]
[Applause]
what's up everybody
my name is Magnus are you interested in
getting started with machine learning
intensive flow well in that case you've
come to the right place because in this
screencast that's exactly what we're
going to do first of all let's get to
the most important stuff locating the
code we're going to use and to find it
simply follow the instructions below in
the description of this video I'll give
you a couple of seconds to do that great
let's now look it's what's gonna happen
in this screencast we're going to create
a deep neural network models to classify
images of clothing and to do this we're
going to use a data set called fashion m
mist look in the description below to
find out where this data set comes from
fashion amnesty contains 28 by 28 pixel
images of different clothing for example
t-shirt and tops and sandals and ankle
boots yay so you can say it's a really
fashionable data set that's so corny
alright here's the deal as I said we're
going to train a deep neural network to
classify these images and this is what
the network will look like so we're
taking 28 by 28 pixels as input which
will be an array of 784 input values if
we flatten it then we have our first
hidden layer with a hundred and
twenty-eight neurons so all the input
pixel values will be sent to each of
these neurons and finally we have the
output layer which gives us ten values
specifying the probability that the
image is of a certain class for example
if it's a t-shirt top a sandal or an
ankle boot and since we're doing
classification here these output values
will be probabilities so if you sum all
of these values up to ten values the
result will be one this is because our
neural network will always be a hundred
percent certain that the image is one of
these classes I mean that's the task
we'll train the model to perform in the
first place that's brilliant
alright but that's enough of my face for
now let's
use the screen space for more important
stuff that's right let's look at the
code okay so by clicking on this button
here I can actually execute the code
directly from the browser through collab
collab is a super cool product that
gives you a virtual execution
environment running in Google Cloud the
only thing you need to be sure of is
that you are logged in with your Google
account
next let's expand the licenses so this
code is licensed under Apache and MIT
now will actually start executing some
code so the first step here is to import
our libraries observe your output may
show a different tensile version and
that's totally okay
alright so let's now load the fashion
and this dataset we do this by calling
this convenience function in Kara's and
this will give us two lists one that has
the images of labels we will use to
train the model as you can see here the
other list we will use to test how
accurate our final model is so remember
that fashion amnesty has ten classes
here you can see all their numbers and
their mapping to the class
remember the favorite I previously
mentioned the t-shirt on top sandal and
the ankle boot here we create a list of
these so given the numbers we can find a
textual description of the class all
right
so let's explore our data set a bit more
here you can see the shape of our
training data set it has 60,000 images
each which is 28 by 28 pixels you can
also see that we have the same number of
labels and that each label is a number
between 0 and 9 and similarly for our
test data set that contains 10,000
images let's take a look at one of these
images so here we're plotting the first
image and look it's an ankle boot you
can also see that each pixel has a
grayscale value between 0 and 255 let's
normalize these values so instead of
having an integer value between 0 and
255 we will have a float value between 0
and 1 now let's print the first 25
images and also print the corresponding
names for each ah
that's all looking great so many
nice-looking images of fashion items and
finally let's do some machine learning
stuff first let's define the neural
network which is going to be a
sequential model this means that the
layers will be processed in the order
declared here as you can see we declare
our first layer to be flat and type
followed by two dense layers going back
to our picture you can see how these
statements match the different layers
first we have a flattened 28 by 28 pixel
image to an array having 784 values then
we send each pixel value to all neurons
in our first layer that's what a dense
layer does we also applied a nonlinear
function reel to the results and finally
we calculate our 10 output classes using
softmax to create the probability
distribution that sums to 1 the only
thing remaining is to specify the
optimizer
loss function and that we'd like to see
the accuracy metrics during evaluation
and that's it now we're ready to train
the model and as you can see provide the
training images and label as well as to
use 5 epochs 1 epoch is a full iteration
of the training data set so since we
have 60,000 examples a total of 300
thousand images will be used to train
our model and that's it for training
let's evaluate our model and see what
the accuracy is on the test data set and
as you can see we're actually doing
pretty pretty good for a simple model
like this now we can use our model to do
predictions and here you can see the
prediction for the first images is a
probability distribution that indicates
it's for class number 9 in other words
the ankle boot when we also print the
correct label for the first image you
can see that our model made the correct
prediction let's do some more
predictions where we print both the
predicted value as well as the correct
tables
with the images and as you can see our
model is doing really really well
finally let's grab the first image from
the test data set as you can see it has
resolution 28 by 28 then we add an
initial dimension because the predict
call requires a list of images to be
passed to it we do the predict call and
as you can see our model predicts its
class line an ankle boot and finally we
pick this highest index from our
probability distribution list index
number 9 and that's it I really hope you
enjoyed this screencast be sure to
subscribe to the tensorflow channel to
follow the amazing world of machine
learning and tensorflow but now it's
your turn so go out there and create
some great models and don't forget to
tell us all about it
[Music]
[Applause]
you