hi everybody and welcome to this episode
of tensorflow meets on this episode it's
my privilege to have Chris Scott breath
from Nvidia and XQ from right here in
Google to talk about tensor RT now
tensor RT Chris tell us all about it
tensor T is our programmable inference
accelerator it's basically software that
we created to allow people who are
creating neural networks and artificial
intelligence to run those networks in
production or in devices with the full
performance that GPUs can offer a lot of
the software that's developed for
artificial intelligence is designed for
training and there's optimization so we
can apply for inference that can get
even more performance that aren't
appropriate for for training again we
created a tensor R T to accomplish this
sort of goal of performance because
that's what GPU you you come to GPUs for
and because we're going to be using it
in inference we also wanted to focus on
robustness so we created as a shared
library it's a very compact modular eyes
thing that you can build on top of it
kind of what we've done with the
tensorflow integration but can also be
used in things like cars and other other
sort of devices so it's not just good
for like tensor RT and NVIDIA right it's
also been great for a tensor flow for us
to be able to work with you could you
tell us all about it excuse T so flow is
a machine learning system as we are
improving our inference time
performances and we really want to give
our users the best experience where's
Tessa Artie and so we really want the
user to within the error without
stepping outside the tester flow within
their inner development cycles be able
to enjoy the benefit of the tensor RT
and just have automatically have the
performance benefit without much trouble
it's easy for them to try and it see
them to finding their models for better
performance so we come to this design
that basically give the best of the both
world to the developers so they can
enjoy the full diversity and the
flexibility of tensor flow while still
enjoy the performance benefit of tester
Artie so
come with the design and the start up on
the discussing the cassava cooperation
with a media it's a it's actually a
really cool that you the that idea
because the original sort of thought
that we had for for ten sortie was to
think of as a post processing step and I
think it's a cool idea to really bring
it into the development environment then
as we've talked to some of the early
folks who are who are looking at this
they really liked that that change it's
a very positive change for users on so
how did this all get started well I mean
users have been coming to us who are
starting with tensorflow you know really
from from the very beginning with with
ten sororities so we knew that there was
important community to engage with and
NVIDIA and Google had been working
together for a long time for GPU
optimization on intensify so there was
already an existing working relationship
and I think you actually you just you
suggested early on with an architecture
quick little white paper hey it wouldn't
be cool if and and we noodle on it and
we thought actually sounded like a
really good idea and got engaged do you
still have that white paper have you
framed it some of its on disk somewhere
it's in Google Drive I think actually ok
so it kept securely exactly so I'm a
developer and I want to start using this
I want to take advantage of this what do
i do how do I get started so well you
start in intensive flow itself so you
you've created a graph in tensor flow
and then with the capabilities that have
been added through this integration I
think you start with tips or flow of 1.7
yes and you'll have your graph you'll
you'll be tuning it as as xq said you'll
get to the point real okay now now
what's my performance like on a V 100 so
you'll you'll you'll go on a machine
that has a V 100 and you'll save the
graph which I think means freezing
that's the freezing is what we
tensorflow
ATM for for saving it so you're still in
tends to flow but now you have the the
graph set up to do inference then
there's a command that was added that
will allow you to do a graph transform
okay and the graph transform will take
the take the network and is ex Cuse said
it'll find the places the subgraph of
the whole graph
that tensor arty can handle and it'll
actually convert that into I think a
single kind of tensor arty op so you can
still look at it with with tensor board
or something like that and you'll just
see that you know the data input it'll
go into the tensor RT op and then you'll
get whatever post-processing you you
might do and the cool thing is that's a
graph right so you're still in tensor
flow and all the things you can normally
do with graphs you can do in
particularly you can you can run in
prints on it right there okay where you
can save it and then run it you know in
cancer flow surveying or something like
that later on cool
I'm we're only really getting started
right yes so this is a nice approach
about this this is the first step toward
the grand vision and the design that we
have in mind right in the current form
it is very interesting that you can
steal the user
everything happens with integer flow and
the users can use a full flexibility and
the generality of the ops that offered
by tensor flow in whatever week they
want the contributed the graph to the
hearts and ten and still for the sub
graph that the tensor RT can support
they will give them the performance
benefit they would you so how do they
then do basically that the in the
current form you still need to do a
graph transformation and in the next
view in the future well our teams who
kind of work very close together so you
don't even have to create a new graph it
just good crea graph and the mention
that I want to enable this RT now and
which is magically get a performance
improvement from the front that SRT
still enjoy the natural development
experience way is tensor flow and that
was one of the things actually isn't it
an Nvidia your processors you've run on
multiple environments right there's auto
mode Evan that's embedded in this cloud
and and they just work across all of
them yeah yeah and it's also supplies
the yes it does
and it streamlines the the data flow so
one of the things that previous to this
work we had customers and we would work
and help them through through this
challenges that it is taking the the
data they could export the the tensor
flow graph in a tense RT but in
intensive flow they were probably doing
some pre-processing and probably you say
who's doing some post-processing using
the tools that a tensor flow environment
brings to them they would have to kind
of replace that with with
see code and and if they can you know if
they can take advantage of the
integration then they can just use the
existing code they've already written in
history whoa so reducing a lot of
friction but yeah I'm able to access all
and then being able to yeah again again
to apply the graph or the artificial
intelligence your Mottola they've
created they can put it in a drone or
they can put it in a in a car or in the
cloud cool cool
so again as a developer there's a
there's a site on NVIDIA right for
developers yeah we'll have the URL is
HTTP slash but surely yeah so yeah it's
basically our developer site has a tense
arty page okay cool so we'll put the
link in the description below so if
you're a developer you go visit that
link and you can learn about all about
tense Rorty and work through some
scenarios you'll be able to add but you
can you can get information there and
it's also just available in tensorflow I
mean so yeah so when you get ten zero
one point seven yeah be there okay I'm
on that site every couple of weeks
downloading my q2 drivers anyway so I'll
check it out thank you so much Chris and
thank you so much XQ and thanks
everybody for watching this episode of
tensor flow mates if you've got any
questions for me or any questions for my
guests just please leave them in the
comments below and we hope to see you in
a future episode thank you
you