hi everybody and welcome to the
tensorflow cafe at the tensorflow
developer summit alex pathos who was
here from the eager team and he was at
the summit talking about eager so alex
welcome
wow thank you yeah how would you talk I
think eager execution is super
interesting like this new way you're
using pencil flow that's a lot more
intuitive pythonic and object-oriented
and I think friendly and I don't know
people seemed excited to hear about it a
lot of developers that I've chatted with
like did getting to understand the
graph-based mode was a little bit of a
bump for them to get over so then having
eager and they're like you say more
pythonic way of doing it certainly makes
it easier for them yeah it's a it's a
hard mental model it can be I mean it
doesn't have to be but it can be a
little hard of a mental model to write
code that builds a graph that then runs
just short cutting this to just write
code that runs it's a lot a much
friendlier experience and once your code
is working he usually just builds a
graph automatically like you once your
code is working a bigger execution you
can flip a switch and it will build a
graph without errors so it's a it's a
much like move or way to approach the
whole process does it does it make like
the concept of like prototyping testing
prototyping testing does it make that a
little bit easier do you think yeah
definitely because you can you also it's
not as if it has to be a prototype if
you're using eager execution you can't
get really good performance like one of
my slides talked about how in ResNet
models and like l SCM models with the
right kernels you have this good
performance as you have with graph
execution so it's not by this I don't
mean we're creating a little prototyping
playground no this is a serious
framework you can use to do your real
development but it's also much easier to
play around it sounds good
and I think for somebody coming into
learning to build tensorflow stuff I
find it's an easier way for them to get
started because it's more familiar yeah
I definitely like especially if you've
done any kind of playing around with
almost any machine learning library
before you've probably interacted with R
or with Python with numpy and those
things have this very interactive like
build as you go inspect as you go
development style and that's you can
replicate that one to one
on the floor would be your execution
right so it's very intuitive to go from
where you are now to like taking the
same methods and applying them to larger
interesting convolution Oh or recurrent
networks or recursive networks or all
these like cool other models that people
are super excited about these days egos
just taking a big step right it's moved
from country to the core intensive yes
we just graduated eager execution into
tensor folklore in TF 1.7 and this is a
strong statement from us that we're
happy with the eager execution API as it
stands like we think enable you get
execution gradient tape those symbols
have moved to Cora they're here to stay
and they're gonna be supported forever
with all the like API stability and
guarantees the chemist and so forth
we see eager as now being a core part of
the tensorflow experience and something
that most of our users are gonna
interactive at one point or another in a
way that will hopefully make them much
more productive and happier I actually
like the way you said that's a sign of
our confidence in ego that we've done
that so that that's really true and I
never thought about it that way so it's
kind of cool now one of the things you
said in your talk you were talking about
like how if somebody wants to write
eager compatible code and how they want
to optimize it that kind of stuff you
gave some guidance good
could you talk through that a little bit
for your code to work well and eager you
want to coach be written in a Python
like an object-oriented style right
graph just flows a little more flexible
and lets you write your code in a way
that involves a lot of action at a
distance which can be super powerful if
you know what you're doing and if you're
an expert with a tool but also can be a
little hard to approach so if we're you
to write code is gonna work well with
eager execution turned on and also when
you're building a graph it helps if you
avoid some of that action of the
distance and some other global state
that discipline has and just write more
straightforward object-oriented code so
things like when you're using layers
tentacle has these two parallel sets of
layers API is one that's a little more
functional and one that's a little more
object oriented and the object-oriented
layers please use those if you're
building your model of a confucian but
once you use those it just translates
naturally to building ground
same thing if you're like building a
model just if you're using functional
layers you might sometimes don't even
have a model class in your code have one
make it inherit from T after karasov
model which is a well-tested model class
has lots of utilities have to save load
train your model right it will save you
a lot of work it won't force you to do
anything but if you use its tools it's
gonna work perfectly well raviga
execution and also perfectly well on
building graphs so these are like big
things about how you build your model
directly but there's a lot more to
making in training machine learning
model than just your model building code
and sadly the TF dot summary package is
not compatible with the execution so
we're making a new summary package which
is now available in country but it will
soon move into a tensor board and this
new summary package is compatible both
eager execution and graph building nice
and similarly the metrics in TF dogmatix
they are not compatible with the
execution because they were written and
is very powerful like action and a
distance way that depends on graph
pruning for correctness so we're
introducing a new metrics package that
is works well in both eager and graph
right so as long as you like stick to
the nice object-oriented user-friendly
if you guys are gonna have high
performance easy to read code that's
gonna be developable and eager and then
deploy a billing graph or even
deployable and eager if you're all to
deploy - - environment so apart from
watching your talk what advice would you
give for somebody wanting to get started
in ego we have our test flow programmers
guide on the website if you go and
testify that are then click on
programmers guide as of today it should
have a chapter on eager execution and
it's really nice then introduces you to
test a flow too eager execution lets you
like play around with it shows you all
the key pieces all the tools you have at
your disposal
I strongly recommend anyone who is
interested to just go and play around
with that chapter the programmers guide
it has a link to a notebook that gives
you like a step-by-step tools like play
around and girls so I played with that
notebook it's really cool yeah right
it's so intuitive
going in France and you can change
things and you can see how they work I I
think eager plays really well with
notebooks and that interactive
development style and testing style
right which you know if our platform for
notebooks the Google collab also gives
anyone access to a GPU kernel so you can
even get the high performance GPU
training for a few hours for free yeah
or they hold a brand I call that yeah
said super cool so thank you so much
Alex that made a lot of fun I've been
really eager to have this conversation
so I had to get that joke in so and
thanks everybody for watching this
episode if you've got any questions for
me or if you have any questions for Alex
please leave them in the comments below
and don't forget to hit that subscribe
button thank you
[Music]