[Music]
we are here today to speak with you
about tensor close high-level api's so
one area I'm particularly passionate
about is making machine learning as
accessible as possible to as many people
as possible and the tensorflow team has
been investing very heavily in the same
thing so we spent a lot of energy making
tensorflow easier to use so there's
three things that are concrete that I'd
like to walk you through and the very
first is even if you're brand new to
tensorflow you're brand new to machine
learning even if you're new to Python
one area that seems silly but is
non-trivial for a lot of people is
actually just installing tensorflow and
different dependencies and I know for
Python developers is just pip install
tensorflow
but that can be hard for people that are
brand new so I'm gonna show you
something called collab and I'll walk
you through collab it's basically a
jupiter notebook server running in the
cloud it's free of charge it has
tensorflow
pre-installed comes with a free GPU it's
awesome I'll walk you through how to use
that how'd it get started with
tensorflow the next thing tensorflow has
many different api's but my personal
favorite what I'd strongly strongly
recommend to you is something called
chaos and chaos the chaos API is
completely implemented inside of
tensorflow it's great I can't tell you
how much fun I've had using it so I'll
walk you through writing hello world and
care us the same API is also useful for
tensorflow Jas and then I'm gonna point
you to some educational resources to
learn more so briefly this is what I
would do if you want to try tensorflow
and chaos and TF data and eager
execution in the fastest possible way
and I should tell you off the bat so all
these API is there fully implemented and
they're working well we are just now
starting to write all the samples and
Doc's around them so I have a feeling
the samples I was able to cook up for
this talk are they're quite rough but
stay tuned and check back in the next
few months as we flesh this out but let
me just show you how to dive right in so
if you go to this website it will bring
you to this github site and if you
scroll down to the readme you'll see a
sequence of a few notebooks
and I just wanna show you how easy it is
to get started if you just click on one
what happens is they open up immediately
in collab and so now you have a jupiter
notebook it's running entirely in the
cloud you can hit connect to connect to
a kernel and now I can start running
these cells and I'll walk you through
this in more detail in a few minutes but
if you go through the first notebook
this is going to show you how to write
your first neural network using Karos
there's a little bit of pre-processing
code but the notebook is very short
the next notebook will show you how to
do the same thing using Karos in
combination with TF data and eager
execution and then we go into a little
bit more depth so it's literally that
easy to get started
so there's broadly five steps to write
hello world and tensorflow using Karos
the good news is steps three four and
five are literally one line of code and
you can see that on the second line
we're importing emne stand this is easy
because the data set is already we have
a loader for it that's baked into
tensorflow here's the format of the data
set so as imported it's divided already
for us into train and test train is
about 60,000 test is 10,000 the top
right I have a diagram of the format of
the images if you look at the notebooks
on that workshop directory the best
thing you can do when you import a data
set is to spend a lot of time asking
really basic questions so literally when
you import the data print it out and
there's a couple points that I want to
make one this is the complete code to
define the network so it's code concise
too broadly
the more layers you add to your network
and the more neurons or units per layer
the more capacity your network has
meaning the more types of patterns that
can recognize the problem is the more
things your network can recognize the
more likely it is to memorize the
training data here's the cool part
building your model is where there are
many many machine learning concepts that
you have to spend a lot of time learning
the next three steps there are literally
concepts that are basically involved
with running an experiment here's the
only parameter so here's how you train
the model so it's one line fit is
synonymous with train and we're training
it using the training images and the
training labels training a network is a
little bit like tuning a guitar so think
of you have a good
car and you want to it starts untuned
and you want to tune the string is to
hit a particular note so you start
tuning it and like every time you twist
the wheel in the guitar you can think of
that as an F Bach after that you can
evaluate it and evaluate just means
giving some new data classify it with my
network and take a look at the accuracy
and other metrics that's also just one
line of code thank you very much
everyone I really appreciate your time
and hope this stuff is useful
[Music]