[Music]
hi everybody I'm Laurence Moroney I'm
reporting here from the tensorflow
summit we're in the tensorflow cafe and
it's a great pleasure to be chatting
with Ian Lang Moore who's a software
engineer and he works with tensorflow in
nuclear physics
Ian welcome hey well thanks for having
me on so tell us all about it what do
you do there's a goal of powering of
getting power from nuclear fusion right
so it's incredibly energy dense what you
do is you take maybe I can borrow a
couple of these coffee grinds you put
together two small nuclei okay and what
you get out weighs a little bit less
than what you put in and the remainder
is a huge amount of energy right so it's
the conversion of mass to energy and it
equals MC squared exactly yeah
and so it's so incredibly energy dense
that to provide the power that humanity
would need over the next hundred years
we require say the boron that the world
currently produces for just seven months
so say hey set aside the next seven
months of boron and we have enough
energy for the next hundred years and no
greenhouse gas emissions that would be
nice that would be nice and it's also
challenging so obviously anything that
has that high of a payoff people have
been trying and they've been trying for
about 70 years and what happens is the
plasma gets unstable so the reaction
happens inside of this plasma which is
say a swarm of charged particles and ten
million degrees or hotter and they don't
want to stay in place
right so they get excited at that
temperature yeah things get a little hot
they want to get out and what happens is
things become unstable they get out and
then it cools down and the reaction
stops and we end up putting in more
energy just to keep the reaction going
can we get out and that's what's been
happening for 70 years Wow okay so
there's this company
Foothill Ranch ta technologies that is
now on their fifth generation plasma
generator okay we've been working with
them since 2015 to try to accelerate
progress so it's this ends up being this
gigantic machine it's like think of this
long cigar where there's a hot plasma in
the middle okay and the goal is to use
the magnets and neutral beams and all
these other technologies to keep that
plasma confined so this is an
experimental reactor it's I mean it's
it's not the fusion reaction it's not
what's happening what's your hat what's
happening here is you're seeing how can
tightly can we can find this plasma as
we ramp up the temperature and so
they're doing experiments every 20
minutes and then every 20 minutes they
push down data we pull it in and we give
back a three-dimensional image of what
their plasma looks like okay nice you
might think well why can't I just look
at the plasma you know and the point is
first of all it's well it's very thin
and it's incredibly hot and you know you
can consider like why can't I just look
at a light bulb and tell you what's
inside of it well you only have a
two-dimensional view you're on the
boundary you get a two-dimensional view
of what goes on but you want to look at
a three-dimensional object right and
moreover it's so hot that you can only
have a limited number of views into it
so what you end up with things are like
you shine 14 lasers through the center
and you measure the phase shift of those
lasers okay and this gives you the
density along each of the lines but from
that you want to reconstruct the density
everywhere so it's a very under
determined problem so I've gone on for a
little no this is great so it's helping
clarify it for me hopefully for you too
and so but the idea then is that so this
distribution reactor every 20 minutes
you're doing an experiment you're
pulling that into code that you've
written intensive
and then that code is generating a 3d
image right yeah now that's not the
typical use of tentacle no no not at all
so this really isn't deep learning this
is an inverse problem this is great
though so it just shows the flexibility
of the classroom yeah a real key
difference is and deep learning often
you have many many many examples you
have many many labels so you have the
input output and you can learn a very
complex functional relationship so here
we actually don't have the labels that
the labels would be this is what the
actual plasma looks like but we're the
ones telling people what the plasma
looks like we don't have those we do
have a precise model for how the
measurement works and so from that it's
an even way think the naive thing would
be just to invert the equation so if
this is what the plasma was this is what
the measurement is well if we know the
measurement let's invert the equation
you get the plasma problem is it's
there's many plasmas that could have
given the same measurement so we're
gonna give them a distribution over
possible plasmas so doing a Bayesian
inverse problem okay and our graph is
modeling the measurement physics and
some physical assumptions rather than an
arbitrary function so then the output of
this does it become a situation where
because of running experiment every 20
minutes that they can now optimize their
future experiments based on the results
that you're giving them yeah well they
can understand their experiments based
on these results there's actually a
coincident effort by Googlers to help
optimize experimental design and there
was a paper published in that Ted bolts
is was one of the names Michael Ducati
well we'll put a link to the paper in
description so then people can go read
it for themselves so fascinating stuff
and it's like how did you get involved
in this well so I have been at Google
for about four years and I was looking
around internally for teams that were
doing something with reducing greenhouse
gas emissions
and so then this popped up and I was
like oh this is great and then it's an
inverse problem which is what I did for
my PhD and my pulse talk so it's like
okay this is like a perfect fit so when
I started working with them nice is your
row like coding the way yeah yeah so I
wrote is writing a code and also coming
up with the statistical models so I've
been writing code specific for our team
and then also the same time they were
writing code for the tensor flow
distributions and tensor flow
probability libraries so these are sort
of form the core building blocks like we
have a normal distribution object or a
Laplace distribution and so on and so
forth and these are you know it's an
object that allows you to you can
produce samples you can get a PDF and so
on and then we have a method or
transforming one distribution to another
with this thing called the by chapter
yep yep so we we actually did an episode
of coffee with a Googler on the
distribution API which is like yeah so
check it out on the Google developers
Channel it was assuming it was
mind-bending because of just the kind of
things that it offers to you as an API
by jackers and all that kind of thing so
it's like as a developer you can go
check that out the distributions API and
maybe they'll be able to build something
like you build for
thank you so much in this has been a
blast but it's alright I I never
expected to come here to learn a little
bit about nuclear fusion today so it's
like a very pleasant surprise thank you
so much if you have any questions for me
or if you have any questions for Ian
just please leave them in the comments
below and don't forget to hit that
subscribe button thank you so much
[Music]
you