hi everybody I'm Laurence Moroney we're
here at the tensorflow developers summit
at the intensive flow cafe and it's my
honor right now to meet with Pete worden
and Pete is the tech lead for tensorflow
on mobile which spends a whole lot of
things people must be a lot of fun oh
there's so much interesting stuff that
people are doing so here now at the
summit we've been showing a lot of
mobile stuff including TF lights yes yes
so what's new and exciting at TF light
so over the last year you know tend to
flow on mobile taking the whole of the
Thames flow framework and fitting it
down to feed our mobile has been really
useful for a lot of people and we've
done some seen some really interesting
applications that people have built but
what we've wanted to do is build
something that's even smaller even
faster and even easier to use
so that's really what TF ly is you know
its mission is to be that framework that
people are looking for we've been seeing
some really cool stuff done and over
like the Kesava demo in the keynote yes
yes I was we were just chatting
off-camera earlier and it was like to me
it blew my mind in that it's very hard
to convey well when we all have great
connectivity that why do you need it to
be isolated on a mobile but that example
I mean yeah how did that work so we
actually have been working with plant
village for I think up to a couple of
years now and we've been working with
them because they had such interesting
problems like they were trying to get
stuff into people's hands who didn't
have data connections and also even if
they had data connections they wanted
answers fast so getting that
interactivity and allowing people to
actually move the camera around and
focus it on the leaves and kind of get
that instant feedback makes a massive
difference for their application and
we've seen that across a whole bunch of
applications it's not just oh I don't
have a data connection it's like oh I
need to work with video or audio and I
need that instant interactivity that you
can only get by running on device that
makes sense and it yet so you got that
speed right because video might be a big
upload to the cloud yeah
that's actually pretty cool and then
beyond like mobile like Android and iOS
now you have TF like tensorflow like
coming on Raspberry Pi yeah we sort of
pulls them all of that yes and Andy has
been doing amazing work with the vast
blue pie and actually getting the speed
that we've got on Android and iOS
actually ported over to these wonderful
sort of $25 devices and these things
that you can put almost anywhere and do
I think we were talking earlier about
donkey car yeah yeah is this fantastic
example of using temp to flow running on
a Raspberry Pi to power a self-driving
toy racing car and if you've seen the
videos they're incredible how they
differ I actually bought when I'm
building it myself a convinced I don't
know what it's gonna be like driving it
at home but we'll see but an actual
self-driving car even though it's a toy
but about yay big but on a Raspberry Pi
yes yeah I think about that think about
the compute power of a Raspberry Pi and
now you can build a self-driving car
thanks to and the fact that this can be
something that almost anybody can
actually buy and build themselves now
for just you know it's so much fun
seeing this get into you know I have a
lot of kids actually playing around with
this stuff a lot of high school students
as well building all of these crazy sort
of you know trash sorters using
raspberry pies you know all of these
other like really really interesting
projects you can only build if you have
this cheap almost disposable computer
that you can play with but when you can
take a model that was typically only
restricted to high ends the offensive
super computers nowadays were tensorflow
you can train that on your desktop
machine might take a little longer we
can train on your desktop machine you
can flatten it and you can deploy it
quickly to an Android or an iOS or now a
Raspberry Pi so they take it
and yeah one thing I would like to give
a shout out to is actually tend to flow
for poets the tutorial which doesn't
require any coding yeah and we actually
have the ability to very easily get that
on to iOS Android or the Raspberry Pi
okay so if you don't feel confident in
coding at all you can still create your
own image model you can just use
tensorflow for poets go through the code
lab and on a laptop with no GPU required
in half an hour
fingers crossed you should have your own
model and if you're now familiar with
out what that does is it takes the last
layer and with it it uses write very
much classification mobile net on it yes
so it takes the last layer of that and
in the poet's code lab you can replace
the last layer of that so instead of
classifying general images you train it
on a bunch of flowers and it recognizes
those flowers and like you said code
lessly you can do it and we generally
have it at conferences like Google i/o
and I think it was the most popular code
lab at i/o last year so it's super cool
but back to Raspberry Pi for a second so
like you know the demo that we showed
earlier on was like tensorflow light
running on a raspberry yes which was
inference only but people will also want
to be able to train on as something like
a raspberry pi yeah how would that work
so the vast we PI is this really
interesting beast because it's half like
a Linux desktop and it's half like a
mobile phone so when all you want to do
is run influenced run a model that's
already been trained tensorflow light is
great for that
but if you actually want to use Python
and you want to program and use the full
programming environment of tensorflow
and do training of models you can
actually get binary pip installs and
just do a pip install there is a URL
that you can find if you unfortunately
we don't have it up on the Ted's photo
org website I'll put a link in that we
will we will add a link that you can
actually just do a pip install and get
it on your arms lastly pie in minutes
cuz so to be able to do that on a small
embedded system because there may be
scenarios like we're talking about
earlier where you don't want to cut
round-trip to the cloud yes and
especially doing things like
personalization or modifying according
to data that you don't want to leave the
device right that can be a really
interesting appetite
so if I'm a developer and I want to get
started and enjoying all this magic
other than the center proper poets
codelab do you have any oh that's that's
a really good question I would actually
look through the examples that are
intensive low and tend to flow light we
actually have some demo applications
that you should be able to get up and
running pretty easily in Xcode or
Android studio and really play around
with them and start to get ideas and
learn to modify the code that's already
there it's so much easier to start with
code that's already working yeah than
trying to build something from scratch
so I actually put the demo on my is my
pixel and I put the Android demo on here
and I'm having fun going around and
classifying and the speed is actually
really good because I can point it like
for example at a mug and it's generally
less than 100 milliseconds and it will
classify itself yeah super and that's in
Java
that's not C first place and that's in
Java and with the neural network API
coming up in Android yeah Android P well
we actually have a preview of it out
already you should see even better
performance especially using the
Qualcomm HVX accelerator bits in your
pixel so nice nice I'll look out further
maybe I'll have to put a pee preview on
here yeah so thank you so much Pete that
it's been a blast I won't learn it fun
sounds Lawrence and thanks everybody for
watching I'm Laurence Moroney and I've
had Pete worden on the show if you have
any questions for me or if you have any
questions for Pete please leave them in
the comments below and don't forget to
hit that subscribe button
[Music]