[Music]
did you know that tensorflow j/s isn't
just for JavaScript on the backend with
node but can also be used in the browser
yes you can train models in the browser
with JavaScript and not only that you
can run inference too and if that wasn't
enough you can have models that you've
trained elsewhere and run inference on
those in the browser using javascript so
today's tip is how do I get my browser
ready for tensorflow and this one's
almost cheating it's a little too easy
so let's start with the simplest web
page imaginable we'll save and run it
and we'll see that we just get an empty
page so let's add a script tag to the
head and we'll add the tensorflow dot
j/s script to that we can save and run
it again and now look at the page
there's not allowed to see right now so
let's add a div to the page and we'll
output to that later
so now let's add a simple script for
training a model to infer a linear
relationship we'll create a model and
just add a single layer to it and we'll
specify the loss function and the
optimizer after that we'll specify a
couple of tensors for the values one
tensor has the X values and the other
has the Y there's a relationship between
them which is y equals 2x minus 1 but
the models going to infer that we train
the model with model dot fit and then
we'll output the prediction for y where
x equals 10 now of course it should be
about 19 so let's take a look and see
and we actually get pretty close so
there's your start in using tensorflow
with javascript I do hope this was a
useful primer for you for more great
videos like this one hit that subscribe
button and we'll see you there
[Music]