[Music]
welcome to tents Flo meets I'm Pete
worden and today we're gonna be talking
to marius erickson so I understand
you're using tensorflow to help your
daughter who's a type 1 diabetic maybe
you could tell us a bit more about that
sure yeah so it helps have a little bit
of background and what's our treating
type 1 diabetes entails so when you are
a type 1 diabetic your pancreas is
basically non functioning and not
secreting insulin into your bloodstream
which is required for yourselves to take
up glucose because of this phenomenon we
have basically be able to predict what
glucose levels should be and then based
on that prediction the liver sort of a
correct amount of insulin or withhold
insulin if we predict that blood glucose
is going to go low right and so because
of those those reasons we approach that
I've taken is to employ machine learning
actually in two ways so one is a model
that uses data that's gathered on a
continual basis every five minutes and
predicts future blood glucose based on
you know that passed and then secondly a
different model or rather model that
builds on the first model tries to
figure out what is an optimal insulin
delivery schedule that will effectively
you know keep blood sugar within this
sort of Goldilocks zone right and so
that second model knows about the sort
of pharmacodynamics of insulin and so on
and so forth
and actually use tensorflow for both of
those right one of the really nice
things about tensorflow is that it's
very easy to compose these models
together and that's exactly what how
this works awesome do you want to it
looks like you actually have pump dead
so this is the pump or pump similar to
what my daughter worse and this is just
something you keep in your pocket or
whatever and there so you see is a
little too big that comes out of this
and insulin reservoir in here the tubing
connects to you know effectively a small
needle that that's inserted into some
fatty area of your body
this pump in particular can be
controlled remotely and so the first
thing that had to do for this
there's not machine learning so related
is to effectively reverse reverse
engineer that radio protocol so I can
control it from a Raspberry Pi which is
the second component and so this is a
Raspberry Pi zero as we can see and this
is sort of where all the magic happens
and so the Raspberry Pi zero through a
custom I some radio with custom firmware
that knows how to communicate to the
insulin pump can effectively instruct in
some pump what to do deliver this much
insulin or withholding stone or whatever
the Raspberry Pi also uses ble to
communicate with the phone and that
serves two purposes one is to receive
blood glucose values from this
continuous glucose monitoring system
that integrates with the phone and the
second is to receive instructions from
the phone as to for example when my
daughter eats and so whenever she eats
we have to enter all your we're eating
this many grams of carbs so the model
can take that into account right and
without that it wouldn't be able to
predict the future very well so what
does your daughter think of this this is
making a difference for her oh
absolutely and so so there's there's two
big ways in which it makes the
difference I think so one is it just
reduces the labor intensity of diabetes
you know you still have to intervene on
occasion there's still a lot of things
to do but you can't beat a computer in
terms of you know being able to do the
same thing every five minutes over and
over and over again right and so
literally every five minutes the system
adjusts insulin delivery based on the
you know predicted what it predicts in
the future the second big thing is that
typically the way diabetes is treated is
with something called basal and bolus
therapy and what that means is that it's
a it's a you know still fairly complex
but far simplified version of what the
model does and you have to sort of even
with this therapy you have to every time
you eat you know check what your blood
glucose us computes you know using a few
ratios how much insulin to liver
and then do it and then check your blood
sugar you know again a little bit later
but again with with using machine
learning techniques and and and other
things we can do far far better we can
understand much more deeply the the
evolution of insulin in the blood we can
predict the evolution of carbohydrate or
parents in the blood and so on and so
forth and the way this model works is
that it you know it's obviously trained
with a lot of historical data and so
individual variants right it's also
something that the model can pick up
very readily right so as an example it's
known that individuals respond slightly
differently to to insulin right maybe
the pharmacodynamics evolved in slightly
different ways maybe they maybe it takes
longer for the insulin to Claire right
maybe the peak is stronger things like
that with this model it actually learns
what the pharmacodynamics are so you
mentioned data as well how did you
actually go about getting the training
data that you needed to train and test
these models right so after i
reverse-engineered the the RF protocol
of the pump i started basically first as
observing and so every five minutes that
effectively queries the pump and asks
how much of it delivered in the last
five minutes right but still doing
manual therapy right so we're still
administering insulin through the remote
control but we were controlling it right
and then all at the same time entering
every time my daughter had a meal we
were to enter our estimate of the number
of carbs in that meal and our estimate
of the grassy mechanics so those things
together would capturing the glucose
readings from the continuous glucose
monitors effectively gives us all the
raw data right so we can observe blood
glucose levels observe the insulin that
that's been delivered and all the food
that she bet she ate and so that's
that's basically how we gathered the raw
data we do that for you know a few
months before I started you know with
the exercise of modeling and at this
point my daughter's values are almost
normal glycemic meaning that from that
point of view it's almost as if she
doesn't have diabetes and so that's
another huge benefit of
Automation and again this is possible to
achieve you know if you're willing to
you know look at your blood sugar every
five minutes and do a motion asking a
five-year-old girl to have to deal with
that when she's more interested in
correct running around and playing is
doesn't work here so maybe you can tell
me a bit about how you found you know I
decided on tensorflow
and how you used it the vast bleep I
yeah so the reason I decided on on
tensorflow is initially because it was
very easy to sort of switch from
experimentation into production right
and so I would do all the kind of
modeling work and experimentation and
you know it's Jupiter notebooks and all
this stuff is very very convenient and
the controller code is actually written
in go right so all the stuff that deals
with the radio transmission and the time
series databases and all that stuff it's
all written and go
and so with tensorflow I was able to
take the model that had developed in
this Jupiter notebook save it to you
know protocol buffers basically and then
you know load it up and go and that
provides a really nice and clean
interface I almost never have to change
the sort of go code that loads the model
it knows how to feed at the right data
and everything but I can change
completely the behavior of the model
just you know sort of purely in this
high-level way using Python right so
that was one really big appealing thing
for tons of flow the other thing obvious
is that it can run in embedded systems
right and so you know the Raspberry Pi
is an ARM based system and I can run the
the inference and the retraining you
know without having to worry about the
underlying architecture or anything like
that
the third thing I think is I'm very much
using the sort of composability of the
tensor flow compute a computation graphs
so as an example it was very easy to
take the model that predicts blood
glucose and compose it with the model
that is going to recommend an insulin
delivery schedule right and because of
the way the competition graphs works and
the automatic differentiation and
everything you know it's it's very very
easy to you know build the second model
and just let an optimizer how they go at
it and you get the right results right
now without having me having to sit down
do any cow
glass or anything like that which is
very very appealing to me so I said
those are kind of main reasons
yeah and for the listeners we do
actually now have a version of
tensorflow that is built already for the
Raspberry Pi that we run as part of our
nightly builds so I'm hoping as you look
at upgrading tensorflow in the future if
we may be able to help you get up and
running using some pre-built binaries so
that you don't have to build everything
from scratch if that's crew it's awesome
that you're actually able to you know
pull it all together and get it up and
running that's right yeah III think it
speaks to Tesla flow that that was
perhaps the most difficult part of this
and is the is the code available for
what you've actually built yes so some
of it is so for different reasons you
know obviously this is a system that
carries some risk and you know could be
construed as a medical device and things
like that the the model that I use in in
production I have not actually released
publicly but kind of most of the code
around it I have right including the
radio stack for you know all that stuff
however I have made a notebook that kind
of replicates the the general setup also
in terms of flow they're using a much
simpler model but it replicates
precisely what the setup is so you have
a model that predicts blood glucose and
then a second model that composes the
first in order to optimize the delivery
schedule and so that's all open source
is a Jupiter notebook that I published
those basically show and demonstrate how
how this can be done in this in this
manner so obviously this is a very
safety critical system and it poses a
lot of questions and problems you
wouldn't have in other machine learning
systems can you tell us a little bit
about how you thought and planned and
tackled that yeah absolutely so so
there's a few different aspects of that
so one is you know obviously a model can
learn the wrong thing and do something
dangerous and so
you know in order to kind of prevent
that there's all sorts of sort of
secondary safety measures in place that
you know simpler models that perform
safety checks effectively and will sort
of shut off the the main model if it if
it's doing the wrong thing
right so that's sort of one aspect of it
the other thing is that from a sort of
systems perspective it's designed to
limit the you know the the amount of
action that the model can do and so as
an example if her blood group know if if
your blood glucose is very very high and
the model wants to correct it down to
the range that it that is desired so the
set point what it does is instead of
correcting down to that range it
corrects down to some maximum level
beneath what it is - at the moment and
so it's required to basically gradually
correct down so that in case sensitivity
changes very rapidly you don't end up
over delivering it's your effective is
kind of throttling the action of the
system and so there are a few mechanisms
like that and then from a sort of
systems point of view anytime you have
you know data loss or you know even if
the software crashes for example it's
the sign so that it fails in a safe way
so you know shuts off insulin or
delivers only a small very small amount
okay well thanks so much everyone for
joining us on tensorflow meats and thank
you Marius and if you want to see more
like this please hit that subscribe
button
see ya
[Music]
[Applause]
you