hey everyone good morning thanks for
coming so early so my name is Josh
Gordon and I'm Laurence Moroney and we
are here today to speak with you about
tensor close high-level api's and I have
a lot of good news for you and I hope
this talk will be concrete and useful so
one area I'm particularly passionate
about is making machine learning as
accessible as possible to as many people
as possible and the tensorflow team has
been investing very heavily in the same
thing so we spent a lot of energy making
tensorflow easier to use and I'd like to
show you basically a demo of what is in
my opinion the very easiest way to get
started with tensorflow today
so there's three things that are
concrete that I'd like to walk you
through and the very first is even if
you're brand new to tensorflow you're
brand new to machine learning even if
you're new to Python one area that seems
silly but is non-trivial for a lot of
people is actually just installing
tensorflow in different dependencies and
I know for Python developers is just pip
install tensorflow but that can be hard
for people that are brand new so I'm
gonna show you something called collab
and I'll walk you through collab
it's basically a jupiter notebook server
running in the cloud it's free of charge
it has tensorflow pre-installed comes
with a free GPU it's awesome I'll walk
you through how to use that how'd it get
started with tensorflow the next thing
tensorflow has many different api's but
my personal favorite what I'd strongly
strongly recommend to you is something
called chaos and chaos the chaos API is
completely implemented inside of
tensorflow it's great I can't tell you
how much fun I've had using it so I'll
walk you through writing hello world and
care us the same API is also useful for
tensorflow Jas and then I'm gonna point
you to some educational resources to
learn more cool so these are the api's
that I want to briefly introduce so
chaos it's basically Lego like building
blocks for building and defining models
TF data so when a lot of people start
learning ml they get really hung up on
okay they learned that a neural network
is composed of layers and they find out
that they can adjust the number of
neurons per layer and there's different
hyper parameters like the optimizer and
stuff like that they spend a lot of time
on what I call modeling but something
that's really really important but
doesn't get enough attention is actually
how do you get your data into the
network and writing input pipelines is
non-trivial so I'm also going to show
you an API called TF data which is a
relatively easy to use but also a very
high-performance way of writing your
input pipelines and then I'm gonna show
you eager execution if you're new to
tips and Lawrence is gonna give you a
lot more depth on eager yep by the way
when you hear the word eager execution
if you're new to tensor flow just ignore
that and just think of this as this is
the thing you always do so you should
always write and run so develop and
debug your tensor flow programs eagerly
and it makes tensorflow feel just like
regular Python this is a short talk so
I'm not going to go into all the details
of how tensorflow works under the hood
but this is the right way to do it if
you're learning tensor flow today so
briefly this is what I would do if you
want to try tensor flow and chaos and TF
data and eager execution in the fastest
possible way and I should tell you off
the bat so all these API is there fully
implemented and they're working well we
are just now starting to write all the
samples and Doc's around them so I have
a feeling the samples I was able to cook
up for this talk are they're quite rough
but stay tuned and check back in the
next few months as we flesh this out but
let me just show you how to dive right
in so if you go to this website it will
bring you oh can we switch to the laptop
for a minute please
thank you it will bring you to this
github site and if you scroll down to
the readme you'll see a sequence of a
few notebooks and I just want to show
you how easy it is to get started if you
just click on one what happens is they
open up immediately in collab and so now
you have a jupiter notebook it's running
entirely in the cloud you can hit
connect to connect to a kernel and now I
can start running these cells and I'll
walk you through this in more detail in
a few minutes
but if you go through the first notebook
this is going to show you how to write
your first neural network using Karos
there's a little bit of pre-processing
code but the notebook is very short
the next notebook will show you how to
do the same thing using Karos in
combination with TF data and eager
execution and then we go into a little
bit more depth so it's literally that
easy to get started it will take you
about five minutes end-to-end to try
this out all right so let's let's switch
back to the slides please
and let me give you a little bit more
depth of what's happening in these
notebooks so of using the Charis api
this is the complete code - a few lines
of pre-processing just formatting the
data to write train evaluate and make
predictions with your first neural
network in tensorflow so if you were
using tensorflow about a year ago it
would have been substantially more code
and there's other great high-level API
is including estimators which are really
really wonderful for doing machine
learning at production but at least for
learning ml I'd strongly recommend this
so I will walk you through exactly what
all of these lines are doing and one
point I want to make is that the code is
it's concept heavy but code light so
writing the code itself should no longer
be a barrier to getting started with ml
I hope that far fewer people are gonna
spend energy and time on the syntax and
debugging and now you can spend more of
your time and energy thinking about what
you're trying to do and why oh yeah and
before I dive into code I want to make a
really really important point so machine
learning is a broad field by far another
mistake that a lot of students make when
they're learning is they learn how to
train an image classifier like we're
gonna do in a moment and they find out
when they write the classifier they
start evaluating it and they see these
numbers like 99% accuracy and then they
find out that by tweaking the network
you can get to like ninety nine point
six or whatever and in reality it almost
never matters the most important thing
you can spend your time on is designing
the experiment and what I mean by that
is concretely thinking about what are
you trying to predict and why how will
it be used in practice what could go
wrong where does the data come from
thinking through the design of your
system as you would in any type of
software is much much more important
than messing around trying to get higher
accuracy
I'm not gonna cover this today there's a
whole talk on that but today I just
wanna show you the code but always think
about what and why in addition to how
all right so before I dive into this a
couple cool things not enough time to
introduce tensorflow I just wanted to
call out the community is the most
important thing about tensorflow in
addition to the thousand plus folks who
have contributed code there are many
many more who are doing things like
teaching organizing events writing
articles these things are incredibly
valuable too and there's a few new
things that I just wanted to call out
this came out two days ago so there's
another library called tensorflow J s
part of tensorflow
in JavaScript uses the same API is the
Charis API that i'ma show you today
weren't you gonna act out this slide I
was gonna act this out great sandbox
where you can try it I could dance it
out anyway it basically it's tensorflow
running in the browser and this runs in
real time there's two links on the
bottom if you check this out at home
there's a really great demo you can play
with on our blog and you can actually
find the code on the website another
thing there's a pair of links here which
I'd really encourage you to try so this
is magenta and magenta is a project that
uses tensorflow for experiments in art
and music and here this is computer
assisted drawing so magenta is helping
me draw duck so I'm drawing the duck
with the mouse in magenta it's sort of
like autocomplete for drawing there's a
great game called quick draw which I'd
encourage you to try it's great for kids
it's yeah quick draw and the magenta
demo is great to try just some fun stuff
before we get in the code and also
before I get the code in a personal note
one of the reasons I care about machine
learning so much is because of a project
called cell bot and cell bot is a
project from 2004 it was in a biology
lab and so bot uses a neural network to
identify specific types of cells in
solution and then sort them and what was
so cool to me as a student working on
this is that machine learning is not
just for computer scientists the fact
that biologists were trying to do
something useful using technology that
originated in our field was really
meaningful to me it's how can we use
machine learning for medicine for art
for healthcare just to do useful things
in the world so that's that's kind of
the thinking behind everything I do with
no it's what can we do to help people
basically all right so collab the URL
for collab is collab research Google com
collab is short for a collaboratory it's
inspired a lot by Google Docs it's a
Google Doc style of code editor and you
can download basically you can save
Jupiter notebooks in Google Drive you
can download them back as regular
Jupiter notebooks so there's no lock and
I know a lot of people by the way are
not from Python so I just want to spend
a minute and introduce Jupiter notebooks
so broadly here's collab and there's two
types of cells
there's markdown cells which contain
markdown and if you edit a markdown cell
like I'm doing with HelloWorld and you
execute it it just renders the markdown
the other type of cell is a code cell
and if you edit the code and execute the
cell it executes the code that's all it
is and there's one really cool thing as
well as that they give you access to
GPUs yes I've spoken with a lot of
people who either find it very difficult
to set up their GPUs or you know maybe
they're in a university environment and
they don't have access to expensive GPUs
and if you're using a colab you can
actually connect it to a GPU in our data
centers so that you can test out your
code running on GPUs exactly with no
coal at all yep it's a really good point
the other thing you can do if you're new
to Jupiter notebooks is you can create
visualizations in line so here I'm using
matplotlib to plot some data and the
graph goes right in line with your
notebook and this is really important
because it's a great way to share
results another thing that I wanted to
mention quickly is you can pip install
libraries so you're basically you're
running in some containers sitting
somewhere on GCP but you can install
whatever libraries you need so here on
pip installing matplotlib so you have
root access to it and then the last
thing a lot of people missed this
feature but it's super useful it's
called snippets and it's it's
conveniently hidden in the table of
contents but what I'm doing in this
notebook is I'm going to create some
data and then I'm going to download the
data off of colab back to my laptop and
to find out how to do that I click on
the snippets thing and I start searching
for downloading data and colab can't
totally see it on the screen has a
snippet of code that I could just copy
and paste directly into notebook and run
so it has examples how to install
libraries and everything like that it's
super useful don't have time to talk
about this collab is great for
reproducible examples alright so let me
jump right into what it looks like to
use chaos
to write your first nil Network and I
talked about this earlier but no one has
ever looked at the code to write your
first mil network regardless of how
smart you are it doesn't matter if you
have like a PhD in physics or whatever
and it's just gone oh I get it it's
impossible it takes months to learn this
stuff so it's completely normal to see
lots of concepts and have no idea what
they mean but let me just at least
introduce you and then I'll point you to
a course you can use to get more depth
oh the other thing I should probably
look at my slides right so you'll see
lots of parameters when you define these
networks and really only one or two are
important to spend your time on and I'll
point you what those are as we go so
there's broadly five steps to write
hello world and tensorflow using chaos
the good news is steps three four and
five are literally one line of code so
that's that's all the work of training
the network evaluating your accuracy and
making predictions collecting the data
set in reality takes a long time
pre-processing the data takes a long
time that's just getting it to the right
shape and building your model is where a
lot of the concepts are so let's see
what this looks like so we're gonna use
em mist I know for people that are
machine learning experts you know em
this cold and the reason I picked it is
just so we don't have to worry too much
about the data if you're new to M this
it's it's sort of the hello world of
computer vision it's a data set of about
60,000 plus very low resolution
handwritten digits and our goal is to
train an image classifier to classify or
recognize digits that it hasn't seen
before so here's what we'll do we'll
import tensorflow and you can see that
on the second line we're importing emne
stand this is easy because the data set
is already we have a loader for it
that's baked into tensorflow and if
you're new to using kiosk mode
tensorflow you can see that it's just
included you can do TF care us and now
you have access to the complete chaos
API so there's nothing else to do it's
just it's just there and this is awesome
by the way there are many many awesome
advanced things you can do using chaos
and tensorflow like it's great here I'm
just trying to show you the straight
easiest possible way here's the format
of the data set so as imported it's
divided already for us since a train and
test train is about 60,000 tests is
10,000 the top right I have a diagram of
the format of the images if you look at
them
books on that workshop directory the
best thing you can do when you import a
data set is to spend a lot of time
asking really basic questions so
literally when you import the data print
it out for an out the shape print out a
single image look at the format what's
the data type is a floating-point is it
an integer what are the dimensions how
many do I have spending a lot of time
just understanding the format the
plumbing will save you a lot of headache
later on so it's always okay to ask
really basic questions in the bottom
right there's many neural networks that
work with 2d images here we're gonna
make a simplification and we're just
gonna unroll the thing so instead of a
2d image we're literally gonna unstack
the rows these images happen to be 28 by
28 pixels when we unstack them we get a
vector that's 28 times 28 equals 780
something
pixels in a line so it's a
simplification that's all it is to
import the data set I didn't show the
code which is just numpy to reshape it
but it's in the notebook so now we're
gonna build our model and here's
concepts that will be probably entirely
meaningless to you if you're brand new
to ml one funny thing about neural
networks so there's many different types
of classifiers and most of my background
I was really invested in tree based
models before deep learning was a thing
and the reason I like tree based models
like random forests is that I can look
at a tree and intuitively my brain
understands exactly what the tree is
doing to classify the data like I get it
it clicks the neural networks can be a
little bit counterintuitive it's hard to
describe in 30 seconds but let me just
tell you what we're doing and you can
take the course to learn more so here
we're defining a fully connected deep
neural network there's gonna be two
layers that you can see so first we're
saying we're defining our model we're
saying we're gonna use the sequential
API which is the simplest API to define
your model it literally means our model
is going to be a stack of layers the
first layer that we're stacking on is
gonna be a dense layer dense means it's
fully connected and I'll show you
diagram of this I'm sorry there's just
this is a one layer network but the
notebooks have an exercise where you can
add a second layer and then we're adding
an output layer with ten outputs and
each of those outputs is basically going
to gather evidence that the image that
we feed through this network corresponds
to each of the digits and this slide I
was editing these slides last night so
this slide is actually a little bit
different but here we actually do have
two dense layers the point that I want
to mention there's a couple points that
I want to make one this is the complete
code to define the network so it's code
concise too broadly
the more layers you add to your network
and the more neurons or units per layer
the more capacity your network has
meaning the more types of patterns that
can recognize the problem is the more
things your network can recognize the
more likely it is to memorize the
training data so in machine learning
there's always this tension between
memorization and generalization you
don't want to just memorize the training
data what you want to do is learn
patterns that are useful to classify
digits that you haven't seen before so
it's very easy to get very high accuracy
on the training set by building a deep
neural network with many neurons and
training it for a long time it's not
necessarily the right thing to do though
so when you're messing around with these
architectures start as simply as
possible and then slowly expand from
there the next thing you have to do is
compile your network this is the last
step of building it it's just one line
there's two concepts I'll get is the
optimizer in a sec the loss function is
basically the objective that your
network is trying to optimize the good
news here is this is a fancy word
categorical cross entropy but what it
literally means is your network is going
to make a prediction so you feed an
image of a two through your network and
it gives you a probability distribution
over all the digits that it could be so
maybe with 10% probability it's a 0 with
5% probability to 1 hopefully with like
90% probability it's a 2 anyway this is
a fancy word that compares the thing the
network predicted to the thing you
wanted it to predict and what you want
it to predict is all the evidence is on
it - the other thing is the optimizer
and this is the method with which you're
going to train the network the truth is
there's a whole bag of different
optimizers you can use you don't have to
worry about what rmsprop means too much
because there are good defaults so for
this type of classification problem
basically you're always using
categorical cross entropy and rmsprop is
a perfectly good
vizor to start with using all the
default parameters so there's there's
good defaults broadly the way the
network is trained is using gradient
descent so here's here's how I would
think about this what a neural network
is when we add those dense layers there
are many different weights connecting
the pixels to the neurons and you can
think of all those weights as a
parameter so here's the simplest example
that I had in my head if you think of
linear regression so let's start with
linear regression you have some points
on some plot and you're trying to find
the best fit line and if you think about
from high school the equation for the
best fit line you've got like y equals
MX plus B and you've got two parameters
that you're trying to learn M is the
slope and you have B it's the intercept
and for different values of M and B you
can calculate how well your line fits
the data and you can look at your error
and there's different ways to get your
error but maybe it's the sum of the
distances from your line to the pixels
so by adjusting m and B you can find the
best fit line neural networks are
trained in a very same in a similar way
except instead of M and B you've got
hundreds of thousands of parameters that
you're trying to learn and these
parameters connect the pixels to the
neurons and so on and so forth and the
way they're trained is using something
called gradient descent and there's a
fancy diagram on the right that's
showing something that's not relevant
but they all start at random values and
you slowly adjust them over time until
the network becomes better at
recognizing digits
anyway I'll point you more educational
resources in a second so here's the cool
part building your model is where there
are many many machine learning concepts
that you have to spend a lot of time
learning the next three steps they're
literally concepts that are basically
involved with running an experiment
so there's here's the only parameter so
here's how you train the model so it's
one line fit is synonymous with train
and we're training it using the training
images and the training labels here's
the only parameter that really matters
and the good news is this concept is a
little bit simpler so Epic's basically
means an epoch means one sweep over all
the training day
so we have 60,000 images one epic
basically means that we're training the
network on all those wants training a
network is a little bit like tuning a
guitar so think if you have a guitar and
you want to it starts untuned and you
want to tune the strings to hit a
particular note so you start tuning it
and like every time you twist the wheel
in the guitar you can think about as an
epic and you tune for a certain number
of epochs until the guitar plays the
right note if you keep tuning past that
point it's no longer gonna play the
right note and eventually the string is
gonna snap so you have to stop tuning it
at a certain point and you stop tuning
it based on the sound you neural
networks are exactly the same way so
there's basically one very simple plot
and it's this which I'd recommend you
look at while you're training your
networks on the y-axis we're seeing this
fancy thing called loss that basically
means air loss is the same thing as air
it's just a fancy word for it what we're
trying to do is minimize our air on the
x-axis is how long we're tuning the
network in terms of number of epics the
longer if you notice after a few epics
the loss reaches a low that's kind of
when the guitar hits the right note if
you keep training the loss will start
increasing again so to find the right
number of epochs you literally make a
plot like this you just plot your air
and then you take a look at you look for
the point of lowest loss usually under
validation data after that you can
evaluate it and evaluate just means
giving some new data classify it with my
network and take a look at the accuracy
in other metrics that's also just one
line of code and as called this will
give you your loss or your air and your
accuracy when you train the model you
can specify other metrics that you like
returned and then to make predictions on
new data it's also just one line of code
so there's some syntax here so you can
say model dot predict and you give it an
image the syntax here is a little funny
as it happened the model expects what's
called a batch of data and a batch just
means it's it's meant to predict on
multiple images at once so you give it
an image and you just wrap it in a list
and this is just syntax to make it happy
but we're making predictions on the on
on the very first image from this
test data and what the model gives you
back is probabilities that that image
corresponds to all the different digits
and basically at the very lowest layer
of the network you'll have evidence
sitting in on the output nodes and if
you do a numpy dot Arg max so you just
find the largest element that will be
the prediction
so here it's predicting that it's a
seven I'm gonna give you a really quick
overview of TF data and then I'm gonna
hand it over to Laurence to show us a
little bit more about eager so when I
would here's something to be aware of in
tensorflow there's many different ways
of doing things you should always do the
simplest possible thing that's adequate
for your problems
so never basically when you're starting
with ml and in probably 90% of settings
don't worry about performance just try
and minimize complexity so before we
wrote our hello world just using the
emne Stata in numpy format that's fine
if we were working with a much larger
data set or if we were reading images
off disk or if we were pulling them from
the cloud there's a lot of complexity
there and performance starts to matter
for example there's latency when you
pull images over network so maybe you'd
want to hit a bunch of different servers
at once or maybe you'd want a bunch of
different threads so TF data has all
sorts of functionality to help you with
things like this also one funny thing
that's happened so GPUs and TP use have
become surprisingly fast and the latency
in training a lot of models is actually
can you keep the GPU fed there's
something called GPU starvation where
the matrix multiply there is so fast
that it's just sitting around waiting
for data and so TF data has lots of
utilities to get your stuff like
prefetching it to the GPU if you need to
anyway what we're gonna do here is hello
world so we imported em missed just one
care us and just for demonstration
purposes I'm gonna wrap it in a TF data
data set so I'm creating a data set from
tensor slices which is a fancy word
which basically tells it that hey this
is a list of things and I want every
element in the list to be an item of my
data set the next thing to do it has
this very nice clean API I can say I
also want you to shuffle the data here
TF data is designed to work with
potentially very long lists
things and it could be an infinite
stream of data you don't want to shuffle
the whole stream so shuffle has a size
for the buffer so I'm here I have a
buffer of a thousand elements in I'm
going to shuffle them as they stream in
and then I can batch it up that means
when I call this data set I'm gonna get
back a batch of 32 things and so now I
want to show you very briefly how do you
use it so to use it what you can do and
this is the complete code by the way you
can just say like for images and labels
print them out so this looks obvious to
me and it's the way things should work
but if you're new to tensorflow it
didn't used to always work this way so
if you have previous experience in
tensorflow you can take a look and you
notice nowhere in this code is there a
session there's no placeholders I'm not
mentioning the word graph I'm just
writing regular Python code and the
thing just works so this is eager
execution in tensorflow 1/8 plus the
only thing I have to do is the second
line of code there it's just I enable
the thing you need to do this at the
start of the Python file or notebook and
now you're basically running tensorflow
eagerly which if you're starting out
it's just regular Python and this is the
right way to use tensorflow it makes
debugging much easier there's lots of
reasons why you would use graphs and we
still love grass there's great talks
from the tensorflow developer summit
that will go into them in lots of detail
but at least when you're hacking
definitely definitely do this okay so
for more context and all that I've been
talking for a while you search element
been handed over to points thanks
everybody just quick survey the crowd
how many software developers here I were
at i/o so we figured it would have a few
so that's good so I've just been working
on tensorflow for a few months and I
think for a getting started intensive
well can be a little bit difficult if
you're coming from a software dev
background and getting started in any
kind of ml can be a little bit tricky
because there's so many new and
different concepts first of all there's
all the math right I mean I didn't even
understand this math when I was in high
school and now I have to understand it
again you know people tell me about
linear regressions and my head explodes
but then you know it's learn herbal it's
something that you can pick up but then
secondly is really the programming model
and what what is the programming model
all about and I come from a background
of traditional program
and in traditional programming you
basically you feed in the rules you feed
in the data and you get answers out so
for example if you're writing something
like an activity detector am i walking
am i running a my biking am i driving
you know you'd feed in rules about that
probably something based around the
speed or I'm a very slow runner so it's
detecting something going at
one-and-a-half miles an hour
you know it's detecting me is running
but I know josh is a really fast runner
and you know so would uh it would it
would probably think he's on a bicycle
if you're using my rules those kind of
things you're feeding those data are
feeding those rules in and this is what
we've been doing for years as
programmers but when it comes to machine
learning you got to kind of flip the
axis on this a little bit and change it
to this so when it comes to machine
learning this is all machine learning is
you feed in the answers and your feed in
the data and you get back to the rules
so when you when we talk about training
a model when we talk about like building
these models what we're ending up
getting is this binary blob that you can
run inference on and this binary blob
that your own inference on is
effectively got those rules that will
give them you know that will give what
you need back out to you so for example
in my example of activity detection you
know if I walk a lot and tell it that
I'm walking and it's measuring my sensor
data when I'm walking and if I run a lot
which would be really nice right and if
I run a lot and like feed in the data
and if I bike a lot and drive a lot and
go on trains and go on airplanes you
know these kind of things I'm feeding
all this data and feeding the answers
telling it okay right now I'm walking
right now I'm biking right now I'm on an
airplane then the idea behind machine
learning is it will build that binary
blob for me which I can then run
inference on and by running inference on
that then it's like okay what am i doing
right now and it will deduce what I'm
doing right now from all of these rules
and so instead of me trying to write all
this if then if then if then if then you
know I train a system with data and with
answers and it gives me back rules so
let me give an example of this so what
if we wanted to build something that
would determine from a picture what's a
cat and what's a dog okay now if I was
doing this with if-then rules I could
probably do something like you know if
it loves you unconditionally no matter
what you do it's probably a dog right
and if it's right now plotting your
murder it's probably a
but right now it's really hard to infer
that from images so III couldn't think
of what the if-then rules would be he
like sometimes like you might have an
image say well if it's got pointy ears
it's a cat but guess what this dog has
pointy ears so you know this this is
where we start thinking about this is
where machine learning starts opening up
these new scenarios and these new ways
that you as a programmer can bring value
to your employers and to your business
so let's talk about the answers in this
case okay so the answers here is like
you know this is this is a cat right you
know and this is a I think it's a dog
right okay and this has got really
pointy ears this little guy but this is
clearly a cat this is a walking tongue
but it's also a dog and this one is what
happens if you feed a Mogwai after
midnight I think but this is actually
one of the dogs in this set of cats and
dogs so like you know here you know I've
got the data and here I'm giving the
answers I'm telling the Machine what all
of these things are so now if I want to
do as a programmer all I have to do is
train a neural network by giving it the
answers we call them labels and giving
it the data but as a programmer here's
where it was tough for me and I've only
very recently been on tensorflow because
what is it you know first of all I have
start working in Python any Python
developers here a few of you it's a
lovely language but you tend to work in
a text editor instead of an IDE and
things like step through debugging
because I came from a background of like
Visual Studio and Xcode and
Android studio so it was a big learning
curve for me to get into that and then
with if you started tend to flow with
graph based execution it was very
strange because you'd have all your code
would like load up a graph and then you
would execute that graph and it's like
but what if I've got bugs in like
reading my data or if I'm not reading it
properly or if I haven't shuffled the
data properly and it's really important
as Joshua's mentioning already want to
shuffle your data properly or you can
insert a bias into your actual training
and I'm not a very good programmer so I
generally like to write two or three
lines of code at a time step through
them make sure they work then write
another two or three step through them
make sure they work in that kind of
thing and that was really difficult for
me to do as a tensorflow developer so if
we can switch the laptop I want to show
why I'm really excited about eager mode
and the screen saver kicked in sorry I'm
just signing in so why I'm really
excited about eager mode intensive flow
is I've taken and Josh's written a
notebook with this cats vs. dogs so you
can go and get this code online and run
it in the notebook but right now I'm
running it in PyCharm because like I
said I'm not a very good developer so I
want to write a few lines of code
execute them write another few lines of
code and PyCharm if you're not familiar
with there's a free community edition
which is what I'm running here if you've
used Android studio it probably looks
very very familiar and what I can
actually do is I can go in and I can say
run debug all right and then I'm gonna
go and I'm gonna debug and I'm gonna
debug cats vs. dogs and it's gonna start
executing and look I hit a breakpoint
you know it's like this this to me is
magical as a developer so now when I'm
when I've hit my breakpoint
I can start stepping through my code and
see what's going on in my code so you
know I'm gonna I've hit another
breakpoint I've set another breakpoint
down here so I'm gonna execute my code
down to that breakpoints and now when I
start stepping through this I can start
seeing that I'm doing things correctly
you know like okay my data directory is
set up properly and I've defined my
labels and you know I'm gonna put
another break I'll leave that breakpoint
there and I'll run down to this
breakpoint and I can start looking at
what's going on in here so I have my
training images and if I hover over that
you see it's like it's a little too big
to print but when I look at this in the
debugger I can now start seeing that
look I've started loading up these
arrays of images and I can see the image
0 here sorry if it's a little small but
image 0 here was cat number 921 and so
if I then keep stepping through and this
is what eager execution is giving me
whoops sorry I had a break I hit a
breakpoint I didn't want ahead so I'm
just gonna go down to here and continue
running alright so and if I then step
over this it should show me a cat okay
so like okay I've gotten this cat I'm
loading it in but is this the right cat
you know have I written my code badly I
have I got the wrong cat so I can go hey
look you know here's my training data I
can go look at my cats I can find cat
number 921 and hopefully it's the same
cat so I know my code is working right
you know anybody else develop like this
you like to do it in little steps
oh good it's not just me cuz I find it
really really difficult to write a lot
of code in one sitting so I just got to
do a baby step by baby step and cat
number 921 is here and there it is it's
the same cat so I'm like excellent I
know my code is working I know them I
know I'm loading properly from my data
and I'll go through here and I can see
you know my load image code what it's
doing is it's reading the image it's
creating a tensor out of that image it's
resizing it to like a smaller image that
we're gonna use in training and when you
come from a world where like the hello
world and machine learning is
handwriting recognition you know for me
hello world was s printf hello world you
know that there's there's some very
complicated scenarios it's very complex
scenarios but this breaks it down as a
developer and I can start poking through
I can start looking at data in the IDE
and I can understand really what's going
on so what I'm gonna do is I'm just
gonna exit code and execute my code a
little more and it really have a really
cool point about this too so this load
image function if you look at it it's
using TF operations so we're saying like
tensorflow dot read image and these are
working exactly like they would work if
you were using numpy because we're
running eagerly this code is imperative
and it executes right after you hit the
line also you'll notice when Laurence
which is really cool hovered over it you
can see the data you can see the data
and not it's it's concrete not symbolic
because we're running eagerly so and of
course if you're you know in in Python
you like to use the console as well one
of the nice things in pycharm is that
I've got a console window so if my
existing code is printing out to the
console I can do that I'm just gonna
step a little bit further down and I
want to go just to the training and one
of the nice things that Josh was talking
about is that this is just an iterator
in Python and you know I can now step
through and I can take a look at what's
going on in my training I can look at
this batch by batch so if I've got six
thousands images that I'm loading in
I've split that into smaller batches and
then once I've done all of those batches
that's an epoch so now I can just go
through and I can look at my actual
epochs and I can look at my training and
I can step into it and I can see what's
going on as I said great another quick
point to to show you how fast these
api's are evolving you'll notice that
we're actually getting the numpy value
of the images and the labels yeah as of
I think a few days ago that's no longer
necessary so you can fit Karos models
using TF data
data sets so you no longer need that
intermediate staff which is great but
thank goodness it still works yeah yeah
and one of the really neat things about
it of course is because tensorflow is
open source if you want to know what's
going on with your training maybe
something is going maybe you've loaded
data that's causing it to crash or
something along those lines as you're
doing this and as you're executing these
things let's see if I can do it you know
and I'm gonna hit pause at some points
and I've now jumped into the tensorflow
source code so not only can I step
through my source to see what's going on
I can actually jump into the tensorflow
source so maybe I've done something to
trigger a bug in tensorflow or maybe I'm
doing something wrong and tensorflow
isn't handling it properly and I can fix
it and then contribute back to
tensorflow
so all of this has been made possible by
eager execution in an intensive low at
Python and as Josh mentioned all you got
to do is use sense flow version 1.7 or
later and set up that executing eagerly
can we switch back to the slides now
please yeah so cryptic error messages
are mostly a thing of the past
so your third promise Josh yes thank you
very much thank you I liked PyCharm a
lot I spent a long time in eclipse
before yeah anyway so to learn more
about these concepts so I'm gonna
recommend two educational resources so
first is we have a machine learning
crash course it's pretty good it's short
so this is probably maybe a day or two
days of your time full-time this won't
teach you all there is about ml but it's
a very solid thoughtful introduction to
what is lost what is gradient descent
next I'd like to recommend a book which
is by Googler and I'm gonna badly
mispronounce his name but the author of
chaos Francois Sholay it's a wonderful
wonderful book it's called deep learning
with Python there are many many books
with very similar titles to deep
learning with Python but the one you
want is written by Francois it's
published by Manning and it comes with a
collection of Jupiter notebooks which
are all freely available in github by
the way that will basically teach you
how to use chaos because chaos is part
of tensorflow all of that code will work
with no changes other than the imports
directly in tensorflow
and that will give you a really solid
foundation in chaos and then later if
you're interested you can learn how to
use things like TF data and other
features of tensorflow to do even more
but it's a wonderful starting point so
take away Oh another thing - so I wanted
to also show tensorflow just in this but
we only have 40 minutes with the chaos
model you can literally do model dots
save it's one line of code you'll save
model dot save and like foo dot some
path or whatever food at hd5 now you've
saved your model to disk using
tensorflow j s if you go to j s
tensorflow dat org they have tutorials
that show you how to import relatively
easily that saved chaos model into the
browser and so the same api is
compatible across these platforms so
basically links check out collab
regardless of your using tensorflow or
not collab is a really really valuable
resource it's also wonderful in
educational contexts you know if you're
teaching after work or anything like
that students can just jump right in
check out the workshops in the next
three months or so we're gonna be
updating a lot of our tutorials
intensive loaded org to use chaos but in
the meantime I'm just hacking some
samples together so you can see what
this looks like ten so J s and we have
an education some really fun demos on J
a sense of like there's one where you
can actually train it to recognize your
face going left right up and down and
then you play pac-man by going like this
it's it's really good super cool yep so
take a look and it's open source yeah so
thank you very much everyone I know it's
early we'll be around afterwards for as
long as you want to take questions
really appreciate your time and hope
this stuff is useful to you thank you
[Music]