[Music]
hi everybody and welcome to the
tensorflow developer summit we're right
here in the tensorflow cafe and I'm
chatting with Sandeep who's a product
manager on tensorflow itself and Sandee
thanks for coming Thank You Don and
really really excited to be here are you
enjoying the summit so far oh this has
been incredibly exciting I mean I think
you know to see all the people the users
that we have here we turned out here in
person to listen to their stories what
they're doing see all the cool work see
the interest and and the following of
tensorflow
and not just here in the room but with
all of our you know livestream viewers
and the global viewing parties and all
that it's it's been really really good
to see all this and it's very motivating
it's like this is a product that you're
working on and just the sheer excitement
that's out there about it it's like yeah
maybe the ideas the creativity I think
it's just just amazing where we are in
the field of machine learning as a whole
and the roller tensorflow is playing in
that sometimes I just have to pinch
myself yes yes absolutely yeah so one of
the things we saw in the keynote was
just how quickly tensorflow is growing
and the trajectory that it's not on
there was that what you expected no I
don't think I don't think any of us
expected that or anticipated that right
I think it's mean it's you know the way
machine learning is sort of
transitioning in the society right now
from not just playing a role in research
and sort of very advanced scientific
discovery type of things but beginning
to make a difference in so many
different areas and I'm think we've seen
that in our in our user community right
it's the just the the explosive growth
and the number of people and I think
it's a testament to the this incredibly
powerful platform that our engineering
teams have built which is you know so
flexible and can address these really
really fundamental problems and then our
focus and making it easier to use and
opening up a lot of new applications and
then how the community has also gotten
involved and like just checks so much
stuff in and contributed so much that's
been a big part of it and I think that
is that has really helped with our
partners with our collaborators and how
they have contributed and helped sort of
open up doors to a lot of applications
that we wouldn't have thought about
ourselves so yeah I think it's it's just
it's just a great place to be at the
and some of the scenarios that we've
seen right it's just like it's it's all
inspiring like finding planets yeah yeah
yeah and the cassava story we saw
earlier today right I mean I think just
all these all these applications that
touching upon all aspects of human life
I think it's just that's that's the best
part about this it's a beautiful thing
so you know when we're seeing this
trajectory of growth in like you know
but now just a pivot to the future a
little bit like you know from a
developer perspective it's I find it's
just really beautiful to see new
programming language is it yes yes yeah
and that has been a big sort of focus
for us to make the platform be supported
on in languages and in environments that
that our users are at and so today we
announced support for Swift in fact the
talkback listener is later today and
JavaScript and I'm super excited about
that because you know JavaScript as we
know is the number one language
programming language with a huge web
developer community that's out there
traditionally you know what we have seen
is that machine learning has been sort
of a little bit more in the in the
Python world and so on
I think this opens up the doors for all
of the web developers to try to zoom
just easily incorporate machine learning
into their applications they can use all
kinds of sensors that are very well
connected into the browser world and
develop some really nice interactive
things and we have some amazing demos
here that that users are seen pac-man is
fun I can't wait to get home and try it
and I beat my son with it yes I could
probably go faster like that yeah and
this is all done in JavaScript that's
right exactly so I think what javascript
will allow us to do really is that one
sort of it works in the browser and it's
sort of there's really nothing no
heavy-duty installations or anything
like that it's very quick and to get
something up and running we can take
previously train models and with the
type of converters that we are making a
little available through this library
it's going to be very easy to bring in
models that have been previously trained
another data and then retrain them and
then apply them to your applications and
in addition to that you can also train
in the browser that's yes exactly yes
which is just mind-blowing yes so it is
it is yeah it is a full fledge training
environment and you can build very cool
interactive applications by doing this
yes I remember my very first JavaScript
program was like to put an alert box
when somebody used the right mouse
button yes yes I think we've all written
one of them yeah yeah and now to think
that that language can be used not just
for training but also for inferences
then yes yes yes and the other thing you
can do is I mean there is this deep
learning playground which is available
on the learn with Google site and that's
another way that JavaScript allows you
to sort of visualize these things in a
such an interactive way that I think it
will drive an ability to understand
these models and really sort of iterate
faster and come up with working
solutions so if you don't want to learn
Python and you're already a JavaScript
developer you know just thinking about
it from a career perspective that your
JavaScript skills have taken on a whole
new meaning yes yes yes start so if I am
a JavaScript developer and I want to
take advantage of this yes how what
would you recommend to get started you
mentioned that playground yes yeah yeah
so I think you know there are a lot of
resources available so specifically for
JavaScript what we are launching today
is a new website JSON support and that
website has a very nice getting started
section which has some step-by-step
tutorials that it walks you through and
some quick examples of some curve
fitting and regression and image
classification that you can get up and
running in your browser so that's an
excellent way to start and I think as we
go forward we will sort of continuously
make more and more of these types of
applications that people want to do and
make them available in this in this
platform is pac-man gonna be there
pac-man demo is already there actually
so you can you can clone that and you
can sort of mess around with it maybe
get two people to simultaneously drive
it but you can do some very fun things
I'm thinking of an April Fool's prank
where I train the left arrow to be right
and the up arrow to be down and see if I
can get people to be back yeah that'll
be fun
don't tell anybody it's just everybody
here you're the only ones who know
so thank you so much sandy learn so much
from this as I always do when I chat
with you so really really appreciate it
and enjoy the rest of the summer
Thank You Lawrence Thank You Don so
awesome try to do and thanks everybody
for watching this episode I'm Laurence
Moroney I've had Sandeep Gupta with me
if you have any questions for me or if
you have any questions for Sandeep
please leave them in the comments below
and we'll put links to what we spoke
about in the description for this video
so thank you everybody
[Music]