[Applause]
hi and welcome to coding tensorflow
where you'll learn all about coding
machine learning and AI apps using
tensorflow I'm Laurence Moroney a
developer advocate for tensorflow
and today I'll be looking at tensorflow
Lite and getting it to run models on
Android tensorflow light is tensor flows
lightweight solution for mobile and
embedded devices and lets you run
machine learn models on mobile devices
with low latency quickly so you can take
advantage of them to do classification
regression or anything else you might
want to do without necessarily incurring
a round trip to a server it's presently
supported on Android and iOS via a C++
API as well as a Java wrapper for
Android devices on devices that support
it the interpreter can also use the
Android neural networks API for hardware
acceleration otherwise it will default
to using the CPU here you can see me
running the app on my Android device and
using it to classify a number of objects
it's quite fun to play with and note how
the interpretation of a mouse changes as
I move the camera around or the first
mug has a high handle which kind of
makes it look like a picture so that
shows up as a possibility
finally my Google mug is broad and looks
a bit like a mixing bowl and the app
detects that so how does all of this
work well let's first talk about the
model the app is built using a mobile
net model mobile nets are small low
latency low-power models that are
designed to meet a number of use cases
such as object detection face attributes
fine grained classification and landmark
recognition what's nice about them is
that there are a number of different
ones that are pre-trained including the
model at this link which works for image
classification that is compatible with
tensorflow lite download that file and
you learn zip it to see two files a dot
TF Lite file describing the model and a
labels file describing the labels that
the model is trained for as you can see
because your model is already in the TF
Lite format it's ready to be run on
tensorflow lite so let's take a look at
the api's for that in fact i would
recommend that you stick with
built models for the time being as
tensorflow light is a Developer Preview
it doesn't support all the operations of
tensorflow yet and you might encounter
some issues with unsupported ones when
you're converting your model to the TF
light format okay
let's get down to looking at it on a
mobile now first of all to use
tensorflow light in your android app you
need to include the tensorflow light
libraries you do this by editing your
build up Gradle file to include them
once you've done that in synced you'll
be able to import a tensorflow
interpreter an interpreter loads a model
and allows you to run it by providing it
with a set of inputs tensorflow light
will then execute the model and write
the outputs it's really as simple as
that of course you have to load the
model and the API makes that very
straightforward now a good place to
store your model is in your app assets
the code will then read the model
directly from there it doesn't have to
be there of course you can load a model
from just about anywhere but make sure
you get your powers right once you've
done that you can instantiate an
interpreter and in this case I called it
tensorflow light and loaded the model
into it let's look at the app again now
what's going on here is that it's
reading frames from the camera and
turning those into images it then uses
those images as an input to the model
which in turn outputs values these
values are an index to the appropriate
label and the value for that label the
probability that the image matches that
label will pick the top three and will
write them to the user interface let's
take a look at the code first you can
see is the input we're getting the image
data which is received from the camera
as a bitmap we convert that bitmap into
a byte buffer which the model can read
this buffer is called IMG data remember
that we'll come back to it in a moment
when you downloaded the model you also
had a TF Lite file and a txt file
containing labels these labels are a
list of all of the objects that the
model can recognize here's the first
view so for example labeled zero is
background label two is goldfish and so
on remember the image data from a moment
ago well we'll load
into our tensorflow light interpreter
and we'll get an output called label
proper ray it's probably easiest if we
look at that in the debugger so here you
can see I had a breakpoint on looking at
a picture of my mug as you can see the
top elements unless the goldfish etc
have very very low probability indeed
it's like 1.7 nine times 10 to the minus
5 but when you scroll through the output
lists you'll see for example that label
505 has a relatively high priority and
number 505 corresponds to coffee cup
which as you'll remember from the video
that's what I was looking at if you want
to try an app for yourself that does all
of this you can get it on github at this
link and that's a starter intensive flow
light for Android this exciting
technology will let you load all your
models onto an Android device taking
advantage of onboard hardware and allow
you to execute them I showed an example
using image recognition in a video
stream but of course you're not limited
to that at the moment tensorflow light
is in Developer Preview so you may
encounter some restrictions in
operations that are supported but we're
updating it all the time finally if you
want to learn more including how to
retrain the model I showed in this video
to tailor it for specific scenarios
check out the tensor flow for poet code
labs on the Google developer site I
can't wait to see what you build on
mobile with tensorflow Lite and don't
forget to hit that subscribe button for
more great coding with tensorflow videos
Cheers
don't forget to click the subscribe
button for more great videos like these
what's