[Applause]
hi and welcome to coding tensorflow
where you'll learn all about coding
machine learning and AI apps using
tensorflow I'm Laurence Moroney a
developer advocate for tensorflow
and today I'll be looking at tensorflow
Lite and getting it to run models on iOS
tensorflow Lite is a lightweight
solution for mobile and embedded devices
and lets you run machine learn models on
mobile devices with low latency quickly
so you can take advantage of them to do
classification regression or anything
else you might want without necessarily
incurring a round trip to a server it's
presently supported on both Android and
iOS via a C++ API and today we're going
to take a look at an iOS app that uses
this API in Xcode here you can see me
playing with an app on my iPad and I'm
using it to classify a number of objects
it's a lot of fun to play with and note
how the interpretation of objects
changes as I move the camera around it
thinks my phone is an iPod for example
it does a great job at detecting a mug
but it thinks my SmartWatch is a digital
watch well why is that
well that's because this network is
trained on a limited number of items it
will see any phone as an iPod and any
watch as a digital watch the nice thing
about it though is that nets like this
can be retrained but for now let's just
stick with this one so how does all of
this work first let's talk about the
model the app is using a mobile net
model and mobile nets are small low
latency low-power models that are
designed to meet a number of use cases
such as object detection face attributes
fine grain classification and landmark
recognition what's nice about them is
that there are a number of different
ones that are pre-trained including the
set at this link which works for image
classification and it's compatible with
tensorflow lite download that file and
you'll unzip it to see two files a docx
TF Lite file describing the model and a
labels file describing the labels that
it's trained for as you can see because
your model is already in the dot TF Lite
format it's ready to be run on
tensorflow lite so let's take a look at
the API is for that in fact though I
would recommend that you stick with
these pre-built models for the
time being as TF fly is a Developer
Preview it doesn't support all the
operations of tensorflow yet and you
might encounter some issues with
unsupported ones when you're converting
your model to the TF light format okay
let's get down to looking at it on an
iOS mobile now before you can code the
app you'll need the universal iOS
library for tensorflow light you can
build this yourself thankfully from open
source and if you don't have Xcode
already you'll need to go ahead and get
it from the App Store you'll also have
to install and run Xcode for the first
time you need to do this to agree to the
license before you can use any of the
Xcode tools including the command-line
tools go ahead and get that done I'll
wait
okay you'll also need to install
homebrew which you can get at the URL
brooder sh this is a pretty neat package
manager' and you're going to use that to
install auto make and Lib tool and when
they're done there's a script intensive
flow that you can run which does all the
building it's going to take a little
while so sit back and have a coffee
while you're waiting once you're done
you can go to the examples iOS camera
directory to find the source code for
the sample app that I showed a moment
ago don't forget to run pod install in
that directory before you continue once
you're done you can now load the code
into Xcode and you can run it do note
that you will need an iOS device to run
it on it doesn't yet work in the
simulator in Xcode if you open the
project navigator you'll see a data
folder this contains a TF flight file
containing the model and its hex file
containing the labels it probably has
the quantized version of the model as
you can see from the quant in the file
name you can replace these with the
model and labels that you downloaded
earlier or if you like just keep them
the way that they are open the camera
example viewcontroller mm file and
you'll see some constants at the top of
the file which specify the name of the
model and labels to load if you've
changed it you'll need to update these
to use TF flight you'll need an
interpreter and this can be loaded from
the API as an interpreter object to this
you'll input details of the captured
frame and it will output a set of
probabilities whether or not it sees
something that matches each of the
possible labels let's take a look at the
app again and here you can see I'm
looking at a mug but it's giving me back
a couple of labels once for a mug and
once for a cup well what's actually
happening here the app is capturing
frames from the camera and feeding them
one by one into the interpreter the
model that's loaded is a 224 by 224 one
so the images will first get resized to
that with this code the interpreter then
outputs a tensor containing all of the
results and this will be an index of all
of the labels with an Associated
probability the get top n function is a
helper function which pulls out the top
few of these I put a breakpoint
there to show what happens with the
output here you can see that the top
value when I pointed the camera at the
coffee mug was the interpreter gave me
back is 74 percent probability that it
was the object at label 505 and if you
look at the list of labels you'll see
that the five or fifth one is a coffee
mug it shows us five or six because when
Xcode prints out the list it starts at
one but the in memory one starts at zero
it's still a coffee mug so that's a
starter in tensorflow light for iOS this
exciting technology will let you load
your models onto a device taking
advantage of onboard hardware and allow
you to execute them I showed an example
using image recognition in a video
stream but of course you're not limited
to that at the moment tensorflow light
is in Developer Preview so remember you
may encounter some restrictions using
the tensorflow api's that are not
supported but we are updating them all
the time finally if you want to learn
more including how to retrain the model
I showed in this video to tailor it for
specific scenarios check out the
tensorflow for poet's code labs on the
google developer site I can't wait to
see what you build on mobile with TF
Lite and don't forget to hit that
subscribe button for more great coding
with tensorflow videos don't forget to
click the subscribe button for more
great videos like these what's