[Music]
[Applause]
hi and welcome to coding tensorflow
a show where we focus on coding machine
learning and AI applications I'm
Laurence Moroney a developer advocate
for tensorflow
and in this episode were going to look
at using JavaScript for machine learning
in the browser in the previous episode
we looked at creating a very basic
machine learning scenario in the browser
you took data that had a linear
relationship and built a basic model
that could predict future values based
on that relationship it might have
looked a little strange in how you fed
the data into the model when you were
training it with one tensor of the
x-values and another for the y-values
that's because one of the core concepts
that you need to learn as a tensorflow
developer is all about that how to shape
your data and how to get it ready for
training this process is a major part of
data science and today we'll look at a
more complex program and how you can get
your data ready for training a machine
learn model with it so instead of a
simple linear arrangement which you
don't really need machine learning for
let's consider a classification problem
and this is when there are multiple
items of data about a thing and then
there's something about how they're
related that determines the
classification of that thing so for
example an email might be a spam if it's
from a particular sender or it contains
particular keywords or pictures an
animal might be a doggie if it has four
paws and a cute wet nose now it's very
difficult to program traditional if-then
type code for these scenarios and this
is why machine learning can be such a
powerful tool so let's take a look at
some public data and we'll use that to
build a classification system we're
going to use the well-known iris dataset
which collects data points from a
hundred and fifty different samples of
flower taking petal length and width as
well as sepal length and width these
measurements are then associated with
one of three types of iris by training a
neural network with these measurements
telling it the values and then the
classes of flower the chorus
to those values you could then build a
neural network that can infer from a new
measurement what type of flower they
represent so let's take a look at the
data and here it is and you might
typically get data like this as a bunch
of comma separated values as you can see
each entry has five values the four
measurements that I mentioned earlier
and then a value zero one or two in the
final column indicating the category of
flower that the data represents consider
the first four values to be your X's and
the last one is your Y thus given a set
of four X's you'd want to predict or
classify the Y so now that you have the
data you can use it to train a model to
do that you'll use tensors for the
training X's and tensors for the
training wise in addition to that you
can use some of your data to test your
model so what you should do is you take
your percentage of your data for
training the model and then with the
remainder compare the predicted value
with their actual value and from there
you can determine how well your model is
behaving so let's take a look at the
code that we use to prepare this data
for training first of all we'll split
the data into different arrays for each
of the classes this for loop iterates
through the iris classes length and it
creates two arrays one for the data of
that class and one for the values for
that class if you then look at the data
you'll see that there are three classes
so we'll have three of each array the
data by class will contain the four
measurements and the targets by class
will contain zero one or two based on
the flower type once we've created these
arrays we can now iterate through the
data and sort the values into the array
based on the target so the data for
class 0 will get loaded into data by
class 0 and the targets for class 0
likewise etc etc if I now log these
arrays to the console I can view them in
my developer tools
the next step will be to convert these
values into tensors with four sets of
tensors an X for training annex for test
a Y for training and a y4 test we do
this according to the test split which
is a parameter that we pass into the
function in this demo I said it's a
point two so that 80% of my data is used
for training and 20% for testing the
workhorse here is the convert to tensors
function this takes the data the targets
and the split and loads all this value
into tensors splitting them into
training and test sets respectively
let's take a look at that next
here is the convert to tensors function
it calculates the number of test
examples by rounding the sample size by
the split and the number of training
examples will just be the remainder it
then creates a two dimensional tensor of
the data as you can see here and a one
heart encoding of the label data now one
heart encoding is a way of helping a
machine understand how your data is
being classified so instead of the
flowers being 0 1 or 2 what happens is
you get an encoded array where instead
of a flower for 0 you would get 1 0 0 in
that array instead of 1 you get a 0 1 0
etc etc the idea is this that that this
array will just map to your output
neurons once you've done that the data
will be sliced into the four arrays
based on the size determined by the test
split the last step is just having a
nice clean linear set of tensors to feed
into the training instead of the 2d one
that you have right now
this is achieved using TF concat along
axis 0 let's take a look at the code for
this and here's the code you can see I
set the concat access to be 0 and then
I'll return my set of 4 tensors where
i'm concatenating them into a one
dimensional tensor as an example if i
log the x trains against the
concatenated x trains you'll see the
difference this has the
reducing the overall complexity of the
data being fed into the model it doesn't
have to try and figure out multiple
dimensions and this makes training
quicker and more accurate
congratulations you've now taken raw
data and you've learned how to
pre-process it into tensors that make
for efficient training including how to
one heart encode the output data this is
a massive part of designing any machine
learning system getting your data right
in the next video we'll train a neural
network with this data and we'll see how
you can design that network and then how
you can do classification given the
terrain model you can find that right
here on the tensorflow youtube channel
so don't forget to hit that subscribe
button right now
[Music]
[Applause]
you