everybody and welcome to the tensorflow
developer summit and welcome to the
tents of hope cafe at this summit I'm
Laurence Moroney and it's my honor to
chat with Jeff Dean and the keynote has
just finished Jeff Gray keynote thank
you thank you I really love the part
where you were talking about like you
know looking at changing the future
using tensorflow and some of the great
stuff that we're doing so could you tell
me a little bit more about it sure I
mean I think over the last four or five
years we've really seen tremendous
developments in a lot of sort of core
areas of machine learning research being
turned from sort of research ideas into
things that are actually practical
things that you can use to solve
problems across a really wide set of
domains right and I think that's part of
the excitement is we know that things
like computer vision that works well
speech recognition you know
understanding language and sequences all
these things can be applied in so many
different areas of the world it's just
amazing and you know in the keynote I
sort of highlighted things through the
lens of the National Academy of
Engineering in the United States they
put out a list of these 14 grand
engineering challenges I talked about 14
of yeah so you highlighted two of them
right yeah yeah
one was engineering the tools of
scientific discovery and I think
actually tensorflow itself is a kind of
a key part of that because machine
learning is very clearly impacting many
different scientific domains and
engineering domains today and so for
example our group has done some research
on how to use machine learning to tackle
quantum chemistry problems right and
like that's not immediately an obvious
fit in most people's minds but you can
actually train a machine learning model
that emulates the behavior of a very
expensive more traditional HPC style
quantum chemistry simulator and you get
essentially the same accuracy but it's
three hundred thousand times faster and
so that just wood is a fundamentally
different kind of tool for chemists
right if you have something that's three
hundred thousand done faster you know
you can imagine screening a hundred
million candidate molecule
configurations and finding the ten
thousand that are most interesting
whereas you couldn't do that before and
it also means that more
research opportunities can open up right
because your 300 times 300 thousand
times faster means that there's more
bandwidth to try different things
different experiments that's right and
like all of the 14 challenges sort of
four of them were related to things that
I think better understanding of chemical
properties of and materials were going
to be pretty important in things like
you know making solar energy more
affordable or things like that and so
machine learning clearly can tackle
those things but engineering the tools
of scientists scientific discovery is a
pretty broad area and one of the things
I talked about was being able to
automate solving of new problems with
machine learning I think one of the
problems in the world is there so much
potential for applying machine learning
to different problems but there's a
fairly limited set of people that have
the skills and expertise to really do
that effectively I'm by democratizing
that you're broadening that base of
people that's right you can happen in
one of the other things he spoke about
which was close to my heart was really
health care and you spoke about like the
diabetic retinopathy retinopathy yes I
could never say the word like it's just
amazing like how they did scale of a
machine learn system can approach that
and even surpass that of many humans now
right I mean I think the realization and
an advances in computer vision you know
mean that the same pretty much the same
technology that is powering labeling
your google photos with like is that a
picture of a mountain or a Labrador it
can be applied to medical imaging
problems and our group has been doing a
lot of work in many different sort of
domains and medical imaging
ophthalmology pathology radiology
dermatology kinds of problems we're sort
of farthest along and started the
earliest on ophthalmology problems
because it's a very unmet need around
the world they're just in many parts of
the world they just aren't enough
opthamologist to screen people for this
disease diabetic retinopathy and it's a
very serious and degenerative eye
disease so you can actually lose your
vision if it's not diagnosed in time but
if you catch it in time then it's very
treatable
yeah and it's a beautiful symmetry that
computer vision is helping real vision
that's right
I only thought of it when you said
computer visionary and then I mean the
one thing that we showed in the keynote
that was really inspiring was their
cassava and the example of cassava and
using like mobile phones that diagnosed
and leave right the if it and I know you
grew up we spent some of your childhood
in Africa yeah I actually moved around
quite a bit as a kid and one of the
places that I lived was in East Africa
in northwestern Uganda for a year when I
was five I also spent six months in
Somalia when I was 13 but in Uganda in
that particular area cassava is sort of
one of the fundamental crops that's
grown to sort of provide most of the
basic nutrition for for meals and you
know when I was five we were living in
this very rural small village of like
thousand people so it's a very agrarian
kind of kind of area I used to love to
go out in the fields and kind of help
pull up cassava and things and so
actually when I saw this this video of a
group at Penn State and at the ìiî TA
Institute in Tanzania that it done some
work on diagnosis of disease versus not
disease cassava leaves essentially do
you take pictures of leaves and then you
can tell you know is this a healthy
plant or is a disease and if it's
diseased you know what you should do to
treat it and and that's like a very
useful and and fundamental thing that
you can do and it relies on machine
learning and computer vision and sort of
an app crafted so that farmers can do
this but it's almost the stuff of sci-fi
right that you if you told me five years
ago that you could go out with a mobile
phone and start looking at leaves and
then diagnose if their disease they're
not it would be it'd be hard to believe
but now it's possible and now it's
happening there's so many potential
applications of this and you know
another one of my favorites is the
Google Translate app which has the
ability to like you turn on the camera
on your phone and you hover over text in
another language and it superimposes
translated text oh yes and so that
relies on many different kinds of
machine learning in there there's like
the computer vision to do the OCR to
recognize the text and then there's
another machine learning model to
actually do the translation from one
language to another and then another
model to figure out how to superimpose
the text
back in the font that you were actually
seeing it in in the original vertical
and hovered over and it's just like very
cool how you know these magical
experiences can be crafted from you know
a few core machine learning models
stitched together in the right way and
it also makes the world a smaller place
right so I mean I spend a lot of time
traveling and like exactly that
translation thing that it saved me from
embarrassing myself by ordering
something I don't like
especially in languages where the script
is even very different than the script
her familiar with I think that's you
know you just feel very lost and this
can make you feel lots long yeah it's
amazing stuff and I think we're only
just getting started right absolutely so
thank you so much Jeff that's been a
real pleasure thank you very much
pleasure chatting minute and thanks
everybody for watching if you have any
questions for me or if you have any
questions for Jeff just please leave
them in the comments below and don't
forget to hit that subscribe button
thank you
[Music]
you