tensorflow tensorflow a name you should
eat hopefully you got that one for the
outtakes right welcome to ask tensorflow
this is the show where we answer your
questions about tensorflow my name is
Laurence Moroney I'm a developer
advocate on tensorflow and with me I
have Magnus it's them I'm also a
developer advocate on tensor film we've
got lots of great questions coming in
from the community so should we just get
straight to them yeah sounds good okay
so the first question is from user three
seven eight nine zero two zero zero and
stack overflow I'd love to have to get a
username like that and the question is
when I try to run tensorflow on Windows
using a GPU it fails with being unable
to load some certain dll's and I have
those dll's installed and I have
tensorflow install and I've checked what
can I do well there's a number of
reasons for this and it's a common thing
in Windows development like DLL
mismatches but I found the most common
DLL mismatch that's really easy to
overlook is that when you go to the
Nvidia site to download the drivers for
your GPU the CUDA and the CU DNN drivers
their website as it should will always
default to giving you the most recent
version of the drivers but tensorflow
actually needs a specific exact version
and if the most recent version one has
passed down from the tensorflow one then
you're gonna get that dll mismatch so
for example when I was setting up my own
windows development box I installed the
latest Nvidia drivers which at that time
were for cuda 9.1 and because they were
the latest I thought I was okay whenever
I tried to run tensorflow and I was
getting DLL errors it took me a little
while digging into them to realize that
the missing dll was CUDA or T underscore
90 DLL but when I looked really closely
I had version 91 or nine one of DLL and
as a result tensorflow was getting a
little bit confused so when I went back
to the Nvidia site and I looked in there
like historic downloads there archive
downloads I found version 9.0 I
uninstalled 91 I installed nine zero and
intensive flow worked perfectly well so
I did blog about this experience because
it was something that you know I've seen
a lot of developers having a little bit
of trouble with and I've put a link to
their blog post in the in the comments
below and complete with beautiful
screenshots sounds good so CUDA problems
are very common yeah definitely so just
make sure that you have the
the matching DLL so should we take a
look at the next question yeah so when I
try to run a tenth of a web I get
overloaded with debug messages how do I
turn them off and this was asked by
d-las on Stack Overflow so that's a
great question sometimes you can just
see them flying flying so it is a great
question dealers well debug messages are
great because they help us understand
what's going on in our code they can
also be a bit cumbersome and it's hard
to find our specific error message
because of this so fortunately there is
an easy enough way to turn them off
there is an environment variable called
TF underscore cpp underscore main
underscore log on the school level and
you can tell it's an environment
variable with all the underscores and
the caps right yes so this is the way
you use it so you essentially set OS dot
environ you set this environment
variable to a specific log level and the
default log level that we have in the
system is zero which essentially means
show everything there if you put one
there instead it will filter out in four
messages to you will filter out warning
messages and three will also filter out
all the error messages so if you set it
to three as shown in this example you'll
see very little output and then the nice
thing is your own debug messages that
you've inserted into your own code they
won't be lost in all the noise no okay
so great question yeah we move on to the
next absolutely and the next one is one
of my favorites and it's from Fidelma in
ireland and she asks I would like to use
tensorflow but I don't know Python do
you have any other languages and how
about Java
well Fidelma thanks for the question and
well we do have stuff in Java which can
be found in their models tree master
samples languages Java directory it does
not have feature parity with the Python
api's and it's more suited for inference
from pre-trained models so I definitely
recommend that Fidelma sticks with
Python for the time being but we are
working on more write madness including
like some cool stuff in JavaScript that
would be talking about soon Python as
well if you want to use it is perfectly
suited for complex mathematical models
and they've got tons of supporting
libraries for that as well and not to
mention is really super easy to learn so
I recommend that you give it a try if
you haven't done so already but you know
on the team we'd also really love to get
feedback on the languages that people
love
Yeah right there whatever it is that
you're programming in and you'd like to
see supported intensive folk going
forward you know please let us know and
like leave a little note in the comments
below right yeah so we take a look at
the next question yeah let's do that so
the next question is asked by LX in
Seattle and the question is what is the
difference between tensorflow mobile and
tensile light well as you may know
tensor field already supports mobile and
embedded development of models using the
tensor for mobile API but going forward
tensorflow light should really be seen
as the evolution of tensorflow mobile
and as it matures it will become the
recommended solution for deploying
models on mobile and embedded devices
with this announcement TFI tensorflow
light is made available as a developer
preview and tensorflow mobile will still
be out there to support production apps
the scope of tensorflow Lite is quite
large though it's huge and it's still
under active development so the
Developer Preview is a constrained
platform to ensure maximum performance
or some of the most important common
models you mean things like Inception
and stuff like that is correct and
mobile net the all the different
resolution variants of mobile net core
but the goal for continued development
or should poor to simplify the developer
experience and enable model deployment
for a wide range of mobile and embedded
device it's nice it's really exciting
that developers are getting their hands
intensive for life and it's gonna be
great to see what everyone out there can
do with it and so that end we've
actually produced a number of episodes
of coding tensorflow on this very
channel all around tensorflow lights so
there's three in the series one is
introducing tensorflow light how it
works and what you can do with it One is
using tensorflow light on Android and
the other one is using tensorflow light
on iOS so go check him out I think we've
time for one more question what do you
think now yes Lauren this one's a beauty
it's from David McLain on Twitter and
David has asked is there a version of
tensorflow for Chrome OS so David I
assume you're using a Chromebook and you
want to start developing on tensorflow
now instead of like hacking your
Chromebook to put Linux on it and
install tensorflow there's a couple of
other good options that you should think
about one of them is there's something
called Cola but I've put a link to it
below where a collab is basically a
Jupiter notebook in the cloud and it
supports tensorflow so you can start on
your Chromebook in your browser
writing and testing training some stuff
intensive flow it's actually really
really cool but if you want to double
click a level beneath that you can also
create a VM on GCE right and using the
Google cloud platform and in that VM you
can install Linux and you can install
tensorflow and you can start programming
tensorflow right away and you can shell
into that from your Chromebook and also
when you're doing it this way you can
take advantage of some of the great
hardware that's in the cloud - like GPUs
and TP use for accelerated your learning
I hope that really helps and I think
there was another option right there is
one more option or if you're a Kangol
user you know the platform that allows
you to test machine learning and data
science problems on different data sets
you should really try out kaggle kernels
that is essentially a notebook that has
lots of packages installed and you can
write all your tensorflow code in there
and try it out
Kaggle kernels cago kernels like the
sound of that you can see the link below
here so thanks David and that was a
great question so that's it for this
episode of Oz tensorflow so some great
questions thanks everybody
and remember if you want us to take a
look at your questions and have them
featured in a future show be sure to
post on social media and use the
ostensive flow hashtag and we'll look
forward to seeing them thanks everybody
[Music]
you