hi everyone thanks for coming today to
see our talk my name is Daniel my name
is Nikhil and I'm Nick and today we're
very happy to talk about JavaScript all
right so if you're in the world of
machine learning if you're doing
training a model or anything about
machine learning you're most certainly
dealing with Python right and for a good
reason
Python has been one of the mainstream
languages for scientific computing for
the last decade it has a lot of tools
but it doesn't have to be that way it
doesn't have to end there today we're
here to convince you that the browser
and JavaScript have a lot to offer to
the world of machine learning and pencil
flow playground is a great example of
that how many people here have seen this
visualization quite a few I'm glad for
those of you that haven't seen it
tensorflow playground is in browser
neural network visualization shows you
what is happening inside the neural
network as the network is training and
when we release this this was kind of a
fun small project when we released this
it had a tremendous success especially
in the educational domain and even today
we're getting emails from high schools
and universities around the world
thanking us for building this and
they're using it to teach students
beginners about machine learning when we
saw the success of tensorflow playground
we started wondering why is it so
successful and we think the browser and
JavaScript have a lot to do with it for
one thing that's very special about the
browser it has no drivers and no
installations you can share your app
with anyone and all they have to do is
click on a link and see your application
another important thing about the
browser is highly interactive in the
playground app you we have all these
controls
drop down controls that you can change
and quickly run different experiments
another nice thing about the browser
it runs on laptops it runs on mobile
devices and these devices have sensors
like the microphone and the camera and
the accelerometer and they're all behind
standardized web api's that you can
easily access in your web app we didn't
take advantage of this in the playground
but we'll show you some demos later and
most importantly when you're building
web apps these apps run client-side
which makes it easy to have the data
stay on the client and never have to
send it back to a server you can do
processing on device and this is
important for privacy now to come back
to the playground example the library
that powers this visualization is not
tensorflow it is a small neural network
library 300 lines of JavaScript code we
wrote we wrote for this visualization
and it wasn't meant to be reusable or to
scale for bigger neural networks but it
became clear to us when this became so
successful and popular that we should go
on and build such a library and we went
and built deep learn j/s we released it
August 2017 we figured out a way how to
make it fast and scale by utilizing the
GPU of laptops and cell phones through
WebGL for those of you that are not
familiar WebGL is a technology
originally meant for rendering 3d
graphics and the library that we built
allows for both inference and training
entirely in the browser when we release
deep lunges we had an incredible
momentum the community went instantly
with it and took pre-trained models from
Python and ported it in the browser one
example I want to show you of that is
the style transfer demo someone went and
took the pre trained model and this demo
has an image a source image on the left
as artists on the right and then it can
mash them together and they made this in
a crea
interesting application another demo is
people would take models that read a lot
of text and then they could generate new
sentences and then they ported it in the
browser and explored novel interfaces
how you can explore all the different
endings of a sentence in the educational
domain people took the standard
convolutional neural nets and built this
fun little game where you can train your
own image recognition model just by
using the webcam and this was very
popular and lastly researchers took
another example they took a phone
generation model that can generate new
fonts previously it was trained in a lot
of font styles and then they build this
novel interface in the browser highly
interactive where you can explore
different types of fonts now building on
that incredible momentum we had with
deep lunges
about a month ago at the tensorflow dev
summit we announced that we're joining
the tensorflow family and with that we
introduced a new ecosystem of tools and
libraries around javascript and machine
learning called tensorflow jeaious now
before we dive into the details I want
to go over three main use cases of what
you can do with tensorflow j/s today you
can write models directly in the browser
we have sets of api's for that you can
also take pre trained models that were
trained in Python or other languages and
then port them for inference in the
browser you can also take these existing
pre-trained models and retrain them do
transfer learning right there on device
to give you a schematic view of the
library we have the browser that does
all the computation using WebGL
tensorflow jeaious has two sets of api's
that sit on top of this a core api which
is a which gives you low-level building
blocks linear linear algebra operations
like multiply and add and on top of it
we have layers api which gives you
high-level building blocks and best
practices to build neural nets and on
top of that because there's so many
models written in Python today we
our tools to take an existing model a
Karass model and attends a floor safe
model these are two formats that are
very popular server-side and these tools
will automatically convert that model to
run in the browser now to give you an
example of our core API I'm gonna show
you how we're gonna go over a code that
tries to train a model that fits a
polynomial curve and we have to learn
the three coefficients a B and C now
this example is pretty simple but the
code walks you through all the steps of
how you would train such a model and
these steps generalize across different
models so we import tensorflow for tens
of flow / tens of flow j s for those of
you that are not familiar this is in
standard es6 modern javascript import we
have our three variables that we're
trying to learn a b and c we mark them
as variables which means that the
optimizer the machine the machinery that
runs and trains our neural network can
change these variables for us we have
our function f of X given some data it
will compute the output this is just a
polynomial function quadratic function
on top of the standard API like TF
identity of multiply we also have a
chaining API chaining has been very
popular in the JavaScript world so you
can call these methods these
mathematical methods on the tensor
itself and this reads better closer to
how we write math so that's our model to
train it
we need a loss function and in this case
we are just measuring the distance
between the prediction of the model and
the label the ground truth data we need
an optimizer this is the machinery that
can optimize and find those coefficients
we specify a learning rate there and for
some number of epochs passes over our
data we call optimizer that minimize
with our loss and our f of X and Y's so
that's our model now this is clearly not
how everyone writes machine learning
models today
over the years we've developed best
practices in high-level building blocks
and new api submerged like TF layers and
caris that makes mod much easier to
write these models and for that I want
to walk over our layers API to show you
how easy it is we're going to go through
a simple neural network that sums to
numbers but what's special about this
network is that the input comes as a
string character by character so ninety
plus ten is the input to this network
being fed as a string and the network
has an internal memory where it encodes
this information it has to save it and
then on the other end the neural network
has to output the sum 1 0 0 again
character by character now you might
wonder why go through such a trouble to
train this neural network like this but
this example forms the basis of modern
machine translation and that's why we're
going over this to show you the code we
import tensorflow from desert flow Jas
we have our model we say TF dot
sequential which means it's just a
linear stack of layers the first two
layers I'm not going to go into details
but those two are building blocks that
can take these strings into a memory
into an internal representation and the
last three layers take this internal
representation and turn it into numbers
and that's our model to Train it we need
to compile it with a loss and optimizer
and a metric we want to monitor in this
case accuracy and we call model that fit
with our data now one thing I want to
point out about model dot fit training
can take for this example it can take 30
or 40 seconds in the browser and while
that's running we don't want to block
the main UI thread we want our app to be
responsive this is why model dot fit is
an asynchronous call and we get a
callback once it's done with the history
object which has our accuracy as it
evolved over time now I went through
examples of how you write these models
in the browser but there is also a lot
of
models that have already been written in
Python and for that we have tools that
allow you to import them automatically
before we dive into the details I want
to go through show you a fun little game
that our friends at Google brand studio
built called image called emoji
scavenger hunt and this game takes
advantage of a pre trained model a
convolutional neural network that can
detect 400 items and I'm gonna walk over
to a pixel phone and open up a browser
just to show you that test flow J's can
also run in a browser because we're
using standard WebGL and I'm gonna ask
here any kill on my right to help me out
here because I'm gonna need some help
now to give you some little details
about the game it shows you an emoji and
then you have to go with your camera run
around your house and find the real
version item of that emoji before the
time runs out and there is a neural
network that has to detect that all
right shall we start all right let me
see we're gonna play it here live all
right we have to find a watch 20 seconds
all right that's great
whoo all right let me see what's the
next alright we need a shoe come on Phil
do things buddy
yay let's see what our next item is
banana we have 30 seconds to find a
banana does anyone have a banana anyone
have a banana
Oh awesome we got a banana over here
fingers man there we go all right
awesome all right so we're our high
scores going up let's see what our next
item is beer
beard Daniels 12:30 in the middle of Io
let's get back to the talk man alright
man alright so let's talk a little bit
about how we actually built that game
switch back to the slides here okay so
what we did was we trained a model in
Python to predict from images 400
different classes that would be good for
an emoji scavenger hunt game these are
things like a banana a watch and a shoe
the way we did this was we took a pre
trained model called mobile net and now
if you don't know what mobile net is
it's a state-of-the-art computer vision
model that's designed for edge devices
it's designed for mobile phones so we
did is we took that model and we reuse
the features that I would learned there
and we did a transfer learning task to
our 400 class classifier so then once we
do that we have an object detector so
this object detector lives entirely in
the Python world so the next step of
this process is to actually take that
and convert it into a format that we'll
be able to ingest in the web and then
we'll skin the game and add sound
effects and that kind of thing so let's
talk a little bit about the details of
actually going through that process so
in Python when we're actually
checkpointing and training our model we
have to save it to disk so there's a
couple ways you do this the common way
with tensorflow is to use what's called
a saved model details are not important
for this talk here but the idea here is
that there are files on disk that you
need to write daniel also mentioned that
we support importing from Charis now
caris is a high-level library that lives
on top of tensorflow
that gives you a sort of higher level
API to use these things details
unimportant there are also files on disk
that it uses to checkpoint all right so
we have a set of files and now the next
step is to actually convert them to a
format that we can ingest in a in a web
page so we have released a tool on pip
called tensorflow J's inside of that
tool we have
some converging scripts all you do is
run the script you point it to those
saved files that you had on disk and you
point it to an output directory and you
will get a set of static build artifacts
that we'll be able to use on the web the
same flow holds for Karis models you
point to your input h5 file and out pops
a directory of static build artifacts
alright so you take those static build
artifacts and you host them on your
website this is the same way you would
host pngs or CSS or anything of that
sort alright so once you do that we
provide some api's in tensorflow j/s to
load those static build artifacts so it
looks something like this for tensorflow
save model we load the model up and we
get a model object back that model
object can actually make predictions
with tensorflow JS tensors right in the
browser the same flow holds for Karis
models we point to those static build
artifacts and we have a model that we
can make predictions on ok so under the
covers
there's actually a lot going on when we
convert these files to a format that we
can ingest in the web we actually are
pruning nodes off of that graph that
aren't needed to make that prediction
this makes the network transfer much
smaller and our predictions much faster
we're also taking those weights and
sharding and packing them into 4
megabytes this means that the next time
the browser loads that page your waste
will be cached so it's super snappy we
also support about 90 of the most
commonly used tensorflow ops today and
we're working hard to continue
supporting more and on the Kara side we
support 32 of the most commonly used
Kara Slater's during that importing
phase and we also support training and
evaluation of those models so computing
accuracy once you get them in of course
you can also make predictions as well
all right so I want to show you a demo
before I bore you any more this demo is
built by our friends at Creative Lab as
a collaboration between them and a few
researchers on Google
so I'm gonna go back over here to this
laptop okay so the idea of this model is
it takes a 2d image of a human being and
it estimates a set of key points that
relate to their skeleton so things like
your wrists point the Centers of your
eyes your shoulders and that kind of
thing so I'm just gonna turn the demo on
here so when I do that the webcam will
turn on and it's gonna start predicting
some key points for me and I'm gonna
step back here so you can actually see
the full thing and as I move around
you'll see you know the skeleton change
and make some predictions about me all
right so there's obviously a lot you can
do with this we're really excited to
show you a fun little demo it's very
it's very thin and what's gonna happen
is when I click this slider we're gonna
move to a separate mode where it's going
to look for another image on the
internet that has a person with the same
pose as me okay let's turn that on is it
gonna work here
of course it's not working now okay well
we have a physical installation of this
which you can go check out it's at the
experiments tent at Allen H and it's
really fun it's a full full-screen
version of that where you can see
another version of you we have released
this model on NPM so you can go and use
this and you need no machine learning
experience to do it the API lets you
point to an image and out pops an array
of key points it's that easy so we're
really excited to see what you do with
that okay so there's a lot you can do
with just porting the models to the
browser for inference but since the
beginning of deep learning is and
tensorflow jess we've made it a high
priority to be able to actually train
directly in the browser this opens up
the door for education in interactivity
as well as retraining with data that
never leaves the client so I'm gonna
actually show you another demo of that
back on the laptop over here okay Daniel
you want to come help me here we go cool
okay so the game is in three phases in
phase one we're going to actually
collect frames from the webcam and we're
gonna we're gonna do is we're gonna use
those frames to actually play a game of
pac-man okay so Daniel once you start
collecting frames what he's going to do
is he's going to collect frames for up
down left and right and those are going
to be associated with the poses of with
the four controls for the pac-man game
itself so as he's collecting those were
saving some of the images locally and
were naturally training them all yet so
once he's done actually collecting those
frames we're going to train the model
and again this is going to be trained
entirely in the browser with no requests
to a server anywhere okay so when we
actually train that model what's gonna
happen is we're actually going to take a
pre trained mobile net model that's
actually in the page right now and we're
going to do a little retraining phase
with data that he has just collected
so why don't you press that train model
awesome our loss value is actually going
down it looks like we've learned
something okay so the phase three of
this game is to actually play so when he
presses that button what's gonna happen
is we're gonna take frames from that
webcam and we're gonna make predictions
given that model that we just trained
why don't you press that play button and
we'll see how it goes so if you look in
the bottom right of the screen you'll
actually see the predictions happening
so it's it's highlighting the the
control that it thinks it is and you'll
see him actually playing the pac-man
game now so obviously this is just a
game
but we're really excited about
opportunities for accessibility you can
imagine a Chrome extension that lets you
train a model that lets you scroll the
page and click now all of this code is
online and available for you to go and
fork and build your own applications
with and we're really excited to see
what you do with it all right men we
gotta go back to the talk all right
okay so let's chat a little bit about
performance what we're looking at here
is a benchmark of mobile net 1.0 running
with tensorflow Python
this is classic tensorflow not running
what tensorflow jazz we're thinking
about this in the context of a batch
size of one and the reason that we want
to think like that is because we're
thinking of an interactive application
like pac-man where you can only read one
sensor frame at a time so you can't
really batch that data on the first row
we're looking at tensorflow
running with cuda on a 1080 GTX this is
a beefy machine and it's getting about
three milliseconds per frame and I want
to mention that the smaller the bar the
faster it is in the second row we're
looking at tensorflow CPU running with
avx2 instructions on one of these
MacBook Pros here we're getting about 60
milliseconds for a frame there all right
where does tensorflow jess fit into this
Victor well it depends so running on
that 1080 GTX that beefy machine we're
getting about 11 milliseconds for a
frame on tensorflow J's running on an
integrated graphics card on one of these
laptops we're getting about 100
milliseconds for frame I just want to
point out that 100 milliseconds is
actually not so bad that pac-man game
was running with this model and you can
really build something interactive with
that the web is only going to get faster
and faster there are new set of
standards like WebGL compute shaders and
web GPU which gives you much closer to
the metal access to the GPU but the web
has its limitations you live in a
sandbox environment and you can only
really get access to the GPU through
these api's so how do we scale beyond
those limitations with that I'm going to
hand it off to Nick who's going to talk
about hollow scale thanks to kill today
we're launching tensorflow support for
nodejs
thank you we're really excited to bring
and easy to use high performance machine
learning library to JavaScript
developers the open source community
around nodejs and npm is really awesome
there's incredible movement in the space
a ton of libraries and packages for
developers to use today and now we're
bringing ml to this front the engine
that runs nodejs v8 is super fast it's
had tons of resources put into it by
companies like Google and we've seen the
interpreter be up to ten times as fast
as Python lots of room for performance
improvements also using tensorflow gives
us access to really high-end machine
learning hardware like GPU devices and
TP use in the cloud look for support for
that soon let's step back and look at
the architecture we highlighted earlier
we have a layers API and in a little bit
lower level core API that has our ops
this whole runtime is powered by WebGL
in the browser but today through NPM
we're shipping a package that gives you
tensor flow that gives you access to
those TP use the GPU and CPU all of this
is through our NPM package to show you
how easy it is to use our node bindings
I want to show you a little code snippet
this application function right here is
a very common server-side request
response handler for an endpoint those
who have worked with the Express
framework know exactly what's going on
here our endpoint listens for slash
model and takes input as a request which
we pass into a tensorflow j/s model and
that output is pushed out into the
response now to turn on high-performance
sensor flow code we only need two lines
of code an import which loads our
binding and in an existing API call to
set our back-end the tensorflow
now this model is running with the
performance of tensorflow
what works today out of the box so we
can take pre-existing Python models and
run those natively and nodejs the models
we've kind of showed off today all of
those will run in our node runtime
there's no need to bring up Python stack
to your node infrastructure just run
into JavaScript our MPM package today
ships an off-the-shelf CPU bill there's
no additional drivers to do just install
our package and you're up and running
our whole API we ship in tensorflow GS
will work with our node runtime every
API we've showcased will work today out
of the box now we've built a little demo
using Major League Baseball data and no
GS to showcase what you can do with
machine learning no GS and JavaScript
we've used Major League Baseball
advanced medias pitch FX data set to do
some machine learning the pitch effects
data set is this large library of sensor
data about pitches that baseball players
have thrown in actual baseball games for
those that aren't super familiar with
baseball we've given a little context
here a pitcher will throw different
types of pitches to fool the player
who's trying to hit this ball there's
pitches that have higher velocities
there's pitches that are a little slower
but have more movement in this example
we've sort of highlighted the fastball
to change up in the curveball those are
all types of pitches don't get too hung
up about the details of baseball what
we're really trying to solve here is a
very classic machine learning problem of
taking sensor information and drawing a
classification to that so for that I'm
gonna actually showcase this demo
Oh rent so on one side of my screen I
have a terminal which I'm going to start
my note application with and on the Left
I have a web browser we've built this a
very simple UI that listens to what our
server is doing over sockets those have
used the socket IO library and node know
what this interaction is doing so I'm
just gonna type node start my server and
now alter node my model is up and
running and training every time we take
a pass through our data set we report
that over the socket to our client and
you can see the blue bar is moving a
little bit closer to 100% that's our
model understanding how to tell the
difference between a curve ball or a
fastball and as you can kind of see
every step it moves a little bit
differently and our model is having a
little bit of trouble at the moment with
the fastball sinker but it's only looked
at data for a few passes the more this
server runs the better it gets at
training so all of this training data
we've shown is historical baseball data
from 2015 to 2017 I'm going to hit this
test live button and this is going to
use with ease the node framework to go
out to Major League Baseball pull in
some newer data some live data and run
the evaluation so once this data comes
in we're gonna see the orange bars and
the orange bars shows how much better we
are at predicting data that our model
has never seen before these are live
pictures and we're really good at I
didn't find that curveball and not so
great at that fastball sinker still so
let's jump back and continue to look at
our next slide
this is the architecture of what we were
doing in that demo we've built a very
simple node server that hosts our
javascript models and when we hit that
live button it reaches out to Major
League Baseball pulls in that live data
and runs inference on those new pitches
we continue to just report that to any
connected clients through the browser
where does this stack up and perform it
so in that training set we were looking
at 7,000 pitches and we were training
every couple seconds 7,000 pitches so
that's an interesting benchmark but
let's actually classify that with the
mobile net benchmark we showcased
earlier so these are the numbers for
Python tensorflow the GPU and the CPU
inference time so we're just getting
started we've just launched an NPM
package we have a lot of a ways to go
but we have some promising early numbers
to showcase tensorflow when no GS is
exactly as fast as Python tensorflow
so with that I'm gonna hand it off to
Nikhil to wrap up thanks Nick
exciting stuff okay so let's recap some
of the api's and libraries and tools
that we have supported today with
tensorflow jazz we have a low-level api
called the core API which is a set of
accelerated linear algebra kernels and a
layer for automatic differentiation we
saw an example of that with the
polynomial Russian demo we also have a
high-level layers API that encodes
machine learning best practices into an
API that's much more easy to use and we
saw an example of that with that edition
RNN translation demo we also have showed
you a couple ways that you can take pre
trained models from Python via saved
model or via Kerris models and port
those to the browser for inference or
doing retraining or competing accuracy
and of course we also showed you the new
node J s support for tensorflow jazz
today and we're really excited about
that okay so this project tensorflow
Jess was not just the three of us on
stage here it was a cross team
collaboration between many amazing
people at Google and we also have some
amazing open source contributors that I
want to send a shout out to this project
literally would not have been possible
without them so thank you all of the
things that we talked about here today
the demos all the code is open source on
our website J s tensorflow org all of
the code is also open sourced on github
github calm / tensorflow
/ TF j s we also have a community
mailing list this is a place where
people can go and ask questions post
their demos and and that kind of thing
we have some office hours today at 3:30
and we have some office hours tomorrow
at 9:30 which I invite you to come and
talk to us in person and we also have
some tents we have the experiments tent
that's @h that's where that move mirror
demo the full-screen version of that
will be and we also will be at the AI
10th as well so we are really excited to
build the next chapter of machine
learning and JavaScript with you thank
you
[Music]