[Music]
my name is Priya and I'm Anjali
we're both software engineers on the
tensorflow team working on distributed
tensorflow we're so excited to be here
today to tell you about distributor
tensorflow training
let me grab the clicker okay hopefully
most of you know what tensorflow is it's
an open-source machine learning
framework used extensively both inside
and outside Google for example if you
tried the smart compose feature that was
launched a couple of days ago that
feature uses tensorflow tensorflow
allows you to build train and predict
using neural networks such as this in
training we learn the parameters of the
network using data training complex
neural networks with large amounts of
data can often take a long time in the
graph here you can see you can see the
training time on the x-axis and the
accuracy of predictions on the y-axis
this is taken from training an image
recognition model on a single GPU as you
can see it took more than 80 hours to
get to 75% accuracy if you have some
experience running complex machine
learning models this might sound rather
familiar to you and it might make you
feel something like this if your
training takes only a few minutes to a
few hours you'll be productive and happy
and you can try out new ideas faster
when it starts to take a few days maybe
you could still manage and run a few
things in parallel when it starts to
take a few weeks your progress will slow
down and it becomes expensive to try out
every new idea and when it starts to
take more than a month I think it's not
even worth thinking about and this is
not an exaggeration
training complex models such as the
resonate 50 that we'll talk about later
in the talk can take up to a week on a
single but powerful GPU like a Tesla P
100 so natural question to us is how can
we make training fast there are a number
of things you can try you can use a
faster accelerator such as a TPU or
tensor processing units I'm sure you've
heard all about them in the last couple
of days here your input pipeline might
be the ball leg so you can work on that
and make that faster there are a number
of guidelines on the tensorflow website
that you can try and improve the
performance or your training in this
talk will focus on distributed training
that is running training in parallel on
multiple devices such as CPUs GPUs or TP
use in order to make your training
faster with the techniques that we'll
talk about in this talk you can bring
down your training time from weeks two
hours with just a few lines of code and
a few powerful GPUs in the graph here
you can see the images per second
processed while training an image
recognition model as you can see as we
increase the number of GPUs from one to
four to eight the images per second
process it can almost double every time
we'll come back to these performance
numbers later with more details
so before diving into the details of how
you can get that kind of scaling and
tensorflow
first I want to cover a few high-level
concepts and architectures in
distributed training this will give us a
strong foundation with which to
understand the various solutions as your
focus on training today let's take a
look at what a typical training loop
looks like let's say you have a simple
model like this with a couple of hidden
layers each layer has a bunch of weights
and biases also called the model
parameters or trainable variables
a training step begins with some
processing on the input data we then
feed this input into the model and
compute the predictions in the forward
pass we then compare the predictions
with the input label and compare to
compute the loss then in the backward
pass we compute the gradients and
finally we update the model's parameters
using these gradients this whole process
is known as one training step and the
training loop repeats this training step
until you reach the desired accuracy
let's say you begin your training with a
simple machine under your desk with a
multi-core CPU luckily tensorflow
handles scaling onto a multi-core CPU
for you automatically next you may speed
up by a dagger accelerator to your
machine such as a GPU or a TPU with
distributed training you can go even
further you can go from one machine with
a single device to one machine with
multiple devices and finally to multiple
machines with possibly multiple devices
each connected over the network with
little with a number of techniques
eventually it's possible to scale to
hundreds of devices and that's indeed
what we do in a lot of Google systems by
the way in the rest of this talk we'll
use the terms device worker or
accelerator to refer to processing units
such as GPUs or GPUs so how does
distributor training work like
everything else in software engineering
there are a number of ways to go about
when you think about distributing your
training what approach you pick depends
on the size of your model the amount of
training data you have and the available
devices
the most common architecture in
distributed training and what is what is
known as data parallelism in data
parallelism we run the same model and
compute
on each worker but with a different
slice of the input data each device
computes the loss and the gradients we
use these gradients to update the models
parameters and the updated model is then
used in the next round of computation
there are two common approaches when you
think about how do you update the model
using these gradients the first approach
is what is known as a synchronous
parameter server approach in this
approach we designate some some devices
as parameter servers as shown in blue
here these servers hold the parameters
of your model others are designated as
workers as shown in green here workers
do the bulk of the computation each
worker fetches the parameters from the
parameter server it then confused the
last ingredients it sends the gradients
back to the parameter server which then
updates the models parameters using
these gradients each worker does this
independently so this allows us to scale
this approach to a large number of
workers this has worked well for many
models in Google where training workers
might be preempted by high priority
production jobs or where this asymmetry
between the different workers or where
machines might go down for regular
maintenance and all of this doesn't hurt
the scaling because the workers are not
beating on each other the downside of
this approach however is that workers
can get out of sync their computing
their gradients on steel parameter
values and this can delay convergence
the second approach is what is known as
synchronous all reduce this approach has
become more common with the rise of fast
accelerators such as keep use or GPUs in
this approach each worker has a copy of
parameters on its own the
no special parameter servers each worker
confused the lost ingredients based on a
subset of training samples once the
gradients are computed the workers
communicate among themselves to
propagate the gradients and update their
model parameters all the workers are
synchronized which means that the next
round of computation doesn't begin until
each worker has received the updated
gradients and a barrier that's Mauro
when you have fast devices in a
controlled environment the variance of
step time between the different workers
can be small when combined with strong
communication links between the
different devices overall overhead of
synchronization can be small so whenever
practical this approach can lead to
faster convergence a class of algorithms
called all reduce can be used to
efficiently combine the gradients across
the different workers all reduce
aggregates the values from different
workers for example by adding them up
and then copying them to the different
workers it's a fuse algorithm that can
be very efficient and it can reduce the
overhead of synchronization of gradients
by a lot
there are many all reduce algorithms
available depending on the type of
communication available between the
different workers one common algorithm
is what is known as Ringold reduce in
recoil reduce each worker sends his
gradients to a successor on the ring and
receives gradients from its predecessor
there are a few more such rounds of
gradient exchanges I won't be going into
the details here but at the end of the
algorithm each worker has received a
copy of the combined gradients ring all
reduce uses network bandwidth optimally
because it uses both the upload and the
download bandwidth at each worker it can
also overlap the gradient computation at
lower layers in the net
with transmission of radiance at the
higher layer which means it can further
reduce the training time wrinkle reduce
is just one approach and some hardware
vendors supplies specialized
implementations of all reduce for their
hardware for example the NVIDIA nickel
we have a team in Google working on fast
implementations of all reduce for
various device topologies the bottom
line is that all reduce can be fast when
working with multiple devices on a
single machine or multiple image or a
small number of machines so given these
two broad architectures and data
parallelism you may be wondering which
approach should you pick there isn't one
right answer parameter server approach
is preferable if you have a large number
of not so powerful or not so reliable
machines for example if you have a large
cluster of machines with just CPUs the
synchronous already's approach on the
other hand is preferable if you have
fast devices with strong communication
links such as TP use or multiple GPUs on
a single machine parameter server
approach has been around for a while and
it has been supported well in tensorflow
Tipu's on the other hand use already
would all reduce approach out of the box
in the next section of this talk we'll
show you how you can scale your training
using the all reduce approach on
multiple GPUs with just a few lines of
code before I get into that I just want
to mention another type of distributed
training known as model parallelism that
you may have heard of a simple way to
think about model parallelism is when
your model is so big that it doesn't fit
in the memory of one device so you
divide the model into smaller parts and
you can do those computations on
different workers with the same training
samples for example you could put
different layers of your model on
different devices these days however
most devices have big enough memory that
most models can fit in their memory
so in the rest of this talk we'll
continue to focus on data parallelism
now that you're armed with fundamentals
of distributed training architectures
let's see how you can do this intensive
flow as I already mentioned we're going
to focus on scaling to multiple GPUs
with the all reduce architecture in
order to do so easily I'm pleased to
introduce a new distribution strategy
API this API allows you to distribute
your training intensive flow with very
little modification to your code with
distribution strategy API you no longer
need to place your ops or parameters on
specific devices you don't need to worry
about structuring your model in a way
that the gradients or losses across
devices are aggregated correctly
distribution does so distributions Riley
does that for you
it is easy to use and fast to Train
now let's look at some code to see how
you can do this intense how we can use
this API in our example we're going to
be using tens of flows high-level API
call estimator if you use this API
before you might be familiar with the
following snippet of code to create a
custom estimator it requires three
arguments the first one is a function
that defines your model so it defines
the parameters of your model how you
compute the loss and the gradients and
how you update the models parameters the
second argument is the directory where
you want to persist the state of your
model and the third argument is a
configuration called run config where
you can specify things like how often
you want to checkpoint how often
summaries should be saved and so on in
this case we've used the default run
config once you create the estimator you
can start your training by calling the
train method
with the input function that provides
your training data
so given this code to do the training on
one device how can you change it to run
on multiple GPUs you simply need to add
one line of code instantiate something
called mirrored strategy and pass it to
the run config call that's it that's all
the code changes you need to scale this
code to multiple GPUs mirrored strategy
is the type of distribution strategy api
that i just mentioned with this api you
don't need to make any changes to your
model function or your input function or
your training loop you don't even need
to specify your devices if you want to
run on all available devices it will
automatically detect that and run your
training on all available GPUs so that's
it those are all the code changes you
need this API is available in TF contrib
and you can use it you can try it out
today let me quickly talk about what
mayor strategy does mirror strategy
implements the synchronous all reduce
architecture that we talked about out of
the box for you in merge strategy the
models parameters are mirrored across
the various devices hence the name
mirrored strategy each device computes
the loss and gradients based on a subset
of the input data the gradients are then
aggregated across the workers using an
all reduce algorithm that is appropriate
for your device topology as I already
mentioned with mirrored strategy you
don't need to make any changes to your
model or your training loop this is
because we've changed underlying
components of tensor flow to be
distribution aware for example optimizer
batch norm summaries etcetera you don't
need to make any changes to your input
function either as long as you're using
the recommended tensor flow data set API
saving and checkpointing works
seamlessly
so you can save with one or no
distribution strategy and resume with
another and summaries work as expected
as well so you can continue to visualize
your training intensive old mere
strategy is just one type of
distribution strategy and we're working
on a few others for a variety of use
cases I'll now hand it off to Anjali to
show you some cool demos and performance
numbers
thanks Priya for the great introduction
to Murad strategy before we run the demo
let us get familiar with a few
configurations I'm going to be running
the resonate 50 model from the tensor
flow model garden ResNet 50 is an
emulsification model that has 50 layers
it uses skip connections for efficient
gradient flow the tensor flow model
garden is a repo where there are
collection of different models they're
written in tensor flow high level ap is
so if you are new to tensor flow this is
a great resource to start with I'm going
to be using the image net data set is
input to model training the image net
data set is a collection of over a
million images that have been
categorized into a thousand labels I'm
going to instantiate the n1 standard
instance on GCE and attach eight nvidia
tesla v 100's or voltage GPUs let's run
the demo now as I mentioned I'm creating
an N 1 standard instance attaching 8
Nvidia Tesla V 100 or voltage GPUs
I also attach SSD disk this contains the
image net data set which is input to our
model training to run a tensor flow
model we need to install a few drivers
and pet packages and here is a gist with
all the commands required
I'm going to make this just public so
you can set up an instance yourself and
try running the model let's open an SSH
connection to the instance by clicking
on a button here this should bring up a
terminal like this
so I've already cloned the garden model
repo we're going to be running this
command inside the resonate directory
we're going to run the image net main
file so we're using the image net data
set a bad-sized of 1024 or 128 per GPU a
model directory is going to point to the
GCS bucket that's going to hold our
check points and summaries that we want
to save we point our data directory to
the SSD disk well charge the image net
data set and the number of GPUs is 8
over which we want to distribute or
trade our model so let's run this model
now and as the model is starting to
train let's take a look at some of the
code changes that are involved in the
interchange the resinate model function
so this is a resonate main function in
the garden model repo first we
instantiate the mirrored strategy object
then we pass it to the run config as
part of the Train distribute argument we
create an estimator object with the run
config and then we call trained on this
estimator object and that's it those are
all the code changes you need to
distribute the ResNet model let's go
back and see how our training is going
so we've run out for a few hundred steps
at the bottom of the screen you should
see a few metrics the loss is descri
cing steps per second learning rate
let's look at tensor board so this is
from a run where I've run the model for
90,000 steps a little over that so it's
not the run we just started so the
orange and red lines are the training
and evaluation losses so as a number of
steps increase
see the loss decreasing let's look at
evaluation accuracy and this is when
we're training ResNet 50 or 8 GPUs so if
we see that around 91 thousand steps we
were able to achieve a 75 percent
accuracy let's see what it what this
looks like when we run it on a single
GPU so let's toggle the tensor board
buttons on the left and look at the
Train and evaluation loss curves when we
train our model on one GPU so the blue
lines are one CPU and red are orange and
eight and you can see that the loss
doesn't decrease as rapidly as it does
with eight GPUs here are the evaluation
accuracy curves were able to achieve a
higher accuracy when we distribute our
model across eight CPUs as opposed to
one
let's compare using wall time so we've
run the same model for the same amount
of time and when we run it over multiple
GPUs we were able to achieve higher
accuracy faster or trained our model
faster let's look at a few performance
benchmarks on the DG X 1 3 2 X 1 is a
machine on win which on which we run
deep learning models
we're running miss mixed precision
training with a per GPU batch size of
256 it also has 8 volta or v 100 GPUs so
the graph shows x-axis the number of
GPUs on the x-axis and images per second
on the y-axis so as we go from one GPU
to a we are able to achieve a speed-up
of 7x and this is performance right out
of the box with no tuning we're actively
working on improving performance so that
you are able to achieve more speed up
and get more images per second
when you distribute your model across
multiple GPUs
so far we've been talking about the core
part of model training and distributing
your model using Murat strategy okay so
let's say now you have deployed your
model on multiple GPUs you're going to
expect to see the same kind of boost in
images per second when you do that but
that may you may not be able to view as
many images per second as compared to
one CPU you may not see the boost and
performance and the reason for that is
often the input pipeline when you run
your model on a single GPU the input
pipeline is pre processing the data and
making the data available on the GPU for
training but GPUs or TP use as you know
process and compute data much faster
than a CPU this means that when you
distribute your model across multiple
GPUs the input pipeline is also not able
to keep up with the training it quickly
becomes a bottleneck for the rest of the
talk I'm going to show you how
tensorflow makes it easy for you to use
TF the data API is to build efficient
and performant input pipelines here's a
simple input pipeline for ResNet 50
we're going to use TF da-ta-da api's
because data sets are awesome they
helped us build complex pipeline using
simple reusable pieces when you have
lots of data and different data formats
and you want to perform complex
transformations on this data you want to
be using T of data API is to build your
input pipeline first we are going to use
the list files API to get the list of
input files that contain your image and
labels then we are going to read these
files using the TF record data set
reader we're going to shuffle the
records repeat them a few times
depending on if you want to run your
model for a couple of epochs and finally
apply your map
permission so this processes each record
and applies a transformation such as
cropping flipping image decoding and
finally batch the input and finally
batch the input into a batch size that
you desire the input pipeline can be
thought of as an ETL process which is
extract transform and load process in
the extract phase we are reading from
persistent storage which can be local or
remote in the transform phase we are
applying the different transformations
like shuffled repeat map and batch and
finally in the load phase we are
providing this processed data to the
accelerator for training so how does
this apply to the example that we just
saw in the extract phase we list the
files and read it using the TF record
data set reader in the transform phase
we apply the shuffle repeat map and
batch transformations and finally in the
load phase we tell sensor flow how to
grab the data from the data set this is
what our input pipeline looks like we
have the extract transform and load
phases happening sequentially followed
by the training on the accelerator this
means whether when the CPU is busy
pre-processing the data the accelerator
is idle and where the accelerator is
training your model the CPU is idle but
the different phases of the ETL process
use different hardware resources for
example the extract step uses the
persistent storage the transform step
uses a different course of the CPU and
finally the training happens on the
accelerator so if we can paralyze these
different phases then we can overlap the
pre
processing of data on the CPU with
training of the model on the GPU this is
called pipelining so we can use
pipelining and some parallelization
techniques to build more efficient
import pipelines let us look at few of
these techniques
first you can parallelize file reading
let's say you have a lot of data that
sharded a car across a cloud storage
service you want read multiple files and
parallel and you can do this using the
non parallel reads call as when you
instantiate the Tierra when you call a
TF record data set API this allows you
to increase your effective throughput we
can also paralyze map function for
transformations you can data paralyze
the different transformation for of the
map function by using the numpad L calls
argument typically the num the argument
we provide is a number of cores of the
CPU and finally you want to call
prefetch at the end of your input
pipeline prefetch decouples the time the
data is produced from the time it is
consumed this means that you can buffer
data for the next training step while
the accelerator is still training the
current step this is what we had before
and this is what we can get an
improvement on here the different phases
of the input pipeline are happening in
parallel were training we are able to
see that the CPU is pre processing data
for the training step 2
while the accelerator is still training
step 1 neither the CPU now the
accelerator is idle for long periods of
time the training time is now a maximum
of pre processing and training on the
accelerator as you can see the
accelerator is still or not 100%
utilized there are few advanced
techniques that we can add to our input
pipeline to improve this we can use fuse
transformation ops
of some of these API calls shuffle and
repeat for example can be replaced by
its equivalent fused up
so this paralyzes buffering elements for
epoch n plus 1 while producing elements
for epoch n we can also replace map and
batch with its equivalent fused up this
paralyzes paralyzes the map
transformation with adding the input
tensors to batch with these techniques
we are able to process data much faster
and make it available to the accelerator
for training and improve the training
speed
I hope this gives you a good idea of how
you can use TF data API is to build
efficient and performant input pipelines
when you train your model so far we've
been talking about training on a single
machine and multiple devices but what if
you wanted to train on multiple machines
you can use as the estimators train and
evaluate API train and evaluate API uses
the acing parameter server approach this
API is used widely within Google and it
scales well to a large number of
machines here's a link to the API where
you can learn more on how to use it
we're also excited to be working on a
number of new distribution strategies
we're working on a multi machine Mirage
strategy which allows you to distribute
your module across many machines with
many devices we're also working on
adding distribution strategy support to
TP use and directly in TF dot chaos in
this talk we've talked a lot about the
different concepts related to
distributor training architectures in
API but when you go home today here are
three things for you to keep in mind
when you train your model distribute
your training to make it faster to do
this you want to use distribution
strategy api's they're easy to use and
they're fast input pipeline performance
is important
use TF data api is to build efficient
input pipelines here are a few tenths of
flow resources first we have the
distribution strategy API you can try
using mirrored strategy to train your
model across multiple GPUs here's a link
to the resonate 50 model garden example
so you can try running this example it
has mirrored strategy API support
enabled here's a link also to the input
pipeline performance guide which has
more techniques that you can use to
build efficient input pipelines and
here's the link to the gist that I
mentioned in the demo you can try
setting up your own instance on running
the resonate 50 model garden example
thank you for attending our talk and we
hope you had a great IO
[Music]