I get questions all the time about some
of the new concepts in machine learning
and what they really mean so for example
I get asked what is one hot encoding and
why should I use it it does seem very
inefficient you know that's a great
question so let's take a look at the
answer by digging into some code will
also see how a function called Arg max
complements this perfectly and saves you
a lot of coding here's the popular iris
classification data set where the values
implemented in a JavaScript array you'll
notice that there are five values in
each entry four of which are features of
the iris and the fifth which will be
zero one or two
is the classification the classes are
shown here with iris setosa being zero
iris versicolor being one an iris
virginica being two now this seems to be
a really efficient encoding but when
doing machine learning you often have to
transform this into something that
appears to be less efficient such as one
hot encoding which you can see here and
instead of 0 1 & 2 for the values you
have an array with 3 values in it and
here we've only got three options of
flower if we had more options this array
would be much bigger the index of the
array is set to 1 for the relative
flower so for example for its Atossa
the first element is 1 and everything
else is 0 and for virginica the third
element is 1 and everything else is 0
now this might seem a little strange but
when you consider the neural network
that's doing the classification they're
designed with the number of output nodes
equal to the number of classes that you
want to determine we're picking between
three classes here so I have three
output nodes these three output nodes
will then produce three probabilities
the probability that you match class 0
the probability match class 1 or the
probability in match class 2 so it might
look something like this
so now when training the network we can
train it from matching values ie if the
flowers of classes who we want to train
it with a 0 desired output from neuron 0
0 desired output from neuron
and a one desired output from neuron two
so that's one hard encoding it may not
look efficient from a storage
perspective but it Maps really neatly to
our desired output and thus is very
efficient for training another function
called Arg max is then really handy for
helping you find the desired values so
instead of searching through a list to
find the biggest value it would
transform that list of priorities into
something like this and from there you
can derive the correct class so let's
jump back into the code and we'll see
this in action
here I'm going to evaluate a flower with
the features five point eight two point
seven five point one and one point nine
I know that this is an iris virginica
which is class two but let's see what
the neural network gives me well first
take a look at the raw prediction and
then we'll take a look at the prediction
that's been determined using Arg max
let's run this in the browser when i
refresh the JavaScript will start
executing and here you can see my epochs
and my loss at that epoch it's steadily
decreasing which is good and now I get
my classification and you can see that
has very low probabilities for 0 and 1
and a very high probability for 2 which
is what we'd expect if I then execute
Arg max on this I will get to consider
the amount of code that you would have
to write in this case it's not a lot
with just two classes but if there are a
lot more classes
and you needed to find the biggest you'd
have a lot of coding to do but Arg max
does this for you given that these
values are in a tensor I hope this was a
useful explanation of one heart encoding
and how it complements an Arg max
function these are some of the concepts
that are a bit different when you're
coding for machine learning but they're
incredibly useful and powerful
one harden coding is great because it's
a way of mapping your classes to the
shape that a neural network outputs
values an Arg max is a function that
saves you writing a lot of code to go
over all those values to find the
biggest there's lots of useful functions
and transforms like these intensive flow
and we'll continue to cover them on this
channel so go ahead and hit that
subscribe button now thank you
[Music]