[Music]
hi everybody we're here at the tents
flow developer summit at the tensorflow
cafe and I'm chatting with Andrew Gasper
ovitch from tensor flow hub and you
announced tensorflow hub today can you
tell us all about it
yeah so tensorflow hub is the new way to
share what we're calling modules which
is meant to be a reusable component so
it's a little bit less than a model it's
just the reusable portion okay but it is
the graph the weights and potentially
any assets that come with it so it's all
packaged up into a component that makes
it easy to share in just one line of
code and one line of code yeah yeah that
was a requirement from the beginning
actually no more than one line of code
where do you go from here off a lot of
code yeah yeah well I guess the natural
zero that's next year now one of the
things you mentioned in your talk was
about these modules being composable
reusable and retrain of all could yes
that's true that composable for us yeah
so composable just means that you can do
things like add your own classification
so if you're talking about an image mod
module it doesn't include the
classification from the model so that is
something that you can compose with what
you're building in the case of text
classification that may be something
like an embedding module okay and then
in other cases we also want to have just
general-purpose modules that you can
compose around almost like functions
that you can call together and make
building blocks for an entire model I
say so so if I have a model that I don't
know for example of doing OCR in an
image and but it can also tag things
within that image what saying is I could
break out the OCR part and I could break
out the tagging part and compose them
into something new yeah absolutely
absolutely and that's gonna be something
really interesting to see what develops
in the community over time just the ways
of putting things together and sort of
modules that people end up ryeol yeah so
it's we're providing building all the
communities providing building blocks
yes
we have we have a number of modules to
start with and they're very
general-purpose things doing you know
image classification doing text
classification we have those embedding
modules but I think that over time what
the community can contribute is what
really will be interesting sounds great
so we've mentioned that there composable
and then reusable reusable just means
that you can basically take something
that already exists and apply it to your
own particular problem makes perfect
sense yeah and then I'm really
interested in retraining below I mean we
speak a lot about the attentive love for
poets where you can retrain the final
layer to make it flowers instead of
general damages and is it to do a
similar thing Gaudi yes yeah definitely
so there is you know the classic sort of
transfer learning case there where you
would take an image classification
module just up to the feature vectors
and then retrain your own classification
on top to do things but you know you can
also go deeper than that you can start
retraining text embedding modules and
the thing about TF hub is that you can
actually do fine-tuning and Retraining
inside the module itself so if you have
enough data you can actually turn on
retraining inside the module because
it's just a graph with the weights so
you know you can really get better
results because it's not just something
that's static it's something that you
can really include in your own model
sounds good now in your talk you showed
this for like classifying rabbits yes
yeah yeah and you had that one picture
of a rabbit which I think is the best
picture of any in the entire day so we
have to cut to that and show it's a
beautiful yeah so tell us what did you
do in that demo in the demo we basically
just it's the same ideas the tensorflow
for poets we start with a general
purpose image classification model just
up to the feature vectors and in the
particular demo example we were
classifying rabbits maybe including the
Easter Bunny and you know we added our
own classification on top and we fed in
all of our own training examples and the
end result is that you get something
that is special to your task but
includes all of the benefits of the
general-purpose model nice it's kind of
fun yeah how was accurate was at
detecting rabbits it's very accurate
we'll have to see how it works with the
Easter Bunny but you didn't put the
Easter Bunny in your test next year so
so if I'm a developer and I want to
build like I'm maybe I'm an expert in
rabbit detection and you know and I want
to build like a custom model and I want
to contribute this into tensorflow hub
how would I go about doing that well
that's something that we're really
excited to work on over the next few
months right now a module is accessible
via any URL and so you can host a module
and you can use it in that one line of
code but we want to create a platform
where people can go and find modules for
all sorts of different topics and have
that one central place that you always
know that you can get really high
quality stuff in a variety of different
areas and is there like some kind of
curation that's something it remains to
be you know seeing specifically what
we're gonna do but we want to be able to
open it up to it as wide a group of
people as possible sounds good so where
can I find this again
it's tensorflow org slash hub tensorflow
org slash hub I keep saying tensorflow
hub / org we should remain tensorflow
org slash hub yeah you know go check it
out so thank you so much Andrew thank
you it's been really fun and I love that
slide okay so thanks everybody for
watching this episode if you got any
questions for me or if you have any
questions for Andrew please leave them
in the comments below and all of the
links that we spoke about today will put
in the text description so thank you so
much and don't forget to hit that
subscribe button
[Music]
you