hi everybody and welcome to the
tensorflow developer summit I'm Laurence
Moroney and I'm here at the tensorflow
cafe and it's my honor to chat with
derek murray and derek just did a talk
on TF data and lots of great stuff and
TF data and lots of great new stuff into
yeah could you could you tell us about
it a lot of works gone into performance
and we made some announcements about the
new performance numbers we're achieving
with TF data so of this 13,000 images
per second number that were really proud
of but we also know that we can totally
beat and we're still working to like
make a making further advances I'm gonna
be chatting with you in this seat next
year and you're gonna be saying it's 130
oh my goodness it will need uh we'll
need that bigger clear a part of our
next keep up with that and a lot of
advances on ease of use as well so we're
adding sort of convenience functions to
make it easier for people to get started
with the library and to deal with
different kinds of data formats that are
maybe not what we're as used to using
internally at Google but are more sort
of inspired by what the community wants
okay okay sounds good so and one of the
things that you spoke about a lot and I
really like that catcher was like fast
flexible and easy to use you know is
that your catchphrase oh that's a yeah
you need three things rhetorical that's
how I do them so what impact do you
think that's gonna have come people
building models well I think I think
before we had a library with these
characteristics we kind of had to made a
dichotomy between two different options
you could either go this feeding route
which was very flexible you could write
any code you liked in Python and it
would work gonna get into tensor books
right super slow I mean it was kind of
held up by the global interpreter lock
in your Python program you just couldn't
keep up with a modern accelerator maybe
like three years ago you could do that
but now there's so much faster than
writing and then on the other side we
had these very flexible queue based
input pipelines that were a lot faster a
lot more efficient plots not very easy
to use they had like very sharp edges
okay could forget to put a line of code
on your program and it would they would
hang there no so what we want to do is
take the good parts of both of those and
put them together so there's just more
there's really just one choice and it's
easy to use for people just getting
started but they can also very rapidly
get
performance that you would need to be
able to saturate a voltage GPU or a
quote GPU in my case like I'm a
relatively new developer with this kind
of stuff and a naive developer it to
some extent so it's like in my I was
thinking like how a lot of this works is
I get my data and I throw it out there
in training model and it rains and it
goes and I never really thought about
how I refine my data to be able to get
it in to make it more efficient so I'm
sure if I was doing it to be 100 images
a second another thousand how do I get
from that to the 13,000 well there are a
lot of sort of tips and tricks that
we've collected as we've done this they
did actually the original play with TF
data it was to make something that was
easy to use and performance was a
secondary consideration but as we
discovered the people were becoming more
and more demanding and as the cloud TPU
project was coming online really well
okay we caught it like trying hard to do
well here let's push it really adds
vision and we've vari these benchmarks
that we're following and that other
people are using in their frameworks to
compare so there's a lot of tips and
tricks and the best way to learn how to
do yourself is to look at the
performance guide that we've just put up
on tensorflow org if you have data
performance guide and it has a lot of
sort of both the theory of how you
optimize pipelines and its kind of
elementary queueing theory in some
senses don't worry there's not too much
math and and also like the literal
ingredients that you use in your program
to achieve these pipeline benefits right
so hopefully it's accessible what we're
also planning to do and Brandon's data
is going to be talking about this later
today is kind of auto-tuning your
pipeline a bit more so right now it's a
very manual process and we're just
trying to give you all the parts you
need so that someone skilled in the art
can put something together that's fast
but we want that speed to be accessible
to everyone as well because it's only by
making things fast enough that we can
sort of chief transformative new uses of
machine learning so we're going to work
on auto-tuning a sort of automatic
compilation to to to apply these changes
automatically for you nice-nice and all
this is going to be in the TF data in
the tf2 names yes probably like that
name it's good name and long then you'd
mention intense flow dog there is that
for optimizing and input and of course
people should watch your talk well they
should watch my type they should also
watch Brennan's talk later this
afternoon he is really going to go into
depth on sort of how you take a slow
program starting out it and go through
the steps of using our optimizations
that also our monitoring tools to like
work out from a sort of hypothesis
testing scientific point of view how to
make your pipeline more efficient sounds
good so if I want to get started with
this where should I go well I think the
best place to get started right now is
actually to head over to cackle because
just in the last couple months I think
cackles put out this API for downloading
data sets Oh what like a single command
you type tag all data sets download and
the name of the data set that you've
seen on their website and it's just one
command puts all the files in your local
directory and then in tensorflow you can
use this new make csv data set api the a
noogler rachel lynn who just joined the
team did in her first like first couple
of weeks it's awesome it really
simplifies the task of working with this
kind of data you just have to like write
one line of code in here off to the
races mode and it was done by in New
England yeah yeah she's just started
she's great did she think that was like
some kind of hazing or like I hope not
very project what you do it's amazing
though that's something that just
somebody newly joined Google could do
that but that's it's great
that's the tensorflow community is like
that there's so many people out there
doing amazing and we love the roof had a
lot of community contributions on this
part of the library for different
formats and sort of different dinner
analysis approaches that people want to
take and we really appreciate and you
know invite people to send as many as
possible okay so great big thanks to the
community yeah and a great big thanks to
you so thank you and thanks everybody
for watching if you've got any questions
for me if you've got any questions for
Derrick please leave them in the
comments below and don't forget to hit
that subscribe button thanks
[Music]
you