hi everybody and welcome to tents Flo
meets in this episode I'm chatting with
how hon Wong thank you for having me
here who's been doing some really really
cool work with neuroscience and
tensorflow and machine learning and all
kinds of cool stuff and even a new
course so you've been working on dyad ex
machina which is a beautiful name for
what looks like a beautiful site could
you tell us all about it
sure so I will start from the name diet
ex machina diet means to us one which is
me and my partner Christian family and
my Christian is going to be on a future
show which is great yes so machine
things we constantly work with machine
and we're at the intersection of deep
learning and affective computing so as
for why we started diet ex machina I
think the story really starts four to
five years ago when we first met so I
was a student in finance and he was
working in human behavior area and we
started to collaborate okay because we
both share the same strong interesting
machine learning right so one of the
first machine learning projects that we
work together is to create the trading
algorithms okay well so christian
challenges us to think outside the box
instead of using the traditional
technical or fundamental analysis into
your algorithm why can't we add some
human behavioral elements like emotions
into your algorithms well so we end up
including sentiment into our algorithm
and a surprisingly sentiment is a great
trading very indicated trading signals I
can see that because I'm sure when some
people are buying then everybody jumps
on board and when some people are
selling well so after that I think it
really brought emotion into our
attention and it was started to study um
a lot more into this fella affective
neuroscience especially and we're at
numerous spoke in the field and I think
we started notice a problem which is how
society at large tends to ignore how
important emotion is especially like in
our daily decision-making process
because people tend to overvalue
cognition and rationality okay over
emotion interesting yeah so I think well
that's really the starting point that we
think probably it's our job
this diet X marking us job to bring this
affective layer back into people's daily
life so it's II saw an opportunity to
bring emotion into what are
traditionally logical decisions yep okay
where it died X marking I started yeah
interesting and now a lot of the work
that you've been doing and a lot of the
learning that you've been doing you're
turning into a course now right yes so
yeah so start from there actually
well the here is where deep learning and
the tense of law came in okay so we were
studying machine learning and but then
we discovered deep learning okay so I
think so here is also the point that we
hit a point that we cannot make more
much anymore progress because we're both
working for time and it what data get
all our free time outraged a jobs just
the way don't they yep trying to
understand machine learning and
effective computing so I think we had a
discussion and made a hard decision I
what took one year off fully folks focus
fully on deep learning and effective
computing okay so here you can think of
this course and we end up making this
course because this course is really the
synthesis of our learning okay because
we really dedicate a lot of time and
effort on learning deep learning and we
think this course will be a great start
for people who are new to deep learning
to get started but more importantly I
think our main focus is to help people
who wants to use deep learning to the
film that they're passionate about to be
able to get started so your course is
about applied deep learning with
tensorflow and cloudy a I yes there's a
lot in there so what kind of content do
you have well so this is our very first
the course and we're a little bit
ambitious trying to put everything in
there but the course is really meant to
help to help people who are new to
machine learning to be able to build
their first deep learning model and take
it all the way to deploy their model as
production level
okay then we move on to talk about the
basics of deep learning okay and how to
design an experiment with some typical
neural networks using Charis Charis yeah
yep and then we move on with of deep
into tensor flow we start from low-level
tensor flow we introduce the concept
like data flow graph and the tensile
board then we move on to high-level
tensor flow then help people to build a
model in the cloud the trend amado
evaluate the model and eventually deploy
their model as a production level API so
the deployment part is really
fascinating to me because there's lots
of great material out there about
training models and maybe doing a little
bit of a test but making it real world
making it applied how intention help
people to apply it to the felt they're
interested in nice and we'll put a link
to the course in the comments below
so you've you've been starting you've
started with neuroscience and then
you've moved into taking a year off and
creating a course and you've obviously
gotten very deep into machine learning
and you've gotten very deep into
neuroscience and the intersection
between the two of them what advice
would you give to people who are just
starting out well yes so like to talk a
little bit about connected back to our
learning experience of journey of deep
learning and possible a little bit about
affective neuroscience okay so I think
we also summarize this four piece of
learning I'd like to share here the four
PS of learning well remember myself a
published article ow our website also
people can check check it out a link for
that so I don't need to remember it yeah
great so the first two P papers and
books okay well I think is really the
foundation because by we we make sure we
read papers and books every single day
and we got up 4:30 a.m. the first attack
is to repaper Wow deep learning papers
so the beginning we read some more like
basic deep learning paper to know what
is trendy in the fill to help people
solve problems with deep learning then
we move on to be more specific about our
domain how people use deep learning to
solve
like neuroscience problems affective
neuroscience problems so 4:30 a.m. for
the first P yeah you've lost me already
so papers and the books Pixar book
second P is practice practice okay yeah
so I think practice very important
especially like I think I'm very
passionate about like every day I will
use tensorflow to build some neural
networks start from the basic neural
networks and they understand like data
flow graph and to like I'm very
interested interested in using tensor
forward to visualize my training and
evaluating results and how to tune my
models like hyper parameters so I think
then practice and you can find those
problems very easily on cargo and a
proud day I yeah
so the third P which with I think
personally is very helpful for my
learning which is preach preach yeah you
can think of lecturing or teaching okay
so every day I will give a Christian as
meaning lecture about what I learned
during the day about deep learning and
some theories or even your network I
built that day so I think it's mutually
beneficial helped me to consolidate my
knowledge and help him to have overview
about what I learned and also making
some progress yeah yeah from his side oh
well last Appy I think we think is
really helping us to get where we are
right now is passion yeah they're
definitely new passions yeah so well
first was like I mentioned we saw this
great potential of deep learning and a
tensor flow that you can leverage to
really bring the transformative change
into you into the domain because because
it's new technology and regularly in the
past at least based on our study about
the affective neuroscience no one has
ever leverage this technology to build
any algorithm yet so where you set out
to make that happen so bringing emotion
into algorithms yes that sounds
fascinating so so you started this
journey you know as you were doing
financial trading stuff and did
took a look at emotions and that you
know from out of that has grown Diet ex
machina and now your course if your
daily four PS that you're doing there's
a lot of amazing stuff there so so
what's next for how hard yes so next for
me and guides machina is where right now
still working on doing running
experiments every day and doing research
in affective computing area we're trying
to put things together to be able to
eventually present to the share with the
community so we're we will be working on
this part of part of the study what's
more it's another thing about the course
okay we are planning to make a new
course and we plan to deliver the course
by the end of this year or the beginning
of next year the course will be called
effective computing okay and deep
learning using tensor flow affective
computing and deep learning using tensor
flow yes I look forward to it yeah so in
this course we will be teaching people
how to use tensor flow and a Google
cloud machine learning engine to
streaming your psychophysiological
signals over time and to process your
signals and eventually the algorithm
should be able to make a real-time
prediction about your affective state
okay yeah excellent so your course on
effective computing it's going to be
coming out pretty soon maybe the end of
this year or sometime early next year
and maybe after the course comes down
we'll have you on again to talk about it
yes I would love to so we look forward
to it so thanks so much how Hanh and
thanks everybody for watching this
episode of tense Flo meets if you have
any questions for me if you have any
questions for Han please just leave them
in the comments below and whatever you
do don't forget to hit that subscribe
button thank you
you