[Music]
[Applause]
hi and welcome to coding tensorflow
a show where we focus on coding machine
learning and AI applications I'm
Laurence Moroney a developer advocate
for tensorflow
and in this episode we're going to
continue our series about using
JavaScript for machine learning in the
browser this is achieved using
tensorflow das a javascript library for
training and deploying ml models in the
browser and on no js' there's lots of
great information about it on the Jas
star tensorflow dot org site including
samples API Docs and frequently asked
questions in the first episode we took a
very basic look at what you need to get
up and running with tensorflow in the
browser by building a simple model that
fits its values to a line by learning
that it is actually a line off of a very
small training set in episode 2 we then
wanted to focus on data and how you
prepare data for training we did this by
taking a popular data set that for
classification of the iris flower and
turned it from raw CSV into a number of
tensors those would feature data and
those would label data for both training
and test sets now that the data is ready
in this episode we'll take a look at how
you can create a neural network to build
a model that can be used to classify
future data so when it sees unknown
measurements it will in fare from that
data which iris flower the data likely
represents it's a simple scenario but it
is the cornerstone building block of all
machine learning from an existing data
set learn how to infer the desired
results without explicit programming of
rules about those results so let's get
coding I'm going to start with an
asynchronous function called do iris
which I will call at the end of my
JavaScript block in the previous episode
we created the iris JS file that
contained the data and all the code we
wrote to pre-process it this was
orchestrated through a function called
get iris data which took a parameter
that dictated the split between training
and test data
by setting it to point to we're saying
that 80% of the data will be for
training and 20% for test so let's call
that and we'll get back our X train why
train X test and Y test values now we'll
create a model by calling a train model
function and passing them as parameters
to it we haven't yet created that so
let's do it now we'll start by making
this function asynchronous were awaiting
its return after all then we'll create
our model in the same way as before
it's a sequential network next we'll set
up a couple of values for our learning
rate and the number of epochs or
iterations that we want to run the
machine learning for it's nice to have
these as constants so we can tweak them
later the learning rate is used to
define the optimizer and if you remember
in episode 1 we use stochastic gradient
descent this time we'll use a different
one and it's called an Adam optimizer
there's lots of ways of optimizing
machine learning and Adam was introduced
as a methodology in 2015 as an
improvement over stochastic gradient
descent it's actually built into tensor
flow so you just have to turn it on but
if you want the details about it you can
find them on the archive.org site now
let's create our model there's an art in
how you define your neural network and
you can experiment with different
combinations for better or faster
results but in this case I'm going to
use two layers the first has ten neurons
and the second has three the first layer
is activated by something called a
sigmoid function I won't go into all the
math of that now but the important thing
to note is that a sigmoid function for
all inputs will provide an output
between 0 and 1 which is perfect for
classification ie
0 means it doesn't match and 1 means it
matches the second or output layer will
have three units and I do this because
we're classifying to three different
types of flour
its activation is softmax which is a
function that normalizes its input
values so that they all add up to 1 that
way when we get our classification it
will be a likelihood for each flower but
the three likelihoods will add up to 1
we can then compile our model with this
optimizer and the desired loss function
as well as the metric that we want to
read the last function this time is
called categorical cross entropy and
again without getting on mathy about it
I've found that when you want to
categorize something as we're doing in
this case picking between different
types of flour instead of predicting a
value like a house price then using this
loss function instead of something like
root-mean-square works much better ok
now we have our model it's time to Train
it will do this with the model dot fit
method passing it our training and our
validation data will also specify the
number of epochs that we want to run the
training for to keep track of its
progress we actually get a callback
called on epoch end in this we can print
our current loss value and when I run it
you'll see this value diminish epoch by
epoch
it's really as simple as that for
training and when we're done we'll have
a model that can classify the input data
so let's now take a look at using the
model to do a prediction
we've only trained this model for a
little time only 40 epochs so we may
have some errors and we'll see how to
fix that later
so here I've created a tensor with a
bunch of input values that match those
of one of the items in the real data
will pass this model to get a prediction
back and hopefully we get the same
result so let's run it you'll see that
we get three values determining the
likelihood of which flower matches the
tensor and it looks like number two is
closest to being the winner but let's
see how we can make that even clearer
now here's the same prediction but using
the Arg max function to polarize the
values effectively setting the
likelihood for flower zero and one to
nothing and flower two to one think of
that as similar to writing a few if-then
statements to compare the values to find
the biggest and think about how much
easier it is then if you were doing this
with a thousand different values and the
number of code that you would have to
write so if you want to test your model
against the test set to see how many it
gets right versus how many it gets wrong
you can then do so with this code for
each X in the test set get the
prediction and then compare it against
the real Y if it's the same you're right
if it's different you're wrong if you
get a very high error rate then you can
tweak the epochs and the learning rate
from earlier and try again
so that's it for this episode of coding
tensorflow
if you've watched these three episodes
and followed along you'll have taken
your first steps into machine learning
in the browser with javascript if you
prefer to go beyond the browser and use
your JavaScript skills with something
like nodejs instead you can still do so
learn more about that and everything
javascript related on jsr tensorflow dot
org if you have any questions please
leave them in the comments below don't
forget to hit that subscribe button for
more great tensorflow content
you
[Music]