hi everybody and welcome to tents Flo
meets in this episode I'm meeting with
Christian fan Li Ramsey who's been doing
some crazy stuff with neuroscience and a
whole new term called affective
computing that you're going to learn all
about welcome Christian thanks I'm glad
to be here so we did have another
episode with your partner how and where
she was talking a lot about diet ex
machina and I know you're working on
that too could you tell us about it sure
sure so diet ex machina is again the
diet part is about two as one so it's
seen two is one and then the machinae is
about really us working alongside a
machine so it's really a fancy way to
say to people working with a machine
nice and so what we're trying to build
out is this effective layer and to us it
means that well currently as it stands
if you look at the neuroscience
literature emotion is just as important
it's cognition okay but in today's
society we seem to value cognition over
emotion then we're kind of like throw
their emotions away get them out of here
Larry : yes make a reasonable decision
but it turns out that to make a
reasonable decision you actually have to
have a marker write an emotional marker
that tells you that's the right answer
and that one's not the right answer
interesting and so we're kind of trying
to build this affective layer to bring
emotion back to the forefront of what
what the everyday life is or really like
okay so I can give you an example of
that okay let's imagine we're working on
the team and you've got all of a sudden
this great idea that you want to tell
everyone about and what's going to
happen is most likely you're gonna have
sympathetic projections down from your
autonomic nervous system okay your blood
pressure is going to rise the skin
temperature is going to rise a little
bit of sweat is gonna secrete from your
sweat glands sounds like I shall have
good ideas and it's actually your body's
way of getting you ready to say what you
need to say okay and in that moment
maybe a couple of seconds later you
might have some thoughts like well what
if I said this and everyone thought it
was stupid or what if I said this and
everyone thought this isn't a great idea
and all of a sudden I've got like brain
regions like the periodical gray or even
the beloved amygdala are going off at
that time and those emotions are so
strong that well I'm not gonna say
anything right okay and
in a couple of days later someone says
it has a positive reaction in here and
now I'm thinking about it and now I'm
ruminating and now I'm filling really
complex emotions like - like resentment
or regret or even envy right and so it's
like how do we actually bring that
emotional journey and make it live for
that person to understand the journey
that they're taking with the things in
their lives or even the relations with
other people and so that's really what
the affective layer is about it is about
awareness making people more aware of
that okay so one of the things you
mentioned on your sites that I really
caught my eye was like you're working at
the intersection of affective computing
and deep learning and so what is that
intersection and habitat yeah I think
that's a really good question a long
time ago we started studying the emotion
and really affective neuroscience which
has been largely at first emotions were
like oh it's a psychological construct
and like yes sort of and then you had
people like yak ping SAP and Antonio
Damasio neuroscientists who showed like
no actually these three brain regions in
some sort of temporal fashion unveil
when you get the emotion of something
like seeking or rage and so they were
able to do the necessary research to
show that emotions were in fact real and
they were real science and you could
actually study them and most of that was
done in like rodents and and then
eventually to humans by looking at
patients who had lesions in certain
parts of their brain and they couldn't
have certain types of emotions okay and
it pointed directly to that and so the
affective neuroscience for us the part
is looking at the deep learning part is
how do you understand a physiological
signal like heart rate and heart rate is
largely modulated by the central nervous
by your brain right right and so what
you want to know is what effective say
this happening in your brain that
eventually transmits down to you having
a higher or a lower heart rate I see and
so we're in trying to model that that's
what you're modeling when you're trying
to model emotion you're trying to model
something that's happening in the brain
so we thought we needed to understand
that so that we could better model these
emotions so that's where the crossroad
and I think tensorflow points out a
really good
almost the complexity of classifying
those emotions is you've got to have
something like a deep learning neuron
that and you got to have even pushing
state-of-the-art like attention networks
and going further and tensorflow
provides that for us
interesting so you've been using tensor
flow quite a bit yes thank you
so and so like just trying to get my
hands around this would be that so when
you can understand the emotions of a
person maybe using a product that will
help you build a better product and
design something because you're
reflecting their emotions all right
right right it's like anytime you're
trying to model something there's this
there's this unknown right part that
your model can't predict is why you
can't get a hundred percent on every
model that you put out there and a lot
of that could be definitely subject to
like the users emotion at that time why
they choose to play the game at that
time rather than another time could also
be like their stress levels were high
and they wanted to play video games or
maybe the opposite but knowing that
gives you that indicator like you're
saying of what their state is and what
they're motivated to do at that time so
it's it's going to be another tool and a
developer's toolbox to help them build
better products exactly exactly we hope
that everyone has access to this
effective layer oh now I know you're
also looking for people to help out with
this right so could you tell us a little
about that sure the effective layer is
massive and if you just look at all the
literature and affective neuroscience
effective competing it's so much work
has been done but yet there's so much
left to do and we're not gonna tackle it
alone we do wish we could say that but
we're going to need partners and work
with people so we think of it as there's
people at the research end of the
spectrum and the applications end of the
spectrum in the research there's a lab
out of Stanford that focuses just on
fear right and so they're just looking
at the physiological outputs of fear
when you see a stimulus that scares you
right okay and so we could actually
partner with a lab like that or any such
lab and say okay how do we bring this
into deep learning and how do we make
some sort of continuous algorithm or
tension network that's deployed in the
cloud to where people who have affective
disorders with anxiety or fear anything
like that we could be predicting when
they're going to be fearful of what and
then help them get better from that
interesting and then on the application
side I think there's a lot of developers
to work with who want to create this
kind of effective computing stuff but
may not have the requisite or like
background or studying in the affective
or emotion sciences and there we can
help out by saying okay how would you
label something like discussed like
difficult and set up the right
experiment to be able or the labeling
process and help with that and then the
last part I think is like thinking of
organizations if you want to get the
effective like style of your team or
something like that and so we could work
with a company to see and it's going to
be able to further the research on the
affective layer but also give insights
to whoever whoever we're working with
right so affective computing it's a
phrase most of us probably haven't heard
of right now but maybe all of us will be
using it in the not-too-distant future
that would be great wouldn't it be cool
thanks Christian and thanks everybody
for watching this episode of tensorflow
meats if you have any questions for me
if you have any questions for Christian
just please leave them in the comments
below and don't forget to hit that
subscribe button thank you
you