[Music]
earlier this year we hit the milestone
of 11 million downloads you're really
excited to see how much users are using
this in how much impact it's having in
the world I'm very excited to say that
we have been working with other teams in
Google to bring tensorflow Lite to
Google Apps
so if retentive flow is also an early
stage project and so we'd really love
for you to get interested and help us to
build this future told you at the
beginning that our mission for Kiev data
was to make a library for him food
processing that is fast flexible and
easy to use we're very excited today to
announce that the plan Jas is joining
the Tanza flow family in general but the
Google brain teams mission is to make
machines intelligent and then use that
ability to improve people's lives I
think these are good examples of where
there's real opportunity for this
[Music]