[Music]
hello everybody this is Laurence Moroney
I'm here at the tensorflow developer
summit were in the tensorflow cafe and
have jeremiah with me all the way from
Zurich that's right it's been an
exciting trip so all the way from Zurich
and you announced TF hub tensorflow hub
at your talk so tell me all about it
tester flow hub is something we're
really excited about we realised that we
want to help people
reuse machine learning which anything is
really hard to do you need a lot of
stuff so we're letting people package up
good machine learning and share it with
the world
okay now you built this in Zurich right
we did we did this is our first big
infrastructure project there we've been
growing Google research to Europe we
have a brain team there that's been
growing and our applied machine
intelligence team is also growing quick
nice nice now so this TF hub it's almost
like a natural extension to some of the
things we've been doing on github right
where we have like model repository and
github but you're taking a lot further
right right certainly sharing models
isn't anything new the big difference
here is that we realize that when you
share a model either fits your problem
exactly okay
or it doesn't you can't use it okay you
can either give it the inputs at once
and take the outputs if you want to do
anything outside that you're sunk
alright so tensorflow hub
gives you smaller pieces so it's more
likely you can reuse them I think the
way to think about it is a model is like
a binary okay a module is like a library
okay
a model is a binary and a module is a
library that's right
we need that on a t-shirt that's right
that's right so where can I find all
these where is tensor hug word where
does that live ten to five checkout
tensorflow org flash hub tend to float
that's easy to remember so what kind of
models are on there well we've got all
kinds of things we certainly have ones
for image processing things that will
let you help or help you build your own
image classifiers if you use tensorflow
for poets we've really taken that
process and streamlined it down to
really a single line of Python so we've
got all kinds of all kinds of models
some of the newer ones include the
neural architecture search models that
are really state-of-the-art
as Andrew mentioned in his talk those
are incredible because with that one
line up
Python you actually get over 60,000
hours of GPU training when it's
discovering the architecture and
training it so it's pretty powerful so
one line gives me 60,000 hours worth of
training use 60,000 GPU hours yep
there's the image ones we've also got
some really exciting text ones where you
can give it the entire sentence and it
will give you back a vector that
characterizes it and again we can do
that same tensorflow for poets trick
where we build a classifier on top of it
and one of the ones we're really excited
about is the universal sentence encoder
this is a paper that just came out on
Archive last night so it's just hot off
the presses and it's great to see people
that can use it instantly just by
clicking on the TF hub link that's in
the paper so what is it all about the
universal sentence encoder so this is
some new work that is doing things like
letting you understand the semantic
differences between different sentences
it actually works on a sentence level
which is a little bit different than
word Tyvek a lot of those you just look
up a single word but this will take the
entire sentence and consider that as it
builds this characterization in the form
of an embedding now remember always that
what was it the fruit flies like bananas
have you heard of that that's right
that's right that's the exact problem
it's solving oh cool I have to look that
up so what was it called again that's
the universal sentence encoder and
that's on TF hub already it's there
ready for you to use it oh wow gotta
check it out so now if I'm like a
specialist in building models in some
scenario I don't know what the scenario
is and I want to contribute you know how
would I go about doing that
yeah we're really excited we're working
very quickly to make it possible for
other people to upload and share these
things I think that's something that's
really important to us certainly as
talented as we are inside Google you
know answer who is really a global
community and there's the wisdom of
crowds right there's there's a lot of
people who know stuff that we don't know
and they can that's right that's right
cool so thank you so much this has been
so much fun and I've learned so much
already so I really want to try some of
these models Liam told me about so thank
you Jeremiah that's been fun and thanks
everybody for watching this episode if
you've got any questions for me if
you've got any questions for Jeremiah
please leave them in the comments below
and if you're looking for any of the
links we spoke about we'll put them in
the description and whatever you do
don't forget to hit that subscribe
button like
so much
[Music]