[Music]
if you've ever wanted to do step-by-step
debugging of tensorflow projects but you
didn't know how check out this video
we're in just a couple of minutes I'll
get you set up to use it with the
PyCharm IDE if you're like me and you
like to write a few lines of code at a
time and then step through them to make
sure that they behave properly but
you're stuck a little bit with doing
that with Python and tensorflow then
this video is for you here I have a very
simple hello world type application
where I'm going to train a model and
then run inference on it so here I'm
feeding the model with a set of X's and
Y's and there's a relationship between x
and y it's a linear relationship and if
you think about it you'll see that y
equals 2x minus 1 so for example if x
equals 4 2x minus 1 is 7 when x equals 3
2x minus 1 is 5 etc etc so with only
just a few points of data I'm going to
train a model and note that I'm not
telling it the formula I'm just training
it on data and then I'll try to infer
from that what the Y value should be
when x equals 10 now we know that that's
19 but what will the model and fare so
let's take a look at debugging it I'm
going to set a breakpoint and just like
I would with Android studio or Visual
Studio I can run and debug the debugger
will launch and now you can see I'm in
step-by-step debugging so here I have my
model and if I click step to step over
it I've created it and I can even take a
peek inside of it here I add my layer
and it's just one with one node so it's
not really a network but it's more like
a single neuron and now I can step over
the compilation of the model and
specifying the loss and optimizer
functions for my X's and Y's you can see
that they're numpy arrays so when I step
over them I can inspect those it
directly in the debugger so now when I
run model dot fit and I'm passing my X's
and Y's in I can see that the correct
data is being passed into the training
of the network so if something goes
wrong I know it's not because of the
so now when I step over that we can see
the training take place now I have a
trained model so I can step to the next
line and start looking at predicting
values based on that model so let's
predict values for 10 11 12 and 13 and
when I run model predict on these values
and print it out we can see the answers
in the console the results are pretty
close for 10 I would have expected 19
and for 11 I would get 21 but you can
see that the model is getting very very
close to that so that's today's tip
using the step by step debugger it was a
very simple scenario but it really helps
demystify some of the stuff that goes on
in a tensorflow application it's
amazingly useful particularly as you
prepare your data for training to be
able to inspect it so give it a try
[Music]