hi everybody and welcome to the tense
flow developer summit I'm Laurence
Moroney and I'm here at the tensorflow
cafe and it's my great honor to speak
with Mustafa sp
you just did a talk at the summit on
estimators and hiking and lots of
different things and you know I was part
of the rehearsals for his talk and I
could chat with him for hours about this
stuff but we've only got a few minutes
so that's good we have a couple so I
just like to ask about some of the
highlights you're hiking scenario could
you tell us about that first so you know
I want to make it an example so that a
practitioner can understand or feel I've
come all of these api's fit well in the
journey of machine learning and I do
like that you think of a machine
learning as a journey not a destination
yeah it's a journey it's never-ending
journey and it's an exciting journey and
the focus of your talk was really about
estimators and about pre-made estimators
pyramid estimators tell us how to
combine these two these things I think
the main lion can be summarized as
experimenting your ideas we take couple
of lines of code so how can you do that
experiment with your ideas with only a
couple of lines of code I like that so
and one of the things you also shared
was just how much estimators are
actually used hearing yeah it's you know
I personally I'm surprised to today
wow it's so popular here and it's and I
personally have some of the projects to
use these estimators and learn from them
and the feedback we got from all of
these different use cases it really
helped us like we see their pain or they
are trying to do this but now this
partitioning is not going well so that's
why the training is so slow
so how can we fix it to be so all those
things or like I worked on the on a team
where we were using machine learning
before to improve a product and at that
time I realized experimenting with
features is the one of the most
important thing right so that's why we
all the pathology experience under the
APS
right because it one of the things in
your talk is you were talking about
feature columns and proper use of
feature columns could help reduce your
lines of code could you give us an
example so yeah that's the thing I
mentioned in that project then I wasn't
there so like what they always have
ideas about features oh how can I use
this feature for example this hiking
example let's think about how you
example
oh I I can use the zip code of user
lifting providing that website right so
I'm can use that like let's make it easy
so that's kind of stuff we work on right
now as well as machine learning we
always think of like this you can have
trees for decisions as well yeah you
introduced this concept of gradient
boosted trees yeah which I want a
t-shirt without my other estimator is a
gradient boosted tree could you tell us
about them whatever we got a lot of
requests like and based on the survey
take a survey like this is really
popular and for example is stable it's
not random like it wasn't like one
bunting with tip learning every time we
trended the model you may get a
different model because of the random
civilizational but the scene trees are
always provide you the same so you can
so there are a bunch of good stuff with
that so we worked hard create this
pyramid estimator so that it should not
be difficult for people if they want to
experiment with no network or trees but
if you don't have pyramid estimator you
need to switch to another pipeline you
need to create another input function
like so that's messed up so we are
solving that hopefully it sounds good
I'm looking forward to trying them out I
do it's one of the things that it's on
my very long to do this and but like you
say it just works hopefully
I think use that phrase several times
but I also said it may ever I mean you
need to experiment so we don't know I
feel like fermentation you don't know
which one really fits well into your
problem so there's a quote from Peter
Norvig he was saying very famous kid oh
yeah he's he's saying machine learning
changes are like how we look at the
engineering because normally you build
something based on the mathematical
rules and you provide that as a solution
but in this case it's becoming more
natural science so you need to
experiment to understand and you need to
analyze the output based on the
statistical thinking so it is different
than like hey this will work for you and
I'm adding this thing and it will work
for you no we cannot say you need to
experiment right okay so becoming more
more scientific right experiment
evaluate the results form a hypothesis
and then you test the hypothesis in the
experiment again alright so switching
gears for a second one of the things
that you also talking about that really
intrigued me and I still need to get my
head around is transfer learning well
you can take like the learning from one
graph and it effectively chocolate
changer to transfer to another this
surprising that that is simple and works
so you can't like this is it it just
works so at the first time I was really
surprised to know I'm copying all these
variables from here to there and it
works how come so then I realized that
network learns a transformation but if
you think layer by layer transformation
and and we are leveraging that those
transformations in my other network and
my other network because of retraining
on top of it as an advantage of can
decide how can they how can it uses the
transformation or not like whether it
helps or not so it can it has a room to
the south that's
pretty : it's just the possibilities of
like some experts in one area being able
to train a model and experts in another
area being able to train a different
model and in chopping changes transfer
yeah I also like give a big shout to TF
hub so they make it one line like that
with the one line you are accessing one
of the best model trained in Google this
that's so powerful it only seems too
good to be true yes if I want to take
advantage of this and I want things to
just work for me what recommendation
would hopefully recommendation would you
give me to get started with the transfer
learning transfer learning gradient
boosted trees estimators all of these
things so we are putting examples under
we called module garden or official
model examples at github and github so
you can start with those examples
because an example as data and some
training parameters so when you start
with that example then you can put your
own data into it slow by slow so I think
starting with an example is the best way
to so take a look at those in the models
garden yes I like that but outside is I
think the official models yeah so much
nicer and you can have some gradient
boosted trees in your garden yes and
yeah it's not out there yet the example
but we are adding the example that
sounds good well thank you so much my
staff at this is Ben
I want to have more hours to do this but
well maybe do more video and thanks
everybody for watching this episode if
you have any questions for me or if you
have any questions for former staffer
please just leave them in the comments
below and don't forget to hit that
subscribe button thank you
[Music]
you