thank you so much for coming to our
session this morning I'm Sarah Sarah
Javon I'm on the tensorflow Lite team
and we work on bringing machine learning
to mobile and small devices and later on
I will introduce my colleague Andrew
celli who will be doing the second half
of this talk so the last couple of days
have been really fun for me I've gotten
to meet and speak with many of you and
it's been really nice to see the
excitement around tensorflow light and
today I'm happy to be here and talk to
you about all the work that our team is
doing to make machine learning on small
devices possible and easy so in today's
talk we'll cover three areas first we'll
talk about why machine learning directly
on device is important and how it's
different than what you may do on the
server second we'll walk you through
what we have built with tons of low
light and lastly we'll show you how you
can use sense of low light in your own
apps so first let's talk about devices
for a bit what do we mean when we say a
device well
usually a mobile device basically our
phones so our phones are with us all the
time we interact with them so many times
during the day and modern phones come
with a large number of sensors on them
which give us really rich data about the
physical world around us another
category of devices is what we call edge
devices and this industry has seen a
huge explosion in the last few years so
some examples are smart speakers smart
watches smart cameras and as this market
has grown we see that technology which
only used to be available on more
expensive devices is now available on
far cheaper ones so now we are seeing
that there is this massive growth in
devices they're becoming in
freezingly capable both mobile and edge
and this is opening up many
opportunities for novel applications of
for machine learning so I expect that
many of you are already familiar with
the basic idea of machine learning but
for those that aren't I'm going to
really quickly cover the core concept so
let's start with an example of something
that we may want to do let's say
classification of images so how do we do
this so in the past what we would have
done was to write a lot of rules that
were hard coded very specific about some
specific characteristics that we
expected to see in parts of the image
this was time consuming hard to do and
frankly didn't work all that well and
this is where machine learning comes in
we with machine learning we learned
based on examples so a simple way to
think about machine learning is that we
use algorithms to learn from data and
then we make predictions about similar
data that has not been seen before so
it's a two-step process first the model
learns and then we use it to make
predictions the process of model
learning is what we typically call
training and when the model is making
predictions about data is what we call
inference this is a high-level view of
what's happening during training the
model is passed in label data that is
input data along with The Associated
prediction and since in this case we
know what the right answer is we are
able to calculate the error that is how
many times is the model getting it wrong
and by how much we use these errors to
improve the model and this process is
repeated many many times until we reach
the point that we think that the model
is good enough or that this is the best
that we can do this involves a lot of
steps and coordination and that is why
we need a framework to make this easier
and this is where tensorflow comes in
it's Google's framework for machine
learning it makes it easy to train and
build neural networks and it is
cross-platform it works on CPUs GPUs TP
use as well as mobile and embedded
platforms and the mobile and embedded
piece of tensorflow
which we call tensorflow lite is what we
are going to be focusing on in our talk
today so now we want to talk about why
would you consider doing machine
learning directly on device and there
are several reasons that you may
consider but probably the most important
one is latency if the processing is
happening on the device then you're not
sending data back and forth to the
server so if your use case involves real
time processing of data such as audio or
video then it's quite likely that you
would consider doing this other reasons
are that your processing can happen even
when your device is not connected on to
the Internet the data stays on device
this is really useful if you're working
with sensitive user data which you don't
want to put on servers it's more power
efficient because your device is not
spending power transmitting data back
and forth and lastly we are in a
position to take advantage of all the
sensor data that's already available and
accessible on the device so this is all
great but there's a catch like there
always is and the catch is that doing on
device ml is hard many of these devices
have some pretty tight constraints they
have small batteries tight memory and
very little computation power tensorflow
was built for processing on the server
and it wasn't a great fit for these use
cases and that is the reason that we
built tensorflow light it's a
lightweight
machine learning library for mobile and
embedded platforms so this is a
high-level overview of the system it
consists of a kind
where we convert models from tensorflow
format to tons of low light format and
for efficiency reasons we use a format
which is different then it consists of
an interpreter which runs on device
there are a library of ups and kernels
and then we have api's which allow us to
take advantage of hardware acceleration
whenever it is available tensorflow Lite
is cross-platform so it works on Android
iOS Linux and a high level developer
workflow here would be to take a train
tensorflow model converted to tensorflow
Lite format and then update your apps to
use the tensorflow Lite interpreter
using the appropriate API an iOS
developers also have the option of using
core ml instead and what they would do
here is to take their train tensorflow
model and convert it to core ml using
the tensorflow - core mm converter and
then use the converted model with the
core ml runtime so the two common
questions that we get when we talk to
developers about tensorflow Lite is is
it small and is it fast so let's talk
about the first question one of our
fundamental design goals with tensorflow
Lite was to keep the memory and binary
size small and I'm happy to say that the
size of our core interpreter is only 75
kilobytes and when you include all the
support adopts this size is 400
kilobytes so how did we do this so first
of all we've been really careful about
which dependencies we include secondly
tensorflow light uses flood buffers
which are far more memory efficient than
protocol buffers are one other feature
that I want to call out here intensive
low light is what we call selective
registration and that allows developers
to only use the ops that their model
needs and thus they can keep the
footprint small now moving on to the
second question which is of speed so we
made several design choices throughout
the system
to enable fast start of low latency and
high throughput so let's start with the
model file format tensorflow light uses
flatbuffers like I said and flatbuffers
is a cross-platform
efficient serialization library it was
originally created at Google for game
development and is now being used for
other performance sensitive applications
the advantage of using flatbuffers
is that we can directly access the data
without doing parsing or unperson of the
large files which contain weights
another thing that we do at the time of
conversion is that we pre fuse the
activations and biases and this leads to
faster execution later at runtime the
tensorflow Lite interpreter uses a
static memory and static execution plan
this leads to faster load times many of
the kernels that tensorflow light comes
with have been specially optimized to
run fast only on unarmed CPUs now let's
talk about hardware acceleration as
machine learning has grown in prominence
it has felt quite a bit of innovation at
the silicon layer as well and many
hardware companies are investing in
building custom chips which can
accelerate neural network processing
GPUs and DSPs which have been around for
some time are also now being
increasingly used to do machine learning
tasks tensorflow Lite was designed to
take advantage of hardware acceleration
whether it is through GPUs DSPs or
custom AI chips on Android the recently
released Android neural network API is
an abstraction layer which makes it easy
for tensorflow Lite to take advantage of
the underlying acceleration and the way
this works is that hardware vendors
write specialized drivers or custom
acceleration code for their hardware
platforms and integrate with the Android
and API
tensorflow light in turn integrates with
the Android and an API via its internal
delegation API a point to note here is
that developers only need to integrate
their apps with tensorflow light
tensorflow light will take care of
abstracting away the details of hardware
acceleration from them in addition to
the Android and an API we are also
working on building direct GPU
acceleration in tensorflow light GPUs
are widely available and used and like I
said before they are now being
increasingly used for doing machine
learning tasks similar to era an API
developers only integrate with
tensorflow light if they want to take
advantage of the GPU acceleration so the
last bit on performance that I want to
talk about is quantization and this is a
good example of an optimization which
cuts across several components in our
system so first of all what is
quantization a simple way to think about
it is that it refers to techniques to
store numbers and to perform
calculations or numbers in formats that
are more compact than 32-bit
floating-point representations and why
is this important well for two reasons
first model size is a concern for small
devices so the smaller the model the
better it is secondly there are many
processors which have specialized sim D
instruction sets which process fixed
point numbers much faster than they
process floating-point numbers so the
next question here is how much accuracy
do we lose if we are using eight bits or
16 bits instead of the 32 bits which are
used for representing floating-point
numbers well the answer obviously
depends on which model that we are using
but in general the learning process is
robust to noise and quantization can be
thought of as a form of noise so what we
find is that the accuracy is 10
to be usually within acceptable
thresholds a simple way of doing
quantization is to shrink the weights
and biases after training and we are
shortly going to be releasing a tool
which developers can use to shrink the
size of their models in addition to that
we have been actively working on doing
quantization at training time and this
is an active area of ongoing research
and what we find here is that we are
able to get accuracies which are
comparable to the floating-point models
for architectures like mobile light as
well as inception and we recently
release a tool which allows developers
to use this and we are working on adding
support for more models in this okay so
I talked about a bunch of performance
optimizations now let's talk about what
does it translate to in terms of numbers
so we benchmark to models mobile lat and
Inception v3 or the pixel tool and as
you can see here we are getting speed
ups of more than three times when we
compare quantized models running on
tensorflow light versus floating-point
models running on tensorflow I'll point
out here that these numbers do not
include any hardware acceleration we
have done some initial benchmarking with
hardware acceleration and we see
additional speed ups of three to four
times with that which is really
promising and exciting so stay tuned in
the next few months to hear more on that
now that I've talked about the design of
tensor flow and performance I want to
show you what tensor flow light can do
in practice let's please roll the video
so this is a simple demo application
which is running the mobile net
classification model which we trained on
common office objects and as you can see
it's doing a good job detecting them
even this tensorflow logo that we
trained this model on like I said it's
cross-platform so it's running on iOS as
well as Android and we also are running
it here on Android things this was a
simple demo we have more exciting demos
for you later on in the talk now let's
talk about production use cases I'm
happy to say that we've been working
with partner teams inside Google to
bring tons of low-light to Google Apps
so portrait mode on Android camera hey
Google and Google assistant and smart
reply are some features which are going
to be powered by tensorflow light in the
next few months
additionally tensorflow light is the
machine learning engine which is
powering the custom model functionality
in the newly announced ml kit and for
those of you that may have missed the
announcement mo kit is a machine
learning SDK it exposes both on device
and cloud powered api's for machine
learning as well as the ability to bring
your own custom models and use them
these are some examples of apps that are
already using tensorflow lite VRML kit
picsArt it's a really popular photo
editing in collage making app and visco
it's a really cool photography app so
back to tensorflow light and what is
currently supported so we have support
for 50 commonly used operations which
developers can use in their own models I
will point out here that if you need an
app which is not currently supported you
do have the option of using what we call
a custom up and using that and later on
in this talk Andrew will show you how
you can do that up support is currently
limited to inference we will be working
on adding training support in the future
we support several common popular open
source models
as well as the quantized counterparts
for some of them and with this I'm going
to invite my colleague Andrew to talk to
you about how you can use tensor flow
light in your own apps thanks Sara
[Applause]
[Music]
so now that you know what tentacle light
is and what it can do and where it can
be run I'm sure you know you want to
know how to use it so we can break that
up into four important steps the first
one it and probably the most important
is get a model you need to decide what
you want to do it could be image
classification
it could be object detection or it could
be even speech recognition whatever that
model is you need to train it yourself
you can do that with tentacle just like
you trained any other tensor flow model
or you can download a pre train model if
you're not ready to make your own model
yet or if an existing model satisfies
your needs second you need to convert
your model from tensor flow to tensor
fold light and we'll show some examples
of how to do that in a second third if
there's any custom ops that you need to
write this could be because you want to
spot optimize something with some
special instructions you know about or
it could be that you're using a piece of
functionality that we do not yet support
like a specialized piece of signal
processing whatever it might be you can
write your ops this may not be necessary
of course the last step is to write an
app and you're going to use whatever
client API is appropriate for the target
platform so let's dive into some code
converting your tenth of a model once
you're done with a tensorflow training
you typically have a saved model or you
might have a graph desk what you need to
do first is put this through the
converter so here I'm showing how to do
this within Python so if you download
the normal tensorflow to Lane
that's pre-compiled like the pip you're
able to run the the converter and it
just takes a save model directory in or
a frozen graph def and it you specify a
file name of what TF Lite file you want
and that will output a flat buffer
that's on disk that you can now ship to
whatever device you want now how much
you get it to the device
you could put it into the package you
could also say distribute it through a
cloud service where you can update your
model on the fly without updating your
core application whatever you want to do
is possible so next once you've
converted well you might actually run
into some issues doing a conversion
because there's a couple of things that
can go wrong so the first one is you
need to make sure that you have a frozen
graft F or a save model both of these
are able to get rid of the parts of the
graph that are used for training these
are typically things like variable
assignment variable initialization
optimization passes these are not
strictly necessary for doing inference
that is prediction so you want to get
rid of those out of the graph because we
don't want to support those operations
right now because we want to have the
smallest version of the runtime that can
be distributed to keep your binary size
small the second thing that you need to
do is make sure that you write any
custom operators that you need and now
I'll go into a little bit of an example
of doing that well before that let me
tell you one more thing which is we also
have some visualizers let you understand
the model that you've transformed and
the transformation process so take a
look at those they're linked off of the
documentation so let's get into writing
a custom op so what kind of optimized we
need well here I have an example that's
a little bit silly but it's to return
pie so the important thing when you
write an op is that you need to
implement for C functions so we have a C
API for defining operations and the
reason we do this is that all of our
operations are implemented in this way
so they can run on devices that only
support C eventually but you can write
kernels in C++ in this case what I'm
doing is I'm ignoring the input tensors
and I'm putting an output tensor which
is M pi now if you had input tensors and
you wanted to make a an output tensor
you could also read the input tensors
and then say oh x 3 and now I have a x 3
operation this was going to be
application dependent and of course as I
said before you don't always need to do
this I'm just laying this out here to
show that if there's some functionality
that you need
we are extensible
okay once you've converted your model
you need to use a client API let me
start with the C++ API but we have other
language bindings as well that I'll get
to and but in any of the bindings it's
going to follow the same basic pattern
the pattern is create an interpreter and
load the model fill in your data execute
the model and read back your data so
it's very simple so in the C++ API the
first thing you do is create a model
object and this is given the file name
of the tensorflow light file and it
creates an object that is going to hold
that model and M map it so as I said
before we use flat buffers and the
reason why is that we can M map the
buffers which means that there is zero
latency to start running the model
effectively okay
second if you have any custom operations
you can register them so basically at
this phase you're deciding which
operations to include into your runtime
by default we provide a built in op
resolver that's that includes all of our
default operations you might also use
selective registration that we alluded
to before where you include only a
subset of the operations in this case
you might provide a minimal resolver and
if you wanted to use the custom
operation that we had before you would
create a custom resolver that would tell
tensive row light how to find your
custom operation so now we know what our
ops are and where to get the code for
them and we know our model now we need
to create an interpreter object so we
take the pair of model and resolver and
put it together and it returns an
interpreter this interpreter is going to
be our handle for doing our execution so
the next step is we're going to perform
our execution but before we can do that
we need to fill the buffer so if you
have a model like a classification model
that is something that takes an image in
where are you going to get that image
well the obvious place you might get it
would be from your devices storage if
it's an image file name but also
commonly would be a camera whatever it
might be you produce a like a buffer in
in this class it's gonna be a floats
hour and an in star buffer and you fill
it in to our buffer and once you fill
this buffer you're ready to run so we
filled our buffer
tensa for light has all the information
it needs to run the the execution and we
just call invoke now it's going to block
until that execution is done and then
we're going to be able to read the
output of it in and in an analogous way
to our input so that is we can get a
float star buffer out which could
represent the class numbers and then
you're free to do with that data
whatever you want so for example in an
image classification app that we showed
before you would read that index out map
it back to a string and then put it into
your gooeys display great so now we know
how to use C++ what if you're using
another platform for example raspberry
pi on raspberry pi the most common thing
to use is probably Python and again it's
gonna follow the same basic pattern
first we create an interpreter object
the interpreter object is now our handle
how do we feed data
well since it's Python we can use numpy
arrays and this is really convenient
because if you'd need to do
pre-processing or post processing you
can do it with the primitives that
you're familiar with and this is kind of
a theme that goes on that we want to
keep our bindings as idiomatic as
possible in the language that they are
and also keep it performant so in this
case we put in some known PI ray and we
take out some numpy array so that's
Python what if you're writing an Android
app or you want to write an Android
things application then you might use
the Java API so in this case it's the
same thing you take you build an
interpreter give it the file name of the
interpreter it might be from a resource
if you're doing an Android application
and then finally you're gonna fill the
inputs in and and call wrong so one of
the things that we did for the Java API
is that we know that many Java
programmers don't really want to deal
with building their own native library
so in that case you can just use our
Gradle file here which will include our
pre compiled version of tensor faux
light you don't have to download our
source code and even for the tooling
parts where you do the conversion from
tensorflow to tensor of light you can
download the pre compiled version of of
tensorflow as i alluded to before great
so what if you're doing iOS well in that
case you can use the C post will say be
API you can also use the Objective C API
but again we
a precompiled binary in the form of a
cocoa pod okay so now that you know how
to use tensor for life I want to tell
you a little bit about what's going to
be coming up intensive row light one
thing that we've haven't been asked for
a lot is adding more operations so the
more operations that we add the more
models can be run from tensorflow out of
the box the other thing that happens
with machine learning that's often
difficult is that researchers come up
with new techniques all the time and
that means that tensorflow is always
adding operations that means that we're
going to continue to follow tensor flow
as it adds important operations and add
them into tensor for light as well okay
the second thing we're going to do is
we're going to improve the tooling
provide better documentation and
tutorials and try to focus on ease of
use so it's really easy for you to
understand on end-to-end examples how to
integrate tensor flow life and the third
thing which sara already mentioned but
I'll mention again is that we're excited
about on device training on device
training is really exciting because it
allows us to refine a model based on a
user's experience it allows us to
decouple that experience from going to
the cloud so if they're disconnected we
can and continue improving the model so
there's a lot of requests for this this
of course will require more and more
computation on the device but we're
excited about upcoming upcoming hardware
accelerators that will make this more
and more possible okay one more question
before we get into some exciting demos
when should I use 10 circle light
so as we alluded to before we're
starting to use tensorflow light for our
first party applications and thirty
third party applications are also using
it that means that what we're doing
moving forward is that we're going to
make ten circle light our standard
solution for running ml on small devices
and mobile devices tensor fly to
tensorflow light currently supports a
subset of tensorflow ops this means that
our recommendation is that you should
use tensor fro light if you can and let
us know
and let us to know about any missing
functionality you need it's not quite
done you probably want to see our demos
so with that I want to show you a video
of retrained models we showed you that
tensorflow go be logo being recognized
this is a common theme that we get which
is people like our pre trained examples
like mobile net but they may not have an
application where they need to tell the
difference between five dog breeds and
many zoo animals they might have an
office scenario where they have markers
and whiteboards and in fact as we were
testing the app we found we had this
issue - it's like we don't have the
classes that are in these pre trained
models so one of the great things that
one of our other tensorflow members
created was something called tensor full
for poets and there was a codelab about
that and it's available online as well
and it basically allows you to take a
pre train image model that has really
good detector ability and put your own
classes into it and I want to show you a
demo app that we created that runs on
the PC and creates ten to full line
models for you so can we go to the video
okay so we showed you before can we
recognize scissors and post-it notes
well let's try it out you always want to
try these models check ok the scissors
looks good right ok great post-it notes
also looks good but what if we had
another object an object that's you know
more common more important like this
metal tensorflow logo this happens in
everyday life right ok let's go take a
look at how this does well it's label
this other that's not very good but the
great thing about machine learning is
that we can fix this and the way we fix
it is we add data so we have our
application we've gone to our training
tab now and now we're going to define a
class called tensorflow and this is
basically short for tentacle logo and
now from our webcam we're gonna click
capture and we're gonna capture a couple
of different perspectives as many as we
can
and ideally you would take it on
different backgrounds so it doesn't
associate the background with it being a
tensor for the logo then I click the
train button and right now it's using
tensorflow to Train the model and you
can see it's converging to a good
validation accuracy it's going to reload
the model and we're testing it intense
or full light running on the PC right
now and
see that it's recognizing tents are full
correctly so it's that fast and easy but
also we can take that model and we can
move to Android and iOS and use the
exact same model and update it so thanks
now let's move to a live demo so I'm
gonna go over here to the podium alright
okay so classification what I just
showed you is kind of this idea that you
have an image in and you put an image
out and you put classifications out but
what if you have multiple objects in the
scene or you have something in a corner
of an object you also want to know where
in the where in the scene that object is
and that enters this model called single
shot detection it's a type of model and
it turns out that our friends in
tentacle research released a package
called object detection as part of the
tentacle models and that basically
allows you to use their pre trained
model that recognizes many classes so
what I've done is I want to load that
onto a small device in this case we're
talking you a lot of things about mobile
devices I want to show you another small
device this is a Raspberry Pi so the
Raspberry Pi is a really cool example of
a device because it's very cheap and
easy to get so any high school student
could have one of these you can have
many of these and just use them for a
dedicated project but the other great
thing about them is not only are they
relatively powerful but they're also
able to interface with other hardware
they have GPIO pins and this this can be
capitalized in a number of different
ways but one way is to run Linux and
that's what we're doing here but you can
also use Android things which you can
see one of the cool sand of the sandbox
has many examples doing that so you
could also do this with Android things
so in this case I have the system the
system board right here and it's
connected to a motor controller and this
motor controller is just a
microcontroller that interfaces to servo
motors these servo motors can go up and
down left and right and they can
basically aim the camera so now what
we're going to do is we're going to load
our object detection model onto this
device and we're gonna actually run it
in order to
recognize different objects so let's go
to the demo feed please and we can see
my app you can tell by the beautiful
nature of this app that I'm not a great
app developer but this is what I can do
on a weekend so give me a little bit of
slack okay so here if we hold up to
Apple it's recognizing the Apple and
it's telling us you know what
probability and where the object is now
that's all good and fine but when we
couple it with the ability to move where
I'm going to turn on the motors now and
now I'm going to bring back the Apple
and what I'm going to do is I'm going to
move the Apple in in the screen and it's
gonna try to keep it centered so as I
move this Apple it's basically going to
try to keep it centered so it's like a
little virtual camera person and this
works on other objects like this banana
here hopefully oh there we go
and it's going to keep that Center and
if you put two objects in the in the
screen it's going to try to keep them
both in okay so so we've got a little
bit of false detection but basically
it's going to try to keep them both
Center so this is really a fun
application and I bet you can come up
with many different applications that
are really exciting to do with this type
of application so can we go back to the
slides again
so I like I said this is basically what
I can do in a weekend but I imagine
great app developers and people with a
lot of creativity about connecting
devices and connecting software can do
many interesting things so what I want
to do now is I want to tell you
in summary tents are full light you've
seen a lot about it basically we feel it
tents or flight makes on device ml small
fast and easy and we think that you're
gonna find it very useful in all of your
applications and we're excited to see
what you build come talk to us I'm going
to be in office hours at 12:30 you can
come talk to me in addition you can come
to our sandbox if you haven't already
and we have of course the examples that
I showed you here we have the the
tracking camera we also have the object
classification on mobile device but
another cool thing that we have is the
donkey cars and this was done by a group
outside of Google and we converted them
over to tensor faux light and we are
excited to say that their application
works really well with tensorflow light
as well so with that I hope you check
these things out I want to tell you that
if you want to get started
you can go to our documentation page you
can go to the tensorflow door page and
there is a TF Lite page where you can
find more information about it in
addition our code is all open source you
can get it on github you can download it
modify it submit a pull request and of
course file any issues that you have
while using it in addition if you want
to talk about tentacle light talk about
your applications ask us about feature
requests please send to our mailing list
this community is really exciting we
found that in open sourcing tensorflow
we got a lot of excitement we got a lot
of interest and we made it a much better
piece of software to use forever in both
people inside Google and outside Google
and we hope that you'll engage tenser
fold light in the same way that
tensorflow has been engaged so with that
I want to thank you for your attention
for coming to i/o for listening to our
talk about tensor pro-lite I also want
to thank you thank our Google partners
this product didn't come out of
isolation
from all of our experience building
mobile apps with machine intelligence as
we gain experience we found that there
was a common need and that was the
genesis of tensor fold light so all of
our partners provided application
provided feedback even provided code and
help with with our models so thank you
so much to you and to them and enjoy the
rest of i/o
[Applause]
[Music]