[Music]
hi everybody and welcome to the
tensorflow cafe at the tensorflow
developer summit I'm Laurence Moroney
and I'm chatting with Patrick Brandt
from the coca-cola company and Patrick
you had a talk here at the summit it
seems to be a really interesting one
yeah yeah about it
sure so I shared how tensorflow is
supporting one of our largest most
popular digital marketing programs here
in the United States okay so it's like
it's scanning codes from bottle caps
that's right that's right so we've
underneath a lot of the bottle caps of
fridge packs and products we sell we've
got unique codes that our consumers can
then use to intern to promotions and
earn and win things okay yeah so why
tensorflow well the we started actually
early on and I could recognize about
last year actually and I could recognize
that tensorflow
had a very I call it approachable
interface right say oh thank you it you
know it presents what would be otherwise
very complex constructions in idioms
that I think I would say every day
programmers could understand so you've
got modules we've got objects you've got
classes you can compose these things to
create you know like a deep learning
graph so it was that it was the entire
you know platform really the
documentation everything it was it
seemed like something that was a you
know a good move for us so now you did
this so you you trained it to classify
basically the digits that are printed in
a bottle tops and now I've seen these
bottle tops and sometimes I'm sure the
dot matrix printer printing on these
things it's like sometimes they're
scared sometimes they're right how did
you do all this yeah so that was one
issue we had with our caps and other
codes is that normal will called like
OCR solutions right they they couldn't
handle the fidelity of the caps so what
we did is we created a training set both
synthetic and real-world because we can
generate these things these caps and
bridge packs ourselves and really just
you know through it it tends to flow and
we adjusted our model several times
through our development but we
eventually got something that performs
extremely well for us
and very well at scale Wow okay so when
you say it's scaled so pretty quick yeah
it's very fast you know it's a we're
about one second it was a performance
client one second average processing
time without from a user experience
perspective it's great you know it's
it's not ruining anyone's expectations
when they engage with our platform now
you went to a tense float to do this
because an m/l based platform you know
what would it have been like what's the
difference if you had done this more in
more traditional programming right so if
we had say apply to more heuristic model
right of trying to use rules to to
interpret these codes so I could imagine
a situation right like where we create
our model and it works really well for
let's say zero degree rotation on the
cap users are holding this thing
perfectly and they're holding their
phone perfectly the second they twist
that thing to degrees in any direction
that heuristic model would fall apart so
you find yourself having to encode all
these different variations through istic
s-- and that sounds arduous definitely
so because the caps circular you don't
really have a frame of reference you
need to know that it's been working yeah
I mean just simple something simple is a
slight to you know twist on the axis and
then rotation which is very natural for
someone holding a cap in their hand to
do so you know with a machine learning
approach we're able to accommodate that
translation invariance with a
convolutional neural net sure and I
think one of the things I found that
like it just to my eye that when I look
at these digits and the bottle caps it's
sometimes it's hard to tell mmm how to
tell the six from a five or an eight or
that kind of thing yeah so did you have
pretty good success with absolutely I
can say anecdotally that that the the
machine I if you wanna think about that
way is actually often works better than
the human eye and just for the reasons
you were saying that to human eye a lot
of the visual artifacts that are on
these caps with skew and pixel drift can
can start to complicate things but our
model is trained to look through that
okay so how did you get training data by
the way well we started with a synthetic
data set
and then that that got us a baseline we
actually got I would say about 50%
accuracy just on synthetic data alone
okay and that was used for transfer
learning actually so we created a where
will a real-world data set just printing
stuff I mean you know we dialed up our
printing facilities and we said hey give
us a bunch and then just we need a whole
bunch of all just print a whole bunch of
gaps for a bank give them to us and then
we distributed those to multiple
suppliers and we derived them with some
custom-built tools that we created to
make it easy for them to take a picture
and label it we started moving into a
much more similar line approach one team
would take images and the other team
through like a portal would verify the
image enter in the code make sure the
quality of the image itself was good but
we were able to very quickly within a
matter of weeks generate enough data for
us to train the model that's so cool now
you mentioned that there are a number of
initiatives you're working on not just
this one right that's right
can you share any of the others I can so
in particular with computer vision and
marketing this code scanning initiative
was the beginning of our kind of our
computer vision platform we this year
have launched a new digital icon a
visual icon that we're starting to put
on the exterior of our packaging and it
it's a delightful looking very beautiful
image and it fits in well with all of
our other branded elements which is
critical but it encodes information for
that product so it's a QR code but not a
QR code it is not a QR code but it's
this principle it's a principle the same
idea I would think of it more as like a
bespoke QR code it's something that is
appealing from a visual person
interested so instead of just lots of
black and white squares it's yeah it's
three concentric rings with a little
coke bottle on them and have to take a
look at let's check it out so cool
so go back to the bottle classifier that
you have I'd like to have a play how
would I get started step one is buy one
of our products not all of our brands
have these caps printed on them but but
most of them do and certainly our core
brands you know any coca-cola product
powerade etc well as well but you buy a
product twist off the cap and you now
have everything you need to enter into
our promotions you know you would create
a count on coke calm slash rewards or on
the new app that we launched two days
ago
I hope ol USA app in the hope is that
you know it becomes an experience that's
rewarding enough to continue engaging
with our consumers sounds good I'll have
to give it a shot so thanks so much
Patrick
yeah you're welcome Lawrence so thanks
everybody for watching this episode if
you've got any questions for me or any
questions for Patrick please just leave
them in the comments below
and any of the links that we discussed
I'll put them in the description for
this video
and whatever you do don't forget to hit
that subscribe button thank you
[Music]