[Music]
hi everybody and welcome to the
tensorflow developer summit I'm Laurence
Moroney here in the tensorflow cafe and
I'm chatting with Clemens me walls and
Clemens you work on tensor flow extended
or tf-x
yep could you tell us all about it seems
really cool yeah it is so G of X is an
end-to-end machine learning platform
that we built around tensor flow okay
what this really means is that
internally at Google a lot of developers
actually want to deploy tensor the
models in production okay and it's very
hard because in addition to the machine
learning piece you need many many more
pieces right intensive lextenda is
exactly this end-to-end machine learning
platform that takes care of all of this
because one of the things in your talk
that I really liked at the beginning of
the talk was like you have this machine
learning little box and you've got all
this stuff's around again that kind of
really hit home because it makes it real
yep so this is actually taken from a
paper from one of my colleagues
discovery and a couple of co-authors and
in this paper he was making this point
that machine learning systems are
extremely complex systems that if all of
these are the components and it's
extremely hard to integrate all of them
and make them work well together and it
there's actually a lot of technical debt
that is incurred by gluing things
together ad hoc okay so what we tried
with tf-x is actually to provide a
solution for this problem provide one
well integrated platform that had all of
these pieces integrated and it provided
an easy way for developers to use all of
these pieces end to end and get started
really fast Wow so there were a whole
bunch of things in the ecosystem but one
of them was like model analysis and I
know you've just published the blog post
on that could you could you tell us a
little bit about it yeah so model
analysis and we just open sources today
as tensor model analysis is
TFM a PF MA it just sounds perfect so
we've used this technology internally
for a while now and we use it for a
couple of purposes one of them really is
that once it's a tenth of the model is
trained you really want to find out how
it performs okay on your entire data set
on slices of that data set for subgroups
of your data and you will really want to
drill down into these metrics because in
some cases or in many cases people only
look at an aggregate quality metric and
that may tell you that the model works
well on average right but I ever H is
not always enough and there could be
some false positives and false negatives
hidden right exactly what you're doing
so a 10th of the modern analysis helps
with both computing this matrix or a
large amounts of data and also four
slices of those data and then we provide
some front-end tooling and interactive
components to drill down into these
metrics okay and find sub areas of data
where the model may not be performing
well or to find error cases or cases
where the model is actually not
performing as expected and then
developers can use this information to
either improve their model or go fix
their data if there's a mistake okay
sounds good so I'm sure a lot of the
time it is a it's a case of refactoring
your data to make it as efficient as
possible yes okay yeah so but this will
help you find that because otherwise
there's a lot of trial and error
exactly okay so cool now there's one of
the other things that I've seen in it is
a TF serving mm-hmm right and that's I
get a lot of questions from people like
you know how do I expose my model to the
world you know that kind of thing it's
like it's all very well if I have it on
my own machine and I can call it so how
does everything actually work so TF
serving it's very interesting the code
base that we actually open sourcing is
exactly the code base that we use
internally to serve our machine learning
models okay and the basic concept behind
it is that you don't want to hard-code
your machine learning model into an
application okay you would rather have a
server that loads a model and a new can
make requests to that server I think
which has a lot of benefits and tentacle
serving is exactly the solution that
that provides the community with this
technology and we just announced today
that we're working on a REST API okay
for the server because this is the
number one feature request from the
community and we've heard the community
and we're working very hard on releasing
this soon you read my mind cuz that's
exactly what's gonna ask what is the
interface is it a REST API like so you
know what is the interface today well
currently it's a it's chair PC
okay which works really well this is
what we use internally but obviously
like externally the standard in the
community and things that a lot of
developers asked us is for arrested yet
okay cool yeah I would love to see a
REST API ran this myself so I'll +1 that
boat perfect so now if I want to get
started with any of this stuff I'm a
developer and I really want to get into
tf-x and see what it gives me maybe
model analysis are serving or
any of the other tools where shall I go
to get started great question so there's
a there's a couple of components we've
already released namely transform model
analysis and serving okay
all of these are under the tensor flow
repo on github but most importantly when
we released model analysis today the
example that we released with model
analysis shows all of these and how they
use together nice and that's in your
covered in your blog post yes okay
that's being discussed in a blog post
and there's also a link where people can
actually go and follow that example to
see how to use all of these components
together our cool nice and then there's
more more components on the way exactly
as I pointed out in in in the dev summit
talk and this is only a very small part
of tf-x and we're working very hard to
release more to give this benefit to the
community and see what the community can
do with it okay Wow sounds good I have
to check it out what can I learn about
this again right now the best place is
really to start with that blog post on
intensive lament analysis okay and we
are actually working on a blog post
specifically for tf-x
in the Prada project sounds good and I
believe I'm working on that with you so
and so we'll put links to all of these
in the description below so you know for
people watching so thank you so much
Clements I've learned so much about tf-x
and I hope that you have too it's been a
real pleasure having you on the show
thanks for having me so thanks everybody
for watching this episode if you've got
any questions for me or if you have any
questions for Clements please leave them
in the comments below and as always
don't forget to hit that subscribe
button
[Music]
you