this is yours everybody and welcome to
ask tensorflow this is the show where we
answer your questions about tensorflow
I'm Laurence Moroney a developer
advocate on tensorflow and I have with
me
hi Magnus it's 10:00 I'm also developer
advocate intensively we got lots of
fascinating questions today so should we
get right down to them yeah sounds good
let's see the first one all right so
this question is from Claudia in Seattle
and the question is I keep hearing about
90 bills having the newest greatest
stuff should I use these and how do I
use them I'd like to know that myself
yeah well tensorflow is open-source and
it's rapidly evolving and often you want
the latest features for your research
and development but you don't want to
wait for a new release and given that
tensorflow is open source you can always
pull the latest source code and build it
from for yourself of course however
building the code can be slow and it can
impact your productivity if you have to
do it very often like every day or so so
there are actually for convenience two
bills that are being done for you on a
daily or nightly hence the name basis
one for tensorflow and one for tensor
flow with GPU additions all you have to
do to get them is to do pip install TF -
nightly or pip install TF - Knightley -
GPU on a clean system and you'll be good
to go I personally like to have two
machines one with the latest nightly
build so I can try stuff out and one
with the most stable release so I have
something stable to work from all the
way make sense I do exactly the same
myself our next question comes from
Joshi on Stack Overflow and the question
is the instructions tell me to install
tensorflow using Kipp but I get an error
where it says there's no matching
distribution I don't
understand this can you help me well
there's actually quite a few things in
it's quite an obscure error message but
for me I've seen this error message with
a couple of things the first and most
obvious or I've seen it is actually to
take a look at your version of pip that
you're using the tensorflow site says
that you need to have at least version
3.1 and this has knocked me out a few
times - if you run pip with the - V
switch you'll see a version if it's
older than this then upgrade and it's
always good to go to the tensorflow dog
and just take a look at what the most
recent recommendations are just in case
this video is a little bit older by the
time you're watching it and also be sure
to use the version of pip that matches
your version of python on some machines
you could actually have two versions of
Python 2.7 and 3x and then the PIP
command might be mapped to the other
version so I always like to say if I'm
using 2.7 to use pip and if you're using
3x to use pip 3 so in if you have 3x and
that's the only one installed and the
PIP command should default to pip 3 so
by typing pip you're actually getting
pip 3 but you really never know so if
your pip or pip 3 installed tensorflow
fails then the next thing you can do is
to try the - - upgrade switch so it's
pip installed - - upgrade tensorflow
that type of thing and finally if you're
still having problems then you can use
the URL of the tensorflow binary as a
switch to pip so you can find the latest
URLs the latest binaries on the
tensorflow dot-org site in the
installing section i've put a link to it
underneath so you just install and
actually point directly at that binary
and then hopefully you're not gonna have
any more mismatches and you'll be good
to go mm-hmm so good question I feel
your pain so should we take another
question yeah that sounds good so this
question is from admin on Twitter at
sandcastle kit that's a good Twitter so
the question is anyone know a free
website where I can train TF models on
the cloud yeah there are a few things
you can do if you want to learn about
training models in the cloud my personal
favorite is to use Google's collab you
can see the link below from within
Google Drive installed the collab add-on
and this will give you a Jupiter
notebook and
on which you can run tensorflow code
there's a lot of public datasets that
you can train for I actually wrote up a
tutorial that you can see in the links
below and it's about how you can train a
neural network on tensorflow for using
CSV data in my case I use it for
classifying breast cancer cells but if
you've got CSV data you can use your own
CSV data and easily modify the code and
it should run happily in collab so be
sure to check it out and there's
something for Kaggle uses as well right
exactly so if you're not a user of
Kaggle you should definitely check Carol
out cago provides a notebook environment
- called kaggle kernels and in kaggle
kernels you can write pretty much
jupiter' code like you could do anywhere
else so that's a great alternative as
well if you want to do serverless
packing one times of law yet these
online notebooks are just becoming
amazing I'm just really learning all
this stuff myself for the first time and
it's just being able to go to my browser
and have a notebook and run code and all
the dependencies are there and maybe
even able to use things like GPUs it's
like it's phenomenal yeah it's amazing I
love it so should we take the next
question yeah let's go on alright so the
next question is from Rebecca in Hong
Kong and it's Google has cloud AI
toolkits as well as tensorflow
which should I use well that's a really
good question you're on the back end you
know there's lots of great stuff in the
Google cloud platform and where we have
like cloud a eye that provides machine
learning services pre train models and
the ability for you to build your own
tailored models but guess what that old
uses tensorflow we're one big happy
family and if you use cloud though you
can also get access to lots of other
great things like hardware that's
optimized for machine learning you might
have heard of GPUs tensorflow processing
units which are processors that are
geared for ML with tensorflow
you can use these in the cloud with the
Google cloud platform there's also lots
of services for specific scenarios
things such as cloud video intelligence
makes videos searchable and discoverable
or there's the cloud vision API that you
can use to analyze the contents of your
actual images it's really cool with some
of the demos you see for that way you
take a photo it upload you upload it and
the cloud API tells you what's in that
image there's also the cloud speech API
which is great for converting audio to
text and there's a whole lot more you've
probably used Google Translate that's
also built in all of this technology but
if you want to get down to the nuts and
bolts of machine language
raining classifiers regressors and the
like then tensorflow is the API that you
can use to do it yourself the bottom
line is that it's not an either/or nor
you can actually use both but great
question about there thank you so much
well thanks everybody this has been a
really fascinating show some lots of
great questions in there and if you have
any more questions for us remember
please post them on social media with
these last tensorflow hashtag and we'll
be looking out to answer them in an
episode coming very very soon thank you
so much
[Music]
you