[Music]
in this episode we're going to create a
very simple machine learned model and
converted to tensorflow light for use on
mobile or IOT devices to start we'll
create a simple model using Chara's the
simplest possible neural network has one
layer with one unit and that takes a
single input in care us you'll then
compile the model specifying two
functions the loss function and the
optimizer on every iteration the
framework calculates the loss using the
method specified and then tries to
optimize the neural network using the
optimizer that specified now we'll
create a set of X values from negative 1
to 4 and now I'll create a set of
corresponding Y values for these X
values the goal will be to infer the
relationship between the two can you see
what it is every Y value is 2x minus 1
so where X is minus 1 Y is minus 3 where
X is zero Y is minus 1 etc etc to train
the neural network we use model dot fit
passing it the X's the Y's and a number
of iterations that we want to train for
in this case we'll save 500 so how do we
test the model to see if I can infer y
equals 2x minus 1 for a new value that's
achieved using the predict method we
simply pass 10 into it in an input shape
which is an array of 1 we then run the
code and the network will be trained and
we'll see that the output is 19 point
zero five which is very close to our
desired value given that we train the
network with a very small data set it's
still quite impressive now that we have
a model we can save it out as a file
this is achieved using the save model
method in care us we'll run it and we'll
then see that linear dot H 5 is created
finally we'll convert to TF light using
the toko converter this is achieved with
the from Charis model file method will
pass the Charis file into it we then
call the converter to convert and save
its results as linear
çf light we can run it and then we'll
see that linear TF light is created for
us to learn more about tensor flow visit
tensorflow org and while you're at it
don't forget to subscribe to this
channel thank you
[Music]