[Music]
[Applause]
hi everybody I'm Laurence Moroney from
the tensorflow team at Google and today
we're going to talk about text
classification it's part one of a
two-part series will will focus on the
data and getting it ready to train a
neural network you will do this hands-on
using a workbook that you can find at
the link in the description below
and I'll step you through it text
classification has some unique
challenges so before you get coding let
me step you through some of these first
of all neural networks typically deal
with numbers are not text when learning
patterns that can be used for prediction
or classification so in this case we're
looking at learning from movie reviews
to see if those reviews are positive or
negative and the first step of course is
to change the words into numbers that
represent them there'll be a little bit
more processing of these words into
vectors determining their sentiments and
we'll cover that in the next video so
let's get coding first first things
first I'll have to check the licenses
before I begin and now I'll import
tensorflow and numpy I'll also use care
Us and print out the version of
tensorflow that I'm using okay now it's
time to get the data set the IMDB set is
included with care us so let's download
it and let's take a look at what's in
there note that in this case the nice
folks that care us have done the work
for us of converting the words into
integers they've also sorted them into a
dictionary so that lower numbers are the
most common words and higher numbers are
the least common words so when we loaded
the specified 10,000 words this will
then give us the top 10,000 words that
are used across all of the reviews okay
now we've loaded the data and we have
our training data and labels as well as
our test data and labels it's also
nicely sorted into integers for us which
is a great first step for learning let's
see what the data looks like next first
we'll look at our training data you'll
see that we have a total of 25,000 items
of data and 25,000 labels describing
them the labels are very simple it's
zero for a negative
view and one for a positive one a
reviews look like this it's just a long
set of numbers and these are the indexes
into the array of words the review will
start with a 1 indicating the start of
the review so the first word in the
review is word number 14 which
translates to the word this followed by
the value 22 which translates to the
word film the next bit of code is then a
handy-dandy way of decoding the review
note that the values zero through three
are reserved with one being the start of
the review as we mentioned a moment ago
and zero is for padding now this is
important and you'll see that in a
moment
I can now decode the review and see that
one
14:22 other start character and this and
then film it's pretty cool right
now earlier I skipped over this piece of
code showing me the length of the review
so for example the first movie was 218
words long and the second was 189 words
long now that's really awkward and it's
confusing to train a neural network if
all of the training data is of different
lengths so let's pick a standard length
for every review and if it's longer
we'll trim it to that length and if it's
shorter we'll pad it to that length the
Charis pre-processing api's make this
really easy here you can see I'm taking
the training and test data and making
sure it's 256 words long if I need to
pad it then I'll pad it with the pad
character which is the 0 that we saw
earlier a quick look will now show that
it worked they're all 256 words long and
if I now look at my first set of
training data you'll see that it's
padded by zeros remember it had been 218
words long
so the extras get patted out to make it
256 great our training and test data is
now ready so in the next episode you'll
take a look at how to design a neural
network to accept this data and to train
a model to determine the sentiment of
movie reviews I'll see you there
[Music]
you