hi everybody and welcome to the 10th
afloat developer summit I'm Laurence
Moroney reporting from the tensorflow
cafe and it's my pleasure to have Megan
catch olya with me in this episode now
Meghan great keynote you gave there was
lots of great information on there and
we had Jeff on the show a few minutes
ago and he was talking about like some
of the great stuff that's been done with
tensorflow and we shared some great
examples could you tell us about them
yeah well actually there was one example
I really liked in Anita's section as
well also kind of right at the beginning
there was the example about the planet
discovery and the reason I really like
this one is because it was someone in my
team and it really was one of these
things where someone came and it was
there like I have this idea this data is
publicly available can we try this I'm
not sure if it's gonna work but I'm
excited about it okay sure 20% project
why not they're like oh how is it what's
it like being in brain and on tend to
flow I'm like oh one of my Swedes
discovered planets it's it's pretty cool
so what did you do so I think that's
really amazing just because when you
take a step back and think about it this
is a person who has very strong software
engineering skills he's good at machine
learning he knows it but he's not an
astrophysicist yep he's never discovered
like doesn't stop with NASA or anything
before it was just the data was there he
was excited about trying it and we found
a way to make a work I thought that was
really to me that just a really cool
example of like oh wow like there are
these problems that before we're like
well we can have a human sift through
all this and maybe figure some things
out right we can actually find things
out better by using machine learning and
then everyone's really excited about
what we've found so I really like that
one that one's one of my favorites it's
not just discovering the planet but it's
also a solar system that has multiple
planets yes so being able to get to the
resolution of saying hey it's not just
we know there's a planet around this
star many light-years away there are
eight of them you know I think it's 30
light years anyway but I think that just
blows my mind because it's not that long
ago like he said it was only the top
astrophysicists and astronomers we might
be able to measure wobble in a star and
say I think there's a planet there now
what machine learned data we can have
somebody go nope there's eight of them
exactly
you shared some examples in your keynote
that I really like like protecting the
rainforests and air traffic control
right so what have you been involved in
any of them or is your team not directly
in any of those examples I don't think I
do have a few folks who have worked on
some of the medical examples that I need
to talked about and then Jeff kind of
talked more about as well I think those
are really exciting and just because
it's a way of augmenting doctors and
helping them right you can give them
more tools you can give them more
information you can give them more data
it's not that you can replace doctors
but you can give them more help so that
they can do their job better and
actually help more people especially in
places where they're just part enough
doctors or aren't enough folks who have
the right kind of training the right I
think that's really exciting just to see
the certain things like the the retina
scans right the different all the other
stuff they're doing in ophthalmology
I've had a couple of folks who've worked
on some of those projects as well but I
always find those really exciting
because it's applying machine learning
to a problem we already know about but
the results are so amazing just they you
can make things better for people
Jeff and I were joking it said but it's
true it's like it's computer vision
helping real vision yes I really like
the air traffic control example because
you know I used to live really right
beside the main air traffic control
center for New York and it was like the
one thing that I learned is how
stressful the job it is to and to think
how quickly people burn out doing that
job but then having something to at
least the system obviously it can't
replace them but to at least the system
in that job because prediction and
projection I mean it's that's what they
have to do in split second that's
correct
the more data or the more information
they can have at their hands or the
faster they can get it at their
fingertips the better off we'll be in
making the right choices and helping
direct everything correctly it takes a
special gift to do that job so anything
we can do to help them and keep us safer
while we're in the air just just just
really blew my mind so now of course all
of this is made possible by tensorflow
and you're part of the engineering team
for tensorflow how does it feel to to be
building all this or to be helping to
build all this it's really exciting I
mean
think sometimes with it's like with any
job you might get lost in the day-to-day
of it right we have teams to run we have
to make sure we're building the right
things but I think the most exciting
thing is when we get to take a step back
and be like what's the community trying
to do right what types of things are
they trying to vote how do we help go in
some of those different directions
whether it's just make it easier for
more people to use things because now
the API is are simpler or those
higher-level API is like Kerris or
whether it's like okay we know there's
really some experts out there who wants
to just fine-tune and hand tune
everything give them the capability to
do that and tell them how to do it for a
really powerful hardware so I think it's
it's one of those groups especially at
Google you don't see as many where they
get to have this external community
interaction I find that to be the most
interesting thing because people
externally are watching what we're doing
we're held accountable to you know to
the team or to the group
we're held accountable to all the folks
who are using tensorflow as well and who
want to use it for different
applications so I find that actually one
of the most exciting things about
tensorflow as a project is that it's not
just about like oh we're doing something
inside for Google no no we're really
looking at like what does it mean for
the community how are we helping all the
different groups how are we enabling
research how are we naming production so
I find that the most the most part the
people are awesome as well and I mean
there are people out there with
world-beating ideas and no way to
implement them right and it's a part of
what we're trying to do is to
democratize AI so that they can go out
there and they can implement them
because we can't think of everything
we're enabling and helping it's actually
really cold as a board just outside the
cafe where people have been writing
their ideas like go check it out well I
think we did this at the last dev summit
as well and it's always really like
overwhelming in a sense to look and see
and like oh my gosh there's so many
ideas there so many things people have
already done as well it's so impressive
some of them are super inspiring and
some of them are hilarious my favorite
is I saw some somebody wants to build a
jazz musician they should they should
talk to my Jess the next Miles Davis so
thank you so much Megan it's been a real
pleasure
and thanks everybody for watching I'm
Laurence Moroney and if you have any
questions for me or if you have any
questions for Megan please leave them in
the comments below and we'll be sure to
answer them and don't forget to hit that
subscribe button thank you
[Music]